Good morning everyone. [music] Let's go
ahead and stand. Let's worship the Lord
together this morning.
>> [music]
[singing]
[singing and music]
[music and singing]
[singing]
[music]
>> Amen.
Welcome to Evangelical Chinese Church.
Great having you here this
[music and singing] morning. You're
going to notice it's going to feel a
little bit more empty this morning cuz
all of our young adults, our Living
Water [music] Fellowship, are off on a
retreat today. So, just expect that. For
those [singing] of you who might be in
the east lobby, feel free to come on in.
We've got plenty of place [music]
space here this morning. Why don't we
just take a minute? Why don't we just
welcome the folks around us? Welcome
[singing] them in the name of the Lord
this morning.
>> [music]
[music and singing]
>> This morning we're going to be singing
about just worshiping God, thinking
forward to the time when we're going to
be in [music and singing] heaven, just
raising our voices along with everyone
else alongside us, praising God
together. And at the same time we're
going to be [music] singing about the
idea [singing] of, "Hey, we want to
bring people with us there." Right? This
is not just a solo event. We want to
bring our friends. We want to bring
people who don't yet know him
[music and singing] to come to a saving
knowledge of Jesus. And that's what
we're going to be singing about today.
Why don't you just go ahead and bow your
heads with me as we lift lift this time
up [music] to our Lord.
>> [singing]
>> Heavenly Father, I thank you for this
morning. I thank you for the gorgeous
weather that we have. I pray for those
who are at the Living Water retreat,
Lord, that you would bless them
[music and singing] in what they're
doing and the discussions that they're
going to have. Pray, Lord, for everybody
who walks in through the doors this
morning or logs in online or watches
[singing and music] this recording
afterwards, that you would bless them as
well, Lord. We are here to worship you
and praise [music and singing] you.
Lord, we want to lift you up. We
recognize that there is a glorious
future that is eventually [music]
coming. It may not be
>> [singing]
>> uh joyful here on earth. There's going
to be trial. There's going to be things
that we go through.
And but we know that there
[music and singing] is a day coming when
we can all worship you alongside those
who have gone before us.
>> [singing and music]
>> And Lord, as we look forward to that
day, allow us and cause us to have a
burden for those who don't know [music]
you yet. [singing]
Lord, don't allow us to just be happy
that we might be saved or know you. Help
us, Lord, to have a fire
[singing and music] and a desire to
bring others to a saving knowledge of
grace as well.
We [singing and music] just lift this
time up to you this morning. In Christ's
name we pray. Amen.
>> [music]
[singing]
[music]
[music and singing]
>> Gathered at the highest throne. [music]
>> [singing]
>> Welcome by a melody.
>> [music]
>> An anthem I have always known.
A song that's always been in me.
>> [music]
[music]
[singing]
>> always [music] been in me.
All [singing and music] glory and honor,
dominion and power to
[singing and music] you.
>> [music]
>> A million [singing] angels fall face
down on the floor, all [music] to echo
holy [singing]
is the
Lord.
My heart [music] can't help but sing
with all of heaven roar, forever
[music and singing] echo holy
is the Lord.
Oh,
>> [singing and music]
>> oh,
forever echo holy
is the
Lord.
>> [music]
>> Memorized by every [singing]
heart.
Written in [music] eternity. [singing]
Every lifted [music and singing] voice
apart.
Joining in the symphony. [music]
Oh,
>> [singing]
>> all glory and honor, dominion
[music and singing] and power to you.
Oh,
>> [singing]
>> all wisdom [music] and wonder belong to
no other but [singing] you.
Yeah.
A million angels [music and singing]
fall face down on the floor, all to echo
[music and singing] holy
is the
Lord. My heart can't help but sing with
all of heaven roar, forever
[music and singing] echo holy
is the
Lord.
Oh,
>> [music and singing]
>> oh,
forever echo holy [singing]
>> [music]
>> is the Lord.
Oh,
>> [singing]
[music]
>> oh,
forever echo holy
is the
Lord.
>> [singing and music]
>> Standing at the edge of time. [singing]
There [music] before the throne of
grace.
Majesty [music] before [singing] my
eyes.
I [music] let it take my breath away.
>> [music]
>> A million [singing] angels fall face
[music] down on the floor, all to echo
[singing] holy
is the
Lord.
My heart [music and singing] can't help
but sing with all of heaven roar,
>> [music and singing]
>> forever echo holy
is the
Lord. A million angels fall
[music and singing]
face down on the floor, all to echo holy
is the
Lord.
My heart can't help but sing
[music and singing]
with all of heaven roar, forever echo
holy
is the
Lord.
>> [singing and music]
>> Oh,
oh,
>> [singing and music]
>> forever echo holy
is the
>> [singing and music]
>> Lord. Oh,
oh,
forever [singing and music]
echo holy
is the
Lord.
Amen.
>> [music]
>> You live among the least
[music and singing]
of these, the weary and the
>> [music]
>> weak.
And [singing] it would be a tragedy
[music]
for me to turn away. [singing]
>> [music]
>> All my needs you have supplied.
[singing]
When [music] I was dead, you gave me
[singing] life.
How could I not
>> [music]
>> give it away [singing]
so freely?
I'll follow you [music and singing] into
the homes of the broken.
>> [music and singing]
>> I'll follow you into the world.
I'll meet the needs [music and singing]
for the poor and the needy, God.
>> [singing]
>> I'll follow you into the world.
Use [music]
[singing] my hands, use my feet to make
your [music and singing] kingdom come.
To the corners [singing]
of
>> [music]
>> the earth
until your work is done.
This faith without [music and singing]
works is dead. And on that
[singing and music] cross, your blood
was shed.
How could [music] we not [singing]
give it away so freely?
>> [music and singing]
>> And I'll
follow you [music and singing] into the
homes of the broken.
I'll follow you into the world.
>> [music]
>> I'll meet the needs for the poor
>> [singing and music]
>> and the needy, God. I'll follow you into
the world.
>> [music]
>> I'll follow you into the homes of the
[singing] broken.
I'll follow you into the world.
[singing]
[music]
I'll meet the needs for the poor
[singing] and the needy, God. I'll
follow you into the world.
And I give [singing and music]
all myself.
I give [singing and music] all myself.
I give [singing and music]
all myself
to you.
>> [music]
>> And I give [singing and music]
all myself.
I give [music and singing]
I give
>> [singing]
>> all [music] myself
to you.
>> [singing]
>> I'll follow [music] you into the homes
of the broken.
I'll follow you into the world.
>> [music]
[singing]
>> Oh,
I'll meet the needs for the poor
and the needy, [music and singing]
God.
I'll follow you into the world.
And [music and singing] I'll
follow you into the homes of the broken.
[music]
I'll follow you [singing] into the
world.
>> [music]
>> I'll meet the needs [singing]
for the poor and the needy, God. I'll
follow you [music and singing] into the
world.
Would you bow your heads with me?
Heavenly Father, I pray that that song
would truly be the the prayer of our
hearts and the desire of our hearts. And
if it isn't already, Lord, I pray that
you would give that to us.
Lord, allow us to see the people around
us. Lord, those who may be friends,
those who may be acquaintances, those
who may be family members. And let us
not just sit to the side, Lord.
Recognizing everything that you've done
for us, sending your son to die for us
on a cross, and the salvation that we
have through him.
Give us the love for the people around
us.
In Christ's name we pray. Amen.
I the [singing and music] Lord of sea
and sky,
I have heard [music and singing]
my people cry.
All who [singing] dwell [music] in dark
and sin,
my hand [singing] will save.
I who [singing and music] made the stars
of night,
I will make their darkness bright.
Who will [singing] bear my light to
them?
Whom [music and singing] shall I send?
Here [singing] I am, [music] Lord.
Is it I, Lord?
>> [singing and music]
>> I have heard
you [music] calling in [singing]
the night.
I will [singing] go, Lord.
>> [music]
>> If you lead me,
I will [singing] hold
>> [music]
>> your people
[singing] my heart.
I the Lord [singing]
of snow [music] and rain,
I have [singing] borne my people's
[music]
pain.
I have wept [singing]
for love of them.
>> [music]
>> They turn away.
I will [music and singing] break their
hearts of stone,
give them hearts [singing and music]
for love
alone.
I will [singing and music] speak my
words to them.
Whom shall I send?
>> [music and singing]
>> Here I am,
>> [music]
>> Lord. Is [singing] it I,
>> Lord?
I have heard
you calling [singing]
in [music]
the night.
I [singing and music] will go,
Lord,
if you [music] lead me.
>> [singing]
>> I [music] will hold
your people [singing]
in my heart.
>> [music]
>> I the Lord [music and singing]
of wind and flame,
I will tend the poor and lame.
I [music] will set [singing]
a feast for them.
My [music and singing] hand will save.
Finest bread [singing and music]
I will provide
till their hearts be satisfied.
[music and singing]
I will give my life to them.
Whom shall [singing] I send?
Here I [singing and music] am,
Lord.
Is it I,
Lord?
>> [singing]
>> I have heard
>> [music]
>> you calling in the night.
I will go,
>> [singing and music]
>> Lord,
if you lead
me.
>> [music and singing]
>> I will hold
your people in [singing] my heart.
>> [music]
>> Here I am.
Here I [singing] am,
Lord.
Is [singing] it I,
Lord?
>> [music]
>> I have [singing] heard
you calling in the night.
[singing]
I will [music] go,
Lord, if you lead [singing] me. [music]
I will hold
your people in [singing and music] my
heart.
Good morning, church.
Sorry, I didn't realize that was ending.
Um
Today's prayer is brought to you by
uh
Psalm 40. I had to look at that, too.
Um a song of David. This was written, we
think, when he was having troubles
having family troubles with his son
Absalom.
Uh if you don't know,
you might think you have family
troubles, but
David had family troubles. His son tried
to kill him
uh and he did a bunch of other things
and ended up
not in a good place.
Um So, this Psalm actually looks back uh
David is looking back on his life and is
thinking of all the ways that God has
saved him in the past
uh and is again crying out to God and
asking him to do it again
uh in faith.
Um so, whatever it is in your life,
maybe you can find some resonance here.
Let's pray.
Oh Lord, hear our cries.
>> [sighs and gasps]
>> We wait and we wait for you.
Draw us up from the pit of destruction
and set our feet upon the rock.
Make our steps secure
and put a new song in our mouths.
For none can compare with you.
We proclaim your name to the nations,
yet nothing we say can be enough because
of all the wondrous deeds you have done.
Thanking thanking you for bringing all
those who were baptized over Easter.
12 people here in the East and five more
in Seattle. And that's only in the
English congregation.
We thank you
for giving them
faith
and allowing them to take this step and
to proclaim their faith in you.
We praise you for raising up our young
adults to meet the needs of the
congregations
serving in ministries like the 40 days
in community campaign on the Eastside or
sorry, on the Seattle side.
Because we know that you do not delight
in sacrifice and burnt offerings.
But we pray that you will honor and
bless those who choose to be living
sacrifices for you
to further your kingdom
with their time and their efforts and
their lives.
And let us worship as one body together.
Especially now as we prepare for the
kindred series next month.
This is our 10th year.
Remind us at this milestone of why we
gather together.
Why
we take the time and the effort as three
churches out of everything else that
we're doing.
Why we make this a point.
That the racial strife
is still a reality in this broken world.
But that you are the one creator God.
We are made in your image.
And it's in this image that we draw our
identities.
Heal us.
Heal us and heal your children.
Let us face this world together
and put our faith in you.
Write your law in our hearts and let us
do your will.
Do not hide your deliverance from us. Do
not conceal your steadfast love.
Show us your faithfulness.
Be pleased to deliver us, oh Lord,
whether we be struggling with physical
or mental illness, whether we be unhappy
at work or have been looking for a long
time.
May all who seek you rejoice and be glad
in you.
Because other in you than in you, we are
all poor and needy.
And finally, we turn our thoughts
further afield. We pray for our
missionaries in Nigeria,
Mawo and Janet Abaya, who have been
serving you for the last 30 years
working with Muslim background
believers.
Restore peace to the region so that they
continue their work and comfort the
principal of their school, Philip Alams,
and his family
who lost eight cousins and family
members during an attack on his village.
Sustain them and keep them safe.
You are the rock upon which they have
built their lives.
They wait and they wait for you.
Draw them up from the pit of destruction
>> [clears throat]
>> and set their feet upon solid rock.
Make their steps secure and put a new
song in their mouths.
Even now, right now,
as we pray the prayer your son taught
us.
Our Father in heaven, hallowed be your
name.
Your kingdom come, your will be done on
earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread and
forgive us our debts as we also have
forgiven our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil. For yours is the
kingdom and the power and the glory
forever. Amen.
Thank you. Please be seated.
Good morning.
So sorry, my my voice is a little
gravelly.
Uh for the youth, let this be a lesson
to you. Don't smoke and drink.
Actually, I'm not kidding. Don't smoke
and drink.
Um all right. So,
I love action movies. I don't know about
you guys, but um
while I think Tom Cruise is a little bit
wackadoodle, I I do like his Mission
Impossible movies. Uh and of course,
Mission Impossible is not the only movie
with a mission, right? I mean, there's
actually a lot of movies out there that
have a mission to them. Uh one of my
favorite is actually the one uh
it's The Mission. I don't know if you
guys have seen that one, but that one's
definitely worth watching. Um our church
has a vision
and our vision is
the mission. It's it's the missional
church and I'll just going to read this
for you. Um ECC strives to be a
missional church. We seek to help people
come into relationship with Christ, grow
and mature their faith through the Holy
Spirit, be transformed into his
likeness, share God's love with those
around us, and be a blessing to others
in our community and in the world all to
the glory of God and our mission motto
is faith to faith, life to life, and
generation to generation.
And one of Jesus's last words,
his last command to his disciples was a
call to missions in the Great
Commission. And it says in Matthew 28,
"Go therefore and make disciples of all
nations, baptizing them in the name of
the Father and of the Son and of the
Holy Spirit, teaching them to observe
all that I have commanded you and
behold, I'm with you always to the end
of the age."
And this call, of course, was not only
to his disciples at the time,
but it's a call for all of us.
Every follower of Christ to heed and the
question becomes,
"What's my mission in the Great
Commission?
How am I part of the Great Commission?
And does that mean I have to become a
missionary?
Spoiler alert, no. You don't all have to
be a missionary. How can I actively
participate
in the Great Commission?
And our passage from today becomes a
model for us to learn how we can all
participate in fulfilling the call, the
command to the Great Commission. And if
you can, please stand with me as we read
God's word together.
Today's passage comes from Acts chapter
13, verses 1 through 5.
Let's read together. Now, in the church
at Antioch, there were prophets and
teachers, Barnabas, Simeon called Niger,
and Lucius of Cyrene, Manaen, who had
been brought up with Herod the Tetrarch,
and Saul.
While they were worshipping the Lord and
fasting, the Holy Spirit said, "Set
apart for me Barnabas and Saul for the
work to which I have called them."
So, after they had fasted and prayed,
they placed their hands on them and sent
them off. The two of them went on their
way by the Holy Spirit, went down to
Seleucia, and sailed from there to
Cyprus.
When they arrived at Salamis, they
proclaimed the word of God in the Jewish
synagogues. John was with them as their
helper. Let's pray with me for a second.
Father God, I do ask that you would
sustain my voice during this talk and I
ask that you would speak through me,
Lord, through your Holy Spirit. And I
pray that everyone here would be just
ready to receive your message this
morning. We pray these things in
Christ's name. Amen. Please be seated.
All right. So, here's the outline of my
talk. I'm going to talk about the
background of the Great Commission.
I'm going to talk about the church as
sender and the church as sent. And then
I'm going to talk about your mission in
the Great Commission.
Now, here's here's the background on the
Great Commission. Now, we just read the
Great Commission from Matthew 28, but
Jesus also said at the beginning of
Acts,
right before his ascension in Acts 1:8,
he said this,
"But you will receive power when the
Holy Spirit has come upon you, and you
will be my witnesses in Jerusalem and in
all Judaea and Samaria and to the end of
the earth."
Now, many understand that Acts 1:8 is
part of the Great Commission. So, these
two passages together, both Matthew 28
and Acts 1:8, together form the call of
the Great Commission.
These are Jesus's last words, his last
instructions, his last charge to his
disciples before he is his ascension and
before he left them.
Now, we see in Acts how God actually
enfolds the Great Commission. And in
fact, if you're studying the book of
Acts, an easy way to structure the
entire book of Acts is by the Great
Commission of Acts 1 through 8. And we
see this progression in Acts 1 through
8. It says, "From Jerusalem
to Judaea
and Samaria and then to the ends of the
earth."
And so, you can see
in Acts chapters 1 through 7,
a focus on Jerusalem. And this is where
the apostles and the others with them
preach throughout Jerusalem
predominantly to the Jewish people.
And then you can see in Acts 8 through
that there's an expansion.
Now, we're talking about Judaea and
Samaria. And in Acts chapter 8, verse 5,
which Pastor Steve Moy preached last
week, he talked about Philip going down
to the city of Samaria and proclaimed to
them Christ.
And in chapter 8, pro- um
Philip proclaims Christ to Samaria,
which is this racially mixed Jewish and
Gentile ancestry people,
who was then backed up by Peter and
John.
And then in chapter 10, you see Peter
was given this vision from God. And you
maybe you recall this, where he's given
this vision to eat all these unclean
animals. And right afterwards, he
entered and preached to a Roman
centurion's house, Cornelius, marking
the first intentional preaching to a
Gentile audience.
And then in chapter 11,
we saw the formation of the Antioch
church, the first Gentile church, and a
major movement into the Gentile uh group
of people. And you know, you may recall
that this is where they were first
called Christians.
And so, the rest of Acts,
Acts 13 through 26,
starting with our passage that we just
read in Acts 13,
God enfolds the rest of the Great
Commission to the ends of the earth. Our
passage shows the first of Paul's three
missionary journeys along with Barnabas
and some others.
And so, we see God's plan enfold,
starting in Jerusalem, then to Judaea
and Samaria. And then as recorded in
Acts, Paul launches the first of his
three missions trip throughout the Roman
world.
So, let me ask the question.
Who initiates God's global mission?
Was it the church?
Was it the prophets in the church?
Was it the church leaders?
Let's look at what our passage said
again.
It said, "While they were worshipping
the Lord and fasting,
they
were probably the whole congregation. It
wasn't just these people
that we read listed. It was the whole
church was praying and fasting.
And then we see it says this,
"The Holy Spirit said, Set apart for me
Barnabas and Saul for the work to which
I have called them."
So, what's going on here?
It's in the setting of worship,
fasting, and prayer
that the Holy Spirit calls them into
action.
It's important to note that they were
not having a missions meeting.
This setting in the Antioch church was
not some strategic planning meeting or
visioning meeting.
It was during worship,
fasting,
prayer,
something that they were already doing,
something that they were probably doing
regularly,
which was putting themselves before the
presence of God.
And in so doing, God called upon them.
And it says, "While they were
worshipping the Lord and fasting, the
Holy Spirit said to them, Set apart for
me Barnabas and Saul
for this work that I'm going to call
them to do."
And so, we can we can see
who initiates God's global mission. The
Holy Spirit initiates God's global
mission.
And we can see that the Holy Spirit's
hand
was actually all over the place in this
passage.
He was guiding the entire missions trip.
It says in verse 4,
"The two of them sent on their way by
the Holy Spirit." And so, they went down
to Seleucia and then from there they
sailed to Cyprus. And then in verse 9,
it says, "Then Saul, who was also called
Paul,
filled with the Holy Spirit." And then
it says what he ended up doing.
In the other passages, the Holy Spirit
plays a very active role in guiding,
leading,
and directing the unfolding of his
global missionary plans.
God directed Peter in chap- Acts chapter
10 to look beyond the Jews
toward the Gentiles by giving him that
vision, "Go ahead and kill and eat these
unclean animals."
In Acts 16,
we see this.
During Paul's secondary missionary
journey, the Holy Spirit blocked Paul
from going into Asia Minor and instead,
through this vision,
directed him to Macedonia.
There are many passages like this. And
the point is,
God is always calling.
He's always calling us.
The question is, are we responding?
Are we listening?
And are we responding to his call?
So first,
are we actively listening to what the
Holy Spirit is telling us?
Do we spend enough time in prayer,
in fasting, in worship,
in meditation, in the word of God,
in all the various avenues
to quiet our mind,
to quiet our souls,
putting down our 5 by 2-in screens that
we constantly have in front of us,
and listen to what God is calling us to
do?
And many times,
we do hear the Holy Spirit nudging us
in a direction,
but then do we respond?
Are we ghosting God like we sometimes do
when we don't want to respond to
messages?
And of course, I would never do that to
you.
I would always respond to your messages,
but anyway,
I believe that sometimes we do hear God,
but we don't want to respond
because sometimes his calling is
uncomfortable.
Sometimes his call is time-consuming.
Sometimes his calling means making
sacrifices.
But that's exactly what God is calling
us to do.
That's the point of being a living
sacrifice.
That's the point of the surrendered
life.
And it's clear from our passage and the
entirety of the act of the book of Acts
that God has a plan.
We don't need to come up with a plan.
We just need to listen to God's call for
us.
And we need to respond. God has a plan
and we need to figure out how we are
part of God's plan.
By we, I mean we both as a church at
large and we as individuals.
What can we learn from the church in
Antioch?
The Holy Spirit spoke to them and as a
church,
they responded.
They actually responded in two ways.
They responded as sender and they
responded as sent.
The church as sender. As sender, they
responded to the Holy Spirit
how?
First, as a church,
they gave of their resources.
The biblical city of Antioch,
from what we understand,
um was actually very powerful and very
wealthy.
Um it's currently uh the city of
Antiochia.
Antioch, right? Antiochia, which is in
modern-day Turkey. It's a
metropolis of Syria.
It was a Hellenistic Roman metropolis, a
city. In the past, it was the capital of
the Seleucid kingdom. The Seleucid
kingdom is the Greek kingdom.
And then the Greek got conquered by the
Romans.
And the Romans made it the capital of
Syria after conquering the Seleucids in
64 BC.
It was a powerful city. On coins, it
would call itself the capital of the
East.
It was the seat of the Roman governor of
the region.
And it was a free city.
Uh the Romans allowed it to govern
itself. It was not ruled or subjugated
by the Roman authorities.
And it was large enough to boast its own
marketplace, its own theater, and its
own amphitheater.
Um they even had a palace and they had a
circus.
Josephus, the Roman historian, claims
that the city ranked
third in size in the Roman Empire,
third in size and wealth only after Rome
and Alexandria.
All right? So, what about the church?
What about the church in Antioch?
What we know about the city,
we can tell that if you recall in Acts
chapter 11, this was the first Gentile
church formed by these no-named
Christians, right? These no-named Jewish
Christ followers
who were persecuted and scattered and
witnessed to the Gentile believers
around them.
And then Barnabas was sent first to
minister to them.
And Barnabas then grabbed Paul to join
him in teaching them and growing their
faith.
The Antioch church were young
Christians.
It was a young church, but they matured
fast.
Despite being a Gentile church, they
were grafted into God's family. And they
responded generously at the end of uh
Acts chapter 11 by collecting a relief
package for the Jerusalem church
sent via
Barnabas and Saul.
So, what can we gather? The Antioch
church, by its location, was powerful
and wealthy.
Uh
by its location in a powerful and
wealthy city,
the church itself was probably fairly
well-off.
And they had God-given financial
resources and means to be a sending
church.
They responded with their resources
and they became a sending church. They
became a launching pad
of not just one,
not two, but all three of Paul's great
missionary journeys as recorded in the
book of Acts. And it all started in as a
launching pad from this very church, the
uh Church of Antioch.
And so their sacrificial giving,
and they did respond sacrificially,
was not just limited to their money.
They responded to God's call by sending
their best. They sent Paul and Barnabas.
And they sent them off
sacrificially, not not holding anything
back. They weren't saying, "No, we got
to hang on to these two guys." No, they
released them.
Now, what about us?
What about ECC?
Are we giving sacrificially
to the Great Commission?
Bellevue,
Redmond,
Seattle,
very much like the city of Antioch,
is a wealthy area.
ECC
is a
resource-rich
church.
Are you using your resources for the
Great Commission?
Are you using your resources for kingdom
purposes?
Now, let me just share you a little
insight with our missions fund here.
So, here's our missions budget.
How do we do?
Well, you can see that we gave about a
half a million dollars
through our missions fund.
And that supports over 40 long-term
missionaries, seven who are from ECC, by
the way,
spread out over 17 countries,
but their actual missions field actually
expands beyond expands beyond the 17
countries that they happen to be
residing in or calling their home.
And we supported mid-term missionaries
and six teams of short-term
missionaries.
And you can see in 2024,
um
we had a shortfall.
And in 2025, we had a surplus surplus,
but you know, I got to say even that is
misleading.
I talked to Albert Eng, who chairs our
missions committee, and he informed me
that every year, every year,
they run a deficit.
They literally run a deficit all the way
up until the last couple weeks in
December
because
throughout the year, we're regularly
supporting our missionaries. It's not
like we just give it to them as a one
lump sum. We're supporting them every
month, month after month.
And by God's providence, by prayer,
through the compassion
of some of the brothers and sisters in
Christ,
there's this last-minute
ditch last-ditch effort to try to make
the missions fund whole by covering the
deficit
at the end of the year so that we can
continue to support our missionaries the
following year.
Now, not many know,
but our missions budget,
by design, is not co-mingled with our
general fund.
So, there's never a risk of raiding it
if our church ever has a shortfall.
But that said, unless you're earmarking
your donations specifically to the
missions fund,
you are not personally contributing to
it.
So, if you feel led by the Holy Spirit
to financially support our missionaries,
please contribute your additional
donations to the missions fund. And it's
really easy. Just in the memo section of
your donation, specify how much you want
to give to the general fund and how much
you want to give to the missions fund.
But beyond financial giving,
we know that the Antioch Church
supported their missionaries. They
prayed for them. They fasted for them
and they encouraged them. And so I would
ask again, how are we supporting our
missionaries beyond finances?
Prayer.
Can you pray for our missionaries? Every
week and you just heard
Kobe pray.
We highlight one of our missionaries
that EC supports every week.
And you can find out
which missionary is highlighted by going
to our website eccseattle.org.
And if you go under worship and then go
to online bulletins, you can see which
missionary we're praying for for that
week. Please pray for them.
Rosalie, for those of you guys who sat
in our um
Mongolia missions sharing, Rosalie
shared last Sunday that your prayers
mean so much out there in the missions
field. We we take it for granted when we
pray. Pray for safety, pray for this,
pray for that. Pray that obstacles would
move.
You know, anything can happen out there.
Anything can happen. There are so many
things that can go wrong.
There are so many obstacles, hurdles,
not to mention spiritual attacks from
Satan that can derail months of
planning.
So much is so out of our control.
But so much is in the control of the
almighty sovereign God.
So your blanket of prayer
has a much deeper and more powerful
effect than you can ever imagine.
How about supporting and encouraging our
missionaries? I know some of the small
groups have adopted a missionary.
Where you all are in contact with the
missionary, you check in on them, you
pray for them and you give them
encouragement. You know, that's so
valuable out there. It's so lonely out
there.
And your encouragement means a lot.
And when you go out on short-term
missions,
a vital role that you play is
encouraging the local church, the local
missions, the long-term missionaries who
are doing the outreach work. And I've
heard multiple times out there
that our mere presence
out there when we're with them
gives them tremendous encouragement.
The church has sent.
What can we learn from the attributes of
Barnabas and Saul, Paul?
And it says in our verse,
"Set apart for me Barnabas and Saul for
the work to which I have called them."
And how did these two guys, how did they
respond to the Holy Spirit's call?
Well, we we read of course that they
went.
And the passage doesn't really say
did they struggle or did they wrestle
with their decision?
But based on the terseness of our
passage and what we know about them, I
don't think they struggled when they
were called to go.
What do we know about these two guys?
What what led them to the respond the
way they did? I just want to spend a
couple minutes talking about their
attributes and their attitude.
And it's a model for the way we can
respond when God is calling us.
Barnabas. Barnabas' name, and many of
you know this, his name literally means
son of encouragement. And he certainly
lives up to his name.
He was one of the ones he was the one
who was sent from the Jerusalem church
to check out the Antioch church when it
was formed. And they did that to they
they sent him not only to examine them
but to encourage and support them.
And we see in him a willingness to serve
others.
And Barnabas was the one who recruited
and sought out Paul, Saul, for
additional help. Now, what do we know
about Paul?
Paul had an infamous past as many of you
know that he was a persecutor of the
church. And in fact, it's it's a little
ironic
that he was part of the very persecution
of Stephen that drove the Jewish
believers to Antioch to found this very
church that he's now serving in. It's
kind of ironic.
Now, also when Paul was zapped and
blinded by Jesus on the road to Damascus
and was sent to Ananias to be healed,
Ananias was afraid of him
because of his reputation.
And Jesus said to Ananias in Acts
chapter 9 verse 15, he says this,
"Go,
for he is a chosen instrument of mine to
carry my name before the Gentiles and
the kings and the children of Israel."
Paul was an instrument of Jesus
to proclaim his name.
In chapter 11,
Paul for his part was willing to drop
whatever he was doing. When he was asked
by Barnabas to come help out at the
Antioch church, he
um Barnabas went out to Tarsus to look
for him and when he found him, he just
dropped whatever he was doing and went
with him to serve the Antioch church.
Paul was the consummate teacher and
spent his energy preaching and teaching
about Jesus.
And the both of them so the both of
them, they threw themselves into the
ministry alongside the brothers and
sisters at the Antioch church. And now
we see in chapter 13, our passage, we
see them submitting
to the calling of the Holy Spirit to be
sent.
And so I just want to highlight a few of
their attributes.
They were clearly missional-minded.
They were willing to share the gospel to
everyone and anyone.
And they made themselves available.
Their agenda was God's agenda.
They showed a willingness to serve
wherever God sent them. And I wonder how
much
are we
willing to be available the same way?
Or do we get hung up with excuses?
They were flexible. They were adaptable.
They were willing to drop their agenda,
their schedules, whatever they were
doing to serve the Lord. And this is a
key trait for missionaries. Something
that I've heard and learned over again
and again in the field.
Because you can make all the plans you
want, but you don't know how God's going
to use you once you get out there.
And they were willing. They were willing
to be sent. Barnabas from the Jerusalem
church and here again, he was sent from
the Antioch church and Paul, he followed
the way after Jesus. I don't think Paul
had a home.
I don't think he's got a place to stay
permanently. From the moment of his
conversion on the road to Damascus, Paul
was always on the move to share the
gospel message proclaiming the risen
Christ throughout the Roman world up
until he was martyred in Rome.
And they were both selfless.
And they had a heart of a servant. Paul
embodied the term living sacrifice. I
mean, he fully lived a surrendered life.
We know that multiple times Paul
suffered for the gospel.
In 1 Corinthians 11, Paul recounts that
he was flogged multiple times. He was a
beaten with rods. He was pelted with
stones. He was shipwrecked, imprisoned
multiple times and he was left for dead.
Yet amazingly,
he remained faithful to Jesus
and to his calling to minister to the
Gentiles. In his letter to Philip to the
Philippians, he wrote,
"For me to live is Christ
and to die is gain."
These are all attributes and attitudes
that we should all have in common when
we are responding to God's call for us.
But I ask this question, are all called
to go?
Are all called to mission specifically
cross-cultural missions?
And here's the last topic.
What's my mission in the Great
Commission?
Your mission
is and here let me just show you the
Great Commission one more time here.
Your mission
in the Great Commission is a
your your mission is a continuation of
the Great Commission. That's your
mission.
All are called to fulfill the Great
Commission. Now, at this point in a
talk,
some people teach and guilt trip people
that all are called to go on
cross-cultural missions and and I don't
actually think that that's right. Um and
I probably hear a sigh of relief in some
people here.
I do believe that however that all are
called to fulfill the Great Commission.
As pre as
Sorry. As Rick Warren said,
he said, "The Great Commission is not
the great suggestion."
All right?
Part of the Great Commission, of course,
is sharing the good news of Jesus
locally.
In our community, in our schools, in our
work, to our friends, to our families.
Really, the missions field
is right at our door,
right next door. Right?
And sometimes it's coming into our
doors.
It's our sphere of influence.
The Great Commandment and the Great
Commission,
those two
answer all of life's tough questions.
Why am I here?
What's my purpose in life?
How should I live my life?
The good news
is the good news
for everyone,
everywhere, including here.
But we shouldn't stop locally.
We do need to participate in God's
global missions.
The Great Commission is active today and
continues to the ends of the earth.
The gospel message and God's plan in the
Great Commission did not stop
at the Book of Acts.
God is still at work in the world today.
And while there are many areas that are
well-trodden and the gospel message is
widely available in many places, there
are still many areas in the world that
are still unreached.
And many of you guys are familiar with
the 10/40 window,
this 10/40 latitude window.
There's still much of the world that has
not heard.
The green areas on the map are areas
where that are considered no longer
unreached,
where there is a strong Christian
presence.
The red areas are unreached people
groups. And how do they define that?
They define it as people groups with
less than 2% evangelical Christian
populations.
And in some of these red areas,
there are no known efforts focused on
reaching out to them and establishing
self-sustaining churches
with evangelical faith and practices.
So, for more details, you know, if you
go I I wrote this down,
peoplegroups.org. Don't do it right now,
but write this down, peoplegroups.org.
They have a really cool interactive map
where you can
flip around the globe and pick these
different areas and just learn about
these different areas.
Now,
here's the question.
How do I know what my calling is? How do
I know if I'm being called to go?
How do I know if and how I'm being
called to send?
I really want to take this
mystery
out of the word calling.
It's really a confusing term. This This
we we throw it around a lot. What's my
calling? Right? Or I'm called to do
this. I'm called to It's a confusing
term and frankly, it's often misused.
>> [clears throat]
>> Calling or invitation in the New
Testament almost always refers to our
calling as believers.
It's not a calling to a particular
ministry.
I'm just going to show you a few verses.
1 Corinthians 1:2 says, "We're called to
be saints
together with all those who in every
place call upon the name of our Lord
Jesus Christ." And in Ephesians 1:18, it
says this, "that you may know what is
the hope to which he has called you."
The hope that he has called you.
And then Hebrews 3:1 says, "You who
share in a heavenly calling, consider
Jesus."
So, most of the time when you read
throughout the Bible about where it
refers to calling,
it's refers to a calling of faith.
Essentially, it's a call to become a
follower of Christ.
And here's how it's kind of misused.
Sometimes calling is used improperly
to elevate one's spiritual status.
It's as if my sense of calling, of
divine calling, to my particular
profession obligates others to treat me
in a special way.
That's not the way to use the word
calling.
Okay. So, what is the right way to look
at being called to a particular
ministry?
How do I know what my calling is for any
given ministry?
All right.
In our passage,
what happened? The Holy Spirit directed
directly called out Paul and Barnabas
for this missions trip.
Now, for almost all all of us,
myself included, we will not be called
out by name
by the Holy Spirit in a prayer meeting.
It's very unlikely that you'll be
blinded by Jesus and called to serve a
particular people while out taking a
walk.
So, how do we know?
How do we know which ministry God is
calling you to?
How do we know if God is calling you
specifically to cross-cultural ministry?
Here's where I really want to take the
mystery out of what it means to be
called. And by the way, this applies to
any ministry, not just missions, but
yes, definitely missions.
You discover God's calling
to you in three phases.
Learn, discern, and confirm.
Learn, discern, and confirm. So, learn.
We first need to take a posture of a
student.
And for the youth here, this is
important for you, but it's also really
This is important for all of us here.
The posture of a student is, "I'm here
to learn. I'm here to explore.
I'm here to discover."
It's opening yourself to the
possibilities and to make yourself
available,
a willing heart to be used by God, a
teachable heart, much like the posture
of Paul and Barnabas.
I want to learn
what God is doing in the world.
See what he is already doing in
different missions fields.
Find out what opportunities are out
there.
Remember, God already has a plan. He's
already working
through people, through organizations,
through other churches.
His plan is already active and it's
unfolding.
You're exploring how you can be part of
God's plan.
And there's many ways to learn.
Some of you guys have taken the
Perspective class. We just hosted the
Perspective class.
By the way, just show of hands, how many
people have taken the Perspective class
before?
Okay, some of you guys. You know, Esther
and Pat and others organized this at our
church last year and it's a great
course. I I would encourage you to take
it next time it's offered.
There are a lot of online options. My
gosh, that doesn't show up very well.
Okay, that says joshuaproject.net.
Okay, joshuaproject.net.net.
There's a lot of online resources here.
This This will help out a little bit.
There are a lot of online resources to
learn about what God is doing in the
world. And this is a great resource.
Um this website talks about different
frontier groups and what different
mission organizations are doing.
Go to a missions conference. You know,
Seattle has a
yearly missions fest that our church
plays an active part in. The next one
coming up is October 16th through 17th.
You know, join that. It's a great way to
learn and hear what God is doing in
missions.
You don't have to go anywhere.
Um if you're in college or if you're a
junior or senior in high school, um
check out Urbana. I went to Urbana many
years ago as a college student. It's a
great It's great time and a great place
to just discover this. Um it happens
every 3 years. Um and the next one is
December 2028. So, again, if you're a
junior or senior in high school, you're
going to be hitting right at the time
that this is happening. I encourage you
to go.
All right. Find out how God is already
at work throughout the world and see if
God may be calling you to join in what
he's already doing.
And in this learn And in this learning
phase, it's all about discovery. And
then next comes this next phase,
discern.
How do you discern whether God is
calling you to go?
There's a few things that you can ask. I
mean, let's just run through this
quickly.
Passion.
Do I have a passion for this? God will
rarely make you do something that you
hate.
Do I have a passion? Do I have the
gifting? Do I have the ability, the
skills, the aptitude for doing this? Ask
yourself, does this ministry fit the way
God made me?
Opportunity.
Is God presenting an opportunity for me
to go? We see many times, many examples
in the Bible where sometimes God's God's
call is just someone asking them to go.
Barnabas went to Tarsus to find Paul to
help in Antioch. In Paul's secondary
second missionary
journey in Acts 15, Paul chose Silas to
go with him. Barnabas chose Mark to go
with him.
In Acts 16, Paul was in Lystra. He heard
that Timothy had this good reputation.
So Paul asked Timothy to join him in his
missions trip.
For both of both Silas and Timothy,
Paul's invitation,
just that alone, was enough for them to
go.
Instead of waiting for some miraculous
sign, just look for opportunities.
And prayer. Prayer. Here Here's a
dangerous thing you could do.
You can ask God to show you
opportunities for you to go.
Super dangerous.
You could ask God to open doors for you
to go.
Do pray that God would open your eyes,
open your hearts
to his missionary work.
The Holy Spirit.
Ask the Holy Spirit to guide you and
lead you in missions. Ask the Holy
Spirit to reveal to you how you can
fulfill the Great Commission.
And the Holy Spirit I don't have time to
go over this, but the Holy Spirit works
in so many different ways. In
circumstances,
in opening and closing doors, speaking
and convicting to you in scripture,
speaking directly to your soul in ways
that only the Holy Spirit
can. And yes, sometimes by visions,
sometimes by miracles.
And this is also key, the wise counsel
of others. One of the ways that the Holy
Spirit does work is that he can speak to
you through the wise counsel of others.
And many times I have asked fellow
mature brothers and sisters in Christ
what they thought about my next steps.
If I should step into a particular
ministry, if I have the right skills
and the calling to do so.
Confirm.
For any ministry, just try it out.
[snorts]
You know, sometimes we just need to go
and do.
Whether that's serving in the church,
serving in a particular ministry, or
missions. You know, for missions,
there's a lot of opportunities here.
Short-term missions, medium-term
missions. It's a great opportunity to
explore is God calling me to do missions
work.
And in doing the work,
is the Holy Spirit confirming your
choice?
Are others affirming your calling and
recognizing your role, your gifting?
Recently, Steve Pastor Steve Morris,
Steve Steve was just ordained.
And as he shared last week, it was a
long journey that got before he got
there.
Um as part of his ordination, a council
of elders and pastors met to confirm his
calling as a pastor.
But here's the interesting thing about
it.
It's not like he wasn't already doing
the work. He was.
He was already doing the work of a
pastor,
a shepherd, an overseer.
Part of his ordination was just a
confirmation that he is called to serve
as a pastor.
And you don't need to be ordained to do
the work God is calling you to do.
Try doing the ministry that you think
God is leading you to do.
See if that lines up with your gifting
and if you have an aptitude for it.
See if you really do
have a passion for that and see if
others recognize and affirm your calling
to do it.
And see if the Holy Spirit, in all the
ways that he works, confirms your
ministry.
Let me conclude with this.
Pastor Rick said this, "A great
commitment to the Great Commandment and
the Great Commission will make you a
great Christian." I shared that with a
youth
last last Sunday.
The Great Commandment,
"Love your God with all your heart, with
all your soul, with all your mind."
And the Great Commission,
"Go and make disciples of all nations."
A commitment to both
will make you a great Christian.
We're all called to fulfill the Great
Commission. We need to discover how God
will use us,
our God-given gifts, our resources,
our ability to share the good news of
Jesus to those around us and beyond us.
Is God Is God calling you to send?
Is God calling you to go?
Let's pray.
Father God,
you have a plan.
You are working out your Great
Commission even now as we speak.
Father God,
you are always calling us
to heed your call to both the Great
Commandment and the Great Commission.
Father God, give us
eyes to see, ears to hear hear, and
hearts that are ready, open, and willing
to receive your call. May we we May we
respond in a way that glorifies you.
We pray these things in Christ's name.
Amen.
Thank you, Elton.
Very convicting. And in fact, we're
going to be sending off Elton here in a
bit. Let's go ahead and stand. Let's
sing in response.
>> [music]
[music]
>> You're the son of God
[singing and music] and man.
>> [music]
>> You're the firstborn
over all
>> [singing]
>> creation.
>> [music]
>> Whether rulers, thrones, or powers,
>> [singing]
[music]
>> you made them all.
And [music] you rule [singing]
them as well.
>> [music]
>> So whatever [singing] your will may be,
would you make [music and singing] it
part of me?
Would you take [music] me?
Take [singing] these
hands. Take these feet. Take my
[singing] life. [music] It is yours to
keep, God almighty.
God [singing]
almighty, [music]
use me
>> [singing]
>> in ways I could not imagine.
Call me by [music] name, Lord, into
[singing] your presence.
Jesus,
[music]
king of
glory. [singing]
>> [music]
>> Before the world began,
>> before the world [singing] began,
my [singing and music] life
My life was made
[music] in your hands. [singing]
Before the stars [music] were put in
their place,
you looked into [music and singing] the
future and called
me by name.
So whatever [music]
[singing] your will may be,
would you make [music and singing] it
part of me?
Would you take me?
Take [music and singing]
these hands. Take these feet. Take my
[music and singing] life. It is yours to
keep, God almighty.
>> [music]
>> God [singing]
almighty,
use me
in ways
I could [music and singing] not imagine.
Call me by
Lord, into your presence. [singing]
Jesus,
[music]
king of glory. [singing]
Take
these hands. [music] Take these feet.
Take Take my [singing]
life. It is yours to keep. [music] God
almighty.
>> [music and singing]
>> God almighty.
Use me in
>> [music and singing]
>> ways I cannot imagine.
Call me by name. Lord, into [singing]
your
>> [music]
>> Jesus,
king [singing] of glory. [music]
>> [singing]
[music]
>> Amen. Would you please be seated?
This morning, um it's it's somewhat
convenient, if you will, uh that Elton
was talking about sending and going. And
this morning, we're actually going to be
sending Elton off. He's going on a
missions trip starting tomorrow. And I
actually wanted him to come up and and
share a bit about what he's going to be
doing.
So, just just briefly, cuz I I know
we're running a little bit over time. Um
uh if you can just show that slide at
the end of my uh talk, um
uh
uh somewhat toward the last minute, I
was asked by um
uh a local team from um
Indonesia
uh to go to Indonesia with some brothers
and sisters from Encounter Church uh
because they needed a physician to do
some medical outreach work uh to the
Sundanese people uh which is an
unreached people group um less than half
percent Christians, 99 plus percent
Muslim.
Um and they're uh I'm going there to
just elevate and support the local team
uh for them to build relationships with
the Sundanese people. Uh I'll be doing
some medical screenings, some public
health talks, uh along with some of the
other folks uh on the team doing other
work as well. So, really would covet
your prayer. Um it's a little bit rough
time to be traveling right now. So, uh
just uh pray for safety. Pray for our
team to be effective. Pray that we would
be able to um reach out and make inroads
uh to the Sundanese people in Indonesia.
Thank you. Thanks, Elton. What I'd Stay
up here. What I'd like to do is if
you're on English Council and you're not
in the middle of doing something,
whether you're in the hall or what have
you, or if at the back table, if you're
in the English Council, could you please
join me uh as we pray for Elton uh
today?
So, anybody who's all right part of
English Council, if you're not in the
middle of doing something, please come
on up to the stage. Uh let's pray for
Elton together.
And everyone in the congregation, if you
wouldn't mind just, you know, extending
your hand uh to Elton, whether it be
physical or um just in your hearts.
We're going to be lifting up our brother
this morning.
Let's pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I thank you that
you have
built Elton the way you have, that
you've gifted him the way you have, that
you've skilled him the way you have, and
that he has made himself available to
you for this trip.
Lord, it is a small team. It's only five
folks, and they needed somebody to help
fill this particular role with a
particular skill set. And and they asked
Elton to do that, and he's made himself
available.
Lord, we ask, of course, you and us
Elton spoke about earlier today. Of
course, we ask for safety.
Of course, we ask for the removal of
obstacles.
We recognize at the same time you know
what's going to happen there. You've
seen it happen already uh from beginning
to end, even before we've stepped into
it over here on this side of heaven.
Lord, as Elton also said
we prepare, we make our plans, and then,
Lord, you know what's going to actually
happen on the field. So, I do pray for
flexibility for the whole team, uh for
Elton, even though he's got a particular
role. Lord, we know that that may morph
as he goes out there.
We do ask, Lord, uh especially for the
the situation in we're in right now in
our world. Traveling there as an
American uh is not uh not an easy thing.
And Lord, I just pray that the people
that this group encounters would feel
your love through this people. That they
would look beyond uh nationalities or
what have you. Lord, that they would see
truly just your love for them. That they
would be blown away um by what it is
you've done to send your own son to die
for us on a cross. Lord, for those who
are from a different belief system,
Lord, that is going to be um
unbelievable in many ways.
And so, Lord, we just ask that you would
give open hearts and open ears to the
people that they are going to encounter.
Pray, Lord, for um health as everybody
heads over there. Um
just pray for um
Pray for the people to come together in
unity, the people that are all going.
For all of us, Lord, who are back here,
we continue to pray for them as uh
they're out there, Lord, that you would
sustain them.
So, Lord, we lift up Elton to you. We
thank you for his willingness to serve
and drop what he's doing and go. And
Lord, I just ask that you would um
when he returns, Lord, we will to hear
of the amazing things that you've done
through him and the team.
Thank you for Elton and that whole team,
and we just put them into your awesome
almighty and sovereign hands. In
Christ's name, we pray. Amen.
Thank you. Thank you.
And now, if you wouldn't mind standing
for the benediction.
Now, to him who is able to do far more
abundantly than all we can ask or think
according to the power at work within us
to him be glory in the church and in
Christ Jesus throughout all generations
forever and ever. Amen. Please be
seated.
I got smart and stayed up here this
time.
>> [gasps]
>> Good morning again, church. Welcome
[sighs] to today's service. Um before I
get into the announcements, I just want
to welcome anybody who's here for the
first time. Uh we just want to give you
an information packet. Uh make sure that
you're welcomed um properly. Uh anyone
on this side of the
uh of the room uh just raise your hands.
Sorry, in case that wasn't clear.
Uh okay. This side of the room?
Anyone over here?
Okay. Uh if you are in the overflow,
also please just raise your hand. Uh
there will be ushers out there also to
give you our welcome package.
On to announcements, the most exciting
thing. Here we go.
Uh Sunday school, we are starting a new
series, A Long Belong. Uh it explores
Christian identity in the secular world,
uh framing the faith journey from the
perspective of an immigrant, uh where
our citizenship is firmly rooted in the
kingdom of heaven.
Uh the dates are there, and the location
will be here.
Uh connect to reconnect. Uh this is a
lunch that we've been having. Um
we are extending it to newcomers and
just folks who want to uh reconnect to
um
their families. Uh it's a time of
welcome uh and also to get to know our
elders and pastors and other church
leaders. Uh we'll be having it at uh
different uh different elders and and
pastors' houses. In this case, it will
be Pastor Max's house uh 516 uh on
Saturday.
Uh youth minister search updates. Uh we
have a new candidate, uh Sam Kui. Uh he
will be visiting our church. Uh Sam, I
think, has been involved on the Seattle
side um uh on our missions uh and I
think he's a member as well there. Uh
there's going to be a bunch of Q&A
sessions uh coming up, and he will
actually uh 2 weeks from today um
on Mother's Day be preaching over on the
youth side. So, not this not next
Sunday, but the one after that. Um so,
if you are interested in hearing him
hearing him preach, uh make a note in
your calendars to join um to listen to
him on the other side.
Uh we've been talking about our
governance restructuring. Uh as ECC
grows, the way that we
uh are structured essentially needs to
grow along with that. Uh there's a bunch
of inefficiencies that people have uh
identified. Um and uh and a lot of folks
have taken a long time to try to put
something together uh that will
streamline and hopefully solve a lot of
these issues. Um we've kind of
solidified the plan now, and so uh we're
starting to present it uh in a whole
form uh to you folks. Um the first town
hall is going to be on 517 at 11:15
right here.
So, make a note to join.
Um Vacation Bible School, summer is
coming up once again. Uh the dates are
there uh
uh July and or no, June and July. Uh and
the QR code is there. Uh it's going to
be a great time for all our kids, as it
usually is, and a lot of work for the
rest of us.
Ping Ling,
um we are sending a bunch of folks over
to Taiwan uh fairly soon.
Uh and in response, Taiwan is also going
to be sending a bunch of students over
here.
Uh if you have the um the calling
uh and the opportunity, here is an
opportunity to be a host family.
Um and uh if you're interested in doing
that or volunteering to help out, uh
there's going to be a meeting on April
26th. Um
and it's uh also in person and on Zoom
and the information is there.
Right. So, Taiwan missions, as I
mentioned, we are sending folks over and
um as usual, they are sharing Taiwan
cuisine uh in a fundraiser. Uh it's
going to be on May 15th uh between 6:00
and 7:30 uh and it's just going to be uh
just in the lobby outside. Um come and
try stuff out. They're they uh
uh there's always really good food there
and uh good time of fellowship.
Uh eyeglass donations, Lee is coming up.
Good morning, brothers uh dear brothers
and sisters. I'm from the um Mandarin
congregation. I just announced the
glasses donations. We've been uh
launching the glasses drive.
Just warmly invite you to take part.
And do you have any prescription or
reading glasses at home?
These glasses may be forgotten in your
drawer.
But,
>> [snorts]
>> those glasses could help great help
for the people far away.
And over 70 people 70% of people in
developing country lack proper glasses.
Through mission team, the global glasses
ministry will distribute the donated
glasses to the people who needs.
A simple a simple glasses
can change people's life.
Can help
student learn, adult work,
and elder to read again.
By through donation your glasses,
you can
bring not only to help clear vision,
also can sharing your hope,
dignity, and the love.
Yeah. You're welcome to donate your
glasses. And this box will be on the
hallway at by the door at the hallway.
And the due date is June 30th.
And thank you. Thank you for your
support.
We already got the We already launched a
couple of weeks. We already got more
than 100 pairs. If you already donated,
thank you. We We can take more. Thanks.
>> [applause]
>> All right. Um open position,
administrative assistant. Uh we are
seeking a detailed-oriented bilingual uh
person to be an administrative uh
assistant um here at ECC uh for Redmond.
Uh if you are interested in that, uh
then the information is there. apply.
Uh join us for the ordination service.
We have two new elders. Um
they're on the Seattle campus um and
they're going to be ordained on May the
3rd at 1:30.
Uh it's that time again, deacon
nominations. Um if you again feel called
uh
to be a deacon um or you see somebody
who uh who you think would be a good
deacon, then please uh nominate them.
Um Grace uh up at the church office has
the forms. Uh you must be an ECC member
um and if you are going to be nominated,
uh
um we need three folks to uh nominate
you as well. So, the deadline for that
to submit that is going to be uh May
3rd.
Uh if I went through this too quickly,
the worship bulletins are online at
eccseattle.org. There's a QR code there
as well.
Um and of course, you can come talk to
any of us if you have any questions.
Uh giving methods, um
uh tithing is a core part of the
Christian walk. Uh we offer several
methods to do this uh which are all
there.
Uh and if you have any questions, please
email finance@eccseattle.org.
Other than that, thank you. Have a
blessed week.