Good morning everyone. Let's go and
stand. Let's worship the Lord together.
You are the Lord,
the famous one. Famous one. Great is
your name in all the earth.
The heavens declare
your glorious,
glorious,
great is your fame beyond
the earth. You are the Lord.
You are the Lord.
The famous one. Nameless one. Great is
your name in all the earth.
The heavens
declare
your glorious,
glorious,
great is your faith beyond
the earth.
for all you've done
and yet to do.
With every
breath
I'm praising you.
Desire
of nations
and every heart.
You alone are God.
You are the Lord.
The famous one. famous one. Great is
your name in all the earth.
The heavens declare
your glorious,
glorious,
great is your fame beyond
the earth.
The morning
star
is shining through
and every
eye
is watching you.
reveal
my nature
and miracles.
You are beautiful.
The morning
star
is shining through
and every
eye
is watching you.
reveal
by nature
and miracles.
You are beautiful.
You are the Lord.
The famous one. Famous one. Great is
your name in all the earth.
The heavens
declare
your glorious,
glorious.
Great is your fame beyond
the earth. You are the Lord.
You are the Lord.
The fameless one. Fameless one. Great is
your name in all the earth.
Heavens declare
your glorious,
glorious,
great is your fame beyond
the earth.
Amen. Welcome to Evangelical Chinese
Church. For those of you who might be
with us that are new, an especially warm
welcome to you. And for those of you who
might be joining us online, we'd love to
see you in person here. U there's
actually for those of you who might be
in the east lobby. There's still a fair
number of uh seats here in the main
hall, too, if you want to just come on
in. Um we are here to worship our Lord
this morning. Um why don't we just spend
a minute just welcoming the people
around us. Just say hello to them and
welcome them in the name of the Lord
this morning.
This morning we're going to be singing
about God and his sovereignty, the fact
that he has brought his uh salvation to
many people who would otherwise not have
heard it. And uh this morning we're
going to be singing some songs that are
so old that they're going to appear new.
Uh some of them are older than people in
this room. Uh some of them are on the
newer side, what have you. But we're
here to worship our Lord together.
That's why we gather. So would you bow
your heads with me as we lift this time
up to our Lord. Heavenly Father, thank
you for this day. Thank you for the
opportunity we have to come and worship
you. Thank you for the gorgeous weather
you've given to us today. Uh Lord, we
just ask that you would help us to set
aside and shed the things that are
distracting us this morning. Allow us to
worship you, Lord, in spirit and in
truth. And uh Lord, we just lift up your
name. Lord, thank you for this chance
for us to come and worship you today. In
Christ's name we pray. Amen.
>> You live. You died. You said in three
days you would rise. You dead.
You're alive.
>> You rule.
You reign.
You said you're coming back again. I
know that you will. All the earth will
sing your praises.
All the earth will sing your praises.
You took
you take our sins away. Oh God,
you give you gave your life away for us.
You came down. You saved us through the
cross.
Our hearts are changed because of your
great love.
You live.
You died. You said in three days you
will arise. You did.
You're alive.
You rule.
You reign.
You said you're coming back again. I
know that you will. All the earth will
sing your praises.
All the earth will sing your praises.
You took
you take our sins away. Oh God,
you give you gave your life away for us.
You came down. You saved us through the
cross.
Our hearts are changed because of your
great love.
You lived,
you died. You said in three days you
were rise. You dead.
You're alive.
You rule. You reign. You said you're
coming back again. I know that you will.
All the earth will sing your praises.
You live. You died. You said in three
days you arise. You did.
You're alive.
You rule.
You reign. You said you're coming back
again. I know that you will. All the
earth will sing your praises.
All the earth will sing your praises.
Breathing through the silence.
with glory in the highest.
The hope of all creation
resting in his mother's arms.
>> A song on the horizon,
ringing through the heavens.
The long awaited Savior
come to set the captives free.
Come to set the captives free.
Come set us free.
Hope has a name, Emmanuel,
the light of the world, who broke
through the darkness.
All hail the king Emmanuel,
the light of the world, the glory of
heaven.
We didn't see it coming.
The story of redemption
was started in a manger.
and in an empty grave. Oh, I know that
hope has a name, Emmanuel,
the light of the world, who broke
through the darkness.
All hail the king Emmanuel,
the light of the world, the glory of
heaven.
Come if you're broken.
Come if you're searching,
if you need healing,
he's where you find it. You lay down
your burdens.
Breathe in forgiveness.
If you need freedom,
yeah, he's here where you find it. Oh,
if you need freedom,
Yeah. He's where you find it.
Yeah. He's where you find it. Oh,
hope has a name.
Emmanuel,
the light of the world, who broke
through the darkness.
All hail the king Emmanuel,
the light of the world, the glory of
heaven.
Hope has a name. Emmanuel,
the light of the world, who broke
through the darkness.
All hail the king
Emmanuel,
the light of the world, the glory of
heaven.
>> Amen. Bow your heads with me if you
would. Heavenly Father, thank you for
being uh a God that saves, a God that
saves in ways that we might find
surprising. Thank you, Lord, for
bringing us um salvation through your
son, Jesus. Uh when we repent of our
sins and trust in him as our savior. And
Lord, this morning, I just want to
recognize, Lord, that there are things
in our lives that we don't recognize or
we don't understand when we're going
through them. But only in looking back
2020 in hindsight can we see your hand
and your your grace uh in those
situations even. And so Lord, as we
think think about and as we learn this
morning and as we hear about uh your
sovereignty in what it is you're
accomplishing and what the ways you do
things, Lord, I pray that in our own
circumstances where we might be feeling
like, hey, where are you? Lord, that you
would um just help us and remind us that
you are there and that in time you would
show us how you are with us every step
of the way. In Christ's name we pray.
Amen.
Sovereign in the mountain air. So on the
ocean floor with me in the calm.
With me in the storm.
So in my greatest joy. So in my deepest
cry. With me in the dark,
with me at the dawn.
In your everlasting arms, all the pieces
of my life. From the beginning to the
end, I can trust you
in your never failing love. You work
everything for good. God, whatever comes
my way, I will trust you.
So in the mountain air, sovereign on the
ocean flow. With me in the calm,
with me in the storm.
So in my greatest joy, sovereign in my
deepest cry. With me in the dark,
with me at the dawn,
in your everlasting arms, all the pieces
of my life. From beginning to the end, I
can trust you
in your never failing love. You work
everything for good. God, whatever comes
my way, I will trust you.
God, whatever comes my way, I will trust
you.
All my hopes, all I need, held in your
hands.
All my life, all of me, held in your
All my fears, all my dreams held in your
hands.
All my hopes, all I need, held in your
All my life, all of me. Hell in your
hands.
All my fears, all my dreams, held in
your hands.
In your everlasting arms, all the pieces
of my life from beginning to the end. I
can trust you
in your never failing love. You work
everything for good, God. Whatever comes
my way, I will trust you,
God. Whatever comes my way, I will trust
you,
you.
Let's pray.
Lord God, you are indeed the sovereign
one. You are the famous one.
Great is your name in all the earth.
All of creation gives testimony of your
glory.
Who are we that you would be mindful of
us? Who are we
who are so undeserving
and yet on us you have shown exceeding
mercy, amazing grace and unfathomable
love. To you be the glory forever and
ever.
Father God, we lift up to you all eight
congregations of ECC. You have called us
as one family in Christ. May we as a
united church with one voice give you
the glory do your name. And Father God,
we lift up as we take turns, we lift up
to you um our Edmonds Mandaring
Congregation prayer requests. First of
all, we thank you for their united
ministry council who are serving in love
and harmony. We thank you and we praise
you that you have given them a vision to
love you, to love others, to serve
faithfully, and to pass on that faith to
those around them.
Father God, we ask that you would give
them wisdom and unity as they make plans
for the Mandarin and English
congregations to stagger their sanctuary
use for Sunday worship. We pray for all
those details and coordination that
needs to happen for that to happen.
Father God, we also pray for their
families as well as families throughout
ECC who are facing illness and
relational challenges. Father God, may
you bring healing, restoration, and
peace.
We also lift up to you our missionaries
that we support. And particularly this
morning, we lift up to you Wendy Wong
and her husband Anowan who have been
serving in Thailand for the past 14
years. We pray that you would continue
to work through them as they serve the
Aka people. Father God, may you spread
your good news of your gospel message of
your son Jesus through the local church,
through the Chinese schools and the
children's home for broken families and
orphans. May you share your good news to
the people of Thailand.
And Father God, we also pray for the
world. We pray for Micronesia as they
are recovering from the aftermath of a
typhoon Sin Laku. We pray that you would
um work through the first responders as
they rescue people from the storm damage
and we pray that you would um help those
who have lost their homes and their
livelihoods and comfort those who have
suffered loss.
Father God, we also lift up to you the
churches and the campus ministries that
are serving the the colleges throughout
the US. Um we pray that you would um
work through them and be with them as
they minister to the students, the
millions of students who are preparing
to graduate. We pray that you would uh
help them uh not only prepare for their
careers but also for the next part of
their spiritual walk with you. We pray
that they would be able to connect with
new church communities after they
graduate.
Father God, we also lift up to you um uh
just Iran and we pray for a sustained
peace in Iran. We also pray for an end
to the war in Ukraine. And we also lift
up to you our brother, Pastor Steve, who
will be giving uh the message this
morning. We pray that you would speak
through him and may you uh prepare our
hearts and minds to receive your
message. And now, let's say the Lord's
Prayer together. Our Father in heaven,
hallowed be your name. Your kingdom
come, your will be done on earth as it
is in heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread, and forgive us our debts as we
also have forgiven our debtors. And lead
us not into temptation, but deliver us
from evil. For yours is the kingdom, and
the power, and the glory forever and
ever. Amen. Please be seated.
Okay, good. Well, good morning everyone.
>> Thank you for being here uh and willing
to listen to this message that I'll be
preparing for you. Uh it's been a while
since I've been here at Redmond campus
to share God's message with you. The
last time I was here, I was uh youth
director. I still am a youth director.
However, uh I've been given the uh the
title uh or the church has seen fit that
I seem fit to get the title of pastor.
So, I come to you this morning as pastor
Steve. I think the name uh
I think the name will still I've been
telling everyone that uh it'll get some
getting used to because I've been called
a minister for the last 12 years. So it
might take 12 years to to be comfortable
with the name of pastor. Uh but I still
enjoy working with the youth. I think a
lot of people have been asking what do
you want to do? Uh and I still enjoy the
youth. Uh, I hope they enjoy me uh as
I'm ministering to them and I hope that
uh that yeah that moving forward this
will be uh this will be a good time for
me to glorify God in all that I do. So,
so as you can see from the graphic this
morning, the gospel, the power of God,
this is our series that we've been doing
for the last five years and we are at
the uh I guess the tail end of it and
that is this um the the power of God. So
this morning I will be sharing on the
power to scatter from Acts chapter 8:es
1 to8.
This five-year plan that we've been
going on has illustrated to us how God
moves a movement of of different parts
of of the gospel message. We've been
able to to walk alongside um previously
we'll see um here we go the gospel
message, the gospel impact and now the
gospel mission. And we are recapping now
in this last portion of it in the next
few months under the power of God and
what it means what it means to us having
the power of God. So the power of God
for us is
learning and understanding what it um
how the gospel message affects our
lives. So, we've been taught in the last
few months about how it reconciles us,
uh how it sets us free,
how it con it renews us and it conquers
all. And last week, Minister Chris was
able to share on one aspect of being
sanctified. And being sanctified means
to be set apart for God's purposes. So,
let me ask you a question this morning,
ECC Redmond, those here and online.
Have you had a moment in your life when
life didn't go according to plan?
When everything was disrupted, you know,
everything was going fine. Everything
you felt everything was stable and then
suddenly everything shifts beneath your
feet and your routine gets changed up
and your plans get disrupted or gets
cancelled.
That is exactly what we'll be learning
in learning about and stepping into with
the early church in Acts chapter 8.
There's a disruption in the lives of the
Christians there and we will walk
through this disruption together this
morning. So, if you're able, please rise
and let's read this passage together.
And Saul approved of his execution. And
there arose on that day a great
persecution against the church in
Jerusalem. And they were all scattered
throughout the regions of Judea and
Samaria except the apostles. Devout men
buried Steven and made a great
lamentation over him. But Saul was
ravaging the church and entering house
after house. He dragged off men and
women and committed them to prison. Now
those who were scattered went about
preaching the word. Philillip went down
to the city of Samaria and proclaimed to
them the Christ. And the crowds of one
accord paid attention to what was being
said by Philillip. When they heard him
and saw the signs that he did, for
unclean spirits crying out with a loud
voice came out of many who had them, and
many who were paralyzed and lame were
healed. So there was much joy in that
city. Please remain standing as we pray.
Father God, we come to you this morning
willing to listen to your words,
willing to see how you will guide us in
our daily lives. May we understand how
you are working through the scriptures,
working through disruption
to achieve your purposes
in your son's most holy name. Jesus
Christ we do pray. Amen. You may be
seated.
So this morning we are we'll be walking
together through Acts chapter 8 verses 1
to8. And these are three different
lessons or points that I would like to
to illustrate or to highlight. The first
one God uses disruption to scatter his
people.
God uses the cou sees the courage of
those who are scattered. And then we
will read into the joy of the unexpected
harvest.
So God disruption uses disruption to
scatter his people. So the story of Acts
is not a new one to us. On a single day
in this passage that rereading the world
changed for the people there in the
early church. One moment they were
gathering just like all of us are and
they were eating together just like all
of us do after church. You still serve
lunch here, right? Or no somewhat. Okay.
Okay. So, so as you gather eating lunch
somewhere else um in Redmond and they
are of course praying together in the
temple and watching the community grow
around them. However, and the next and
the next a disruption happens. Steven is
murdered, martyed, and now persecution
on a large scale breaks out
and everything changes overnight for
these early Christians.
There was persecution. Let me let me
pull back a little bit. There was
persecution during this time, but it was
not as a huge of a scale as it is after
the murder and the martyr of Steven. So
listen again to verse one and two with
me. And Saul approved of his execution.
And there arose that day a great
persecution against the church in
Jerusalem. And they were all scattered
throughout the regions of Judea and
Samaria except the apostles. Devout men
buried Steven and made great lamentation
over him.
See the story begins in grief and chaos.
Saul the Pharisee approved, as you can
read here, approved the execution of
Stephen.
The English translation of the word
approved is it's not it's not strong
enough.
In the ancient Greek, the word issumed
quo which is to be pleased with.
So Saul was a bad man. He was a very
very bad man. He enjoyed as the Greek
says he was pleased with killing
someone. And we have to understand this
is Saul the Pharisee. Saul who would
persecute Christians from now until his
conversion on the road to Damascus which
will come later
but we will not cover that today.
But Saul did not stop there. He did not
just murder one person in Steven but
instead he was ravaging the church and
entering house after house. He dragged
out off men and women and committed them
to prison. There's not enough
description of what he did. Some
commentaries have said that he took
pleasure in attacking the Christians,
imprisoning them. Saul was ravaging the
church and the ancient word from some
commentaries uh for ravaging means two
things. An army destroying a city and a
wild animal tearing at its meat. So if
you can envision that a wild dog animal
just tearing at meat pulling it from fl
from pulling from the moon from the bone
itself very vicious stuff and this is
who he was this is Saul the the Pharisee
so men so he didn't spare anyone
he went after men he went after women
and this was unprecedented because at
that time mostly men were the ones who
were imprisoned most of the men who were
the only ones that were arrested. But
for for Saul, that was that was not a
problem for him. He would take care of
everyone, every Christian going from
house to house. And he also said if the
believers did not renounce their faith
in Jesus Christ, they would be they
would be murdered.
Uh sorry, if they did not renounce Jesus
Christ, they would be set free. For
those who did continue to have faith in
Jesus, who proclaimed Jesus Christ as
their own personal savior, he would
murder them. He would set he would kill
them.
This whole situation
kind of reminds me of this
this guy.
He was minding his own business, right?
Take on the planet of Tatooine, living a
comfortable life, harvesting water. And
then a disruption happens. Two droids
show up and they upend his life.
So much upending in his life that his
family died. His home was destroyed.
And in this painful disruption of his
life pushes him into something greater,
a larger purpose.
He joins the rebellion to fight against
the empire.
In the same way,
the early church didn't choose to leave
Jerusalem, but God used that very
moment, that very disruption in their
lives to send them out, to scatter them.
So, back in Acts chapter 1:8, Jesus had
already said this to his disciples.
But you will receive power when the Holy
Spirit has come upon you and you will be
my witnesses in h Jerusalem and all
Judea and Samaria and to the end of the
earth.
Now here's the surprising part in in it.
The story doesn't end there. The story
tells us that the believers were
scattered and it tells us that what they
also did when they scattered as well.
Up until this point, the Christians had
stayed in Jerusalem.
They were doing their thing as we
mentioned, gathering together,
worshiping together, spending time
together, growing together.
So doesn't sound that sound pretty good
just being around each other and I think
all of us can can contest to that or
attest to that when we are at uh a
retreat together when so comfortable for
us to be singing songs together to be
worshiping together to be spending time
in the word together because we're all
surrounded by Christians we're all
surrounded by our brothers and sisters
in Christ
that sounds pretty amazing to be able to
do that they were comfortable that the
these Christians in the early church
they were comfortable in Jerusalem
but God had a bigger part for them. God
had a bigger mission for them.
So for these early Christians, they were
doing things according to their plans
and it took this disruption to move them
out to move them into the world as Jesus
had proclaimed to them.
So the early Christians were scattered
to all different parts.
Samaria being the biggest one that that
we mentioned here.
So now those who were scattered went
about preaching the word. Philip went
down to the city of Samaria and
proclaimed to them the Christ.
So we see here as Luke writes, those who
were scattered did not go into hiding.
Although you would think this would be
something that they would do. They're
being persecuted rampantly in Jerusalem.
People are coming after them to kill
them, to capture them, to imprison them,
to torture them. Yet they were on a
mission.
It reveals to us, the scripture reveals
to us, the scattering actually
emboldened them
to preach the gospel message.
And what is the gospel message? The
gospel message is what Jesus life is.
His life, his death, and his
resurrection that all the early church
knew about because it was told to them
from the apostles that have followed
Jesus Christ for many years. And this
message continues to permeate through us
as we read through it in our script in
the scriptures that we have and also for
those people who have mentored us, who
have guided us as well. So this is a
gospel message that that should be on
our hearts all the time that we can be
able to share with others.
So in this gospel message as it moves
from Jerusalem into Judea and Samaria,
it's a a a good as what they call the
good news.
Even though the Christians were hunted,
they continued God's work. They were
courageous in spreading the gospel
message.
You're probably thinking, "Wow, these
Christians are amazing, right? They're
the train p teachers, the train pastors
um or clergy at that time or the
apostles."
However, in verse two, we are told that
the apostles actually stayed in
Jerusalem
and they weren't scattered.
The apostles of course were the ones
that followed Jesus Christ and they
remained in Jerusalem seeing that their
mission was there. But those who are
scattered
were the believers of the early church.
The ones who converted
and these were the these are the the
regular people as they would say just
like you yourself here. They were
students or they were teachers. They
were cooks. They remained here, the
normal people, not the trained preachers
to spread the gospel message. And that
attests to how how this message, this
gospel message is a part of their lives
and how they were moved and how they
continue to to want to spread this
gospel message to everyone around them.
So sometimes when we think about the
gospel message, we think that this is
just for pastors or missionaries,
all the people who are qualified.
But here in this passage, it tells us
differently. It reminds us that mission
belongs to all of us.
Oh, sorry about that. So, Philillip
in the next verse in verse 5, Philip
went down to the city of Samaria and
proclaimed to them the Christ.
Now, Philip, you've heard his name
before. You've heard this name before.
You've heard it as possibly the uh the
the apostle Philip that Jesus Christ had
called to be one of his uh disciples.
But it's not him
and is of course it's not these Phils
either.
It is actually he is Philip is actually
one of the deacons that were raised up
in the acts chapter 6 and in chap
chapter six was when Steven was also
raised up as a deacon to serve the
widows to provide care for those who who
were disadvantaged and to provide food
for for for the people there. So in
essence he was a waiter but yet he was
raised up to become an evangelist to the
Samaritans.
He was just a normal guy but he had the
message of the gospel message within him
to share with others around him.
So preaching for for for a Jewish person
to be preaching to Samaria
that would be really difficult.
If you remember Jesus Christ traveling
through Samaria and he encountered the
women at the well.
The women said this about them that Jews
did not have dealings with Samaritans.
You see, this was a long
festering tension of hundreds of years
of ethnic and religious tension between
the Jewish people and also the
Samaritans. So there was a lot of
distrust and animosity between them.
And this was caused by hundreds of years
as far back as Ezra in the Old Testament
where it testes to how uh the Jewish
people were exiled and how they came
back and were were conquered over and
over again. And also tests to how how
the mixing of the Jewish people and the
Gentiles at in the time of the Old
Testament was unheard of and God had had
wanted to keep them separate. So now we
see the the fruition of what it is as
they came together. Now there's a hate
between these two uh people groups.
So for the early Christians to preach
the gospel message to the Samaritans, it
took a lot of courage
and breaking out of social norms.
Just think about how they must all have
felt.
These early Christians, they were being
hunted down. they should go into hiding
and not and not go out and preach the
gospel message. And they were in a place
where they were considered enemies to
the people.
And yet they were willing to spread this
gospel message. This good news that all
of them have heard.
And this is not out of their own power,
out of their own desire to do so, but
the power of God that permeates through
them. the power of the Holy Spirit that
compels them to share this gospel
message.
And we can read this in the letters to
Timothy chapter 2:es 1-7. For God gave
us a spirit not of fear but of power and
of love and self-discipline.
This is also the power that permeates
through us now as well. that will that
should compel all of us to share that
should compel all of us to go on
missions and missions can be doesn't
have to be overseas missions can be here
which there is always a need in Seattle
which is still considered the most
unchurched place in America
however you would not think that because
it seems like for me every block has a
church so I don't know if they have done
studies on the demographics of that But
I see so many different churches. So you
would think that the gospel message
would be permeating through here,
through the place that we are at.
So let's take a a quick trip back to
2020 and 2022.
What was happening at that time? It was
a global pandemic that all of us
experienced through.
So during that time churches of course
were closed
and you know forcibly closed because the
government didn't allow a gathering
together. So the church members all of
us had to be scattered.
We scattered to living rooms. We scouted
to v zoom screens and we saw a surge in
digital missions and local local
neighborhoods were were cared for
that had that hadn't happened in many
years.
So this scattering of us during the co
pandemic was a force gathering as well.
It allowed us to to spread the gospel
message through digitally. So we were
able to reach so many different people
that are around us and beyond our
borders.
The word was taken out of the temples,
our churches
and into the street.
And we still see this because uh a live
streaming uh we get reports that
hundreds of people continue to to tune
into to ECC's messages. They continue to
to want to be a part of this message.
that we that we are sharing with them.
So Tim Keller says this of the gospel.
The gospel is this. We are more sinful
and flawed flawed than we ever dare to
believe yet more loved and accepted than
we ever dare to hope.
Here he's sharing that the gospel
message
moves through everyone
is for everyone to hear and for us to
hang our hope on for for the salvation
of everyone around us.
Yes, we were sinners and Jesus died on
the cross for all of us to bring us into
relationship with him to be the bridge
between us and God to allow us to
journey with him on this earth.
Yes, this gospel message is not new and
it's not reserved for just a few, just
us within this congregation or just us
within ECC as a whole, but it's
entrusted to all of us. Entrusted that
we will share this gospel message with
the ordinary people who faithfully
proclaim Christ.
Something powerful happens when we do
proclaim this message.
As we can see
here, the joy of the unexpected harvest
when we do proclaim the message of Jesus
Christ.
In verse six, we will read,
"And the crowds with one accord accord
paid attention to what was being said by
Philillip when they heard him and saw
the signs that he did. For unclean
spirits crying out with a loud voice
came out of many who had them, and many
who were paralyzed or lame were healed."
So there was much joy in that city.
Here Luke writes and shares with it that
that people listened,
chains were broken because of the gospel
message. The sick were healed,
lives were restored.
And then we reached the climax in verse
8. So there was much joy in that city.
Much joy, you know, something that is is
shared as well. It wasn't something
private. It wasn't something that was
held in and it wasn't quiet. It was
overflowing,
probably communal for those around in
Samaria and probably visible as well.
So this is what the gospel does.
When the gospel takes root, it just
doesn't transform individuals but
communities.
The Samaritans believe and were
delivered from their sins.
The gospel message just doesn't fix
problems. It restores joy to all the
communities.
When God's kingdom breaks in, it's a
shared collective restoration.
Even in the midst of persecution,
there was a sense of joy.
In Psalm 65:8, the psalmist sings this
to us.
who still the roaring of the seas, the
roaring of their waves, and the turmoil
of the nations. The whole earth is
filled with awe at your wonders. Where
morning dawn,
where evening fades, you call forth
songs of joy.
This should be something that that we
can sing as well. Knowing that Jesus
Christ, knowing that we have the joy
that comes from from God, a joy that
cannot be taken away from us. It's not a
feeling that we have, but it's an
overwhelming certainty, a overwhelming
hope for us that God is there for us
each and every way
because we should call out songs of joy,
understanding of some of the things that
we've experienced through Jesus Christ,
understanding some of the things that he
brought us through.
So this morning
we heard how the early Christians in
Jerusalem were scattered due to
persecution.
This great persecution as they call it
as many Christian writers wrote
have the the early Christians scattered
but not shattered.
God still had a mission for them to
accomplish to be witnesses in Jerusalem
and all of Judea and Samaria and to the
end of the earth.
A disruption became a direction for
God's people.
It became for ordinary people. It became
they became messengers of God's gospel
message.
And the gospel also produced joy for all
who listen to it.
So this morning
as we as we close up,
what how does Oh, sorry about that.
This is C. Lewis and this last joy is a
serious business of heaven. So, so he
can attest to that as well as a famous
writer who is strongly devoted to
writing about the Christian message for
for readers all around.
And this is the joy that comes from God
himself.
This morning, as we close up, these
applications are some things that I
would like for us to to to walk
alongside with. How does being scattered
in your context at home, at school, at
work, how does that affect you?
For us as a church, as ECC as well. Let
us be a church that equips everyone,
not just leaders,
but to be brid, but for everyone to be
bridge across cultures and generations.
Let's see ourselves on mission as well.
Be a presence of peace, integrity, and
grace. Look for opportunities to share
your hope. Share the stories that you've
experienced from Jesus Christ to all
those around us. Yes, I know it's it's
difficult um to step into a place where
you're uncomfortable, but think about
how uncomfortable the early Christians
were as well when they had to go to
enemy territory to share the gospel
message.
And also, let's live out our faith with
courage, humility, and build
relationships beyond our comfort zone.
And that's what God is calling all of us
to do.
to step out to have faith and to carry
this gospel message to everyone around
us.
Let us pray.
Father, you have brought us through a
journey this morning that showed us how
as followers of Christ, we can trust you
in all difficult situations.
You lead us with your power that is
beyond our own understanding.
May we always remember you. Remember you
as you're moving us for your purposes
even when we do not see it.
And we pray all this in Jesus Christ's
name. Amen.
Thank you. Thank you, Pastor Steve.
When I think about the way God has gone
ahead and saved all of us and at the
same time think about the joy that he's
given to us, this is the response.
Gratitude. Would you go ahead and stand
with us?
All my words fall short.
>> I've got nothing new.
>> How could I express
all my gratitude?
I could sing these songs
as I often do,
but every song must stand
and you never do.
So I throw up my hands, praise you again
and again.
>> Cuz all that I have is a hallelu.
And I know it's not much, but I have
nothing else fit for a king
>> except for a heart singing hallelu.
Hallelu.
I've got one response.
I've got just one move
with my arms stretched wide.
I will worship you.
So I throw up my hands and praise you
again and again.
All that I have is a hallelujah.
And I know it's not much, but I'm
nothing else fit for a king
except for a heart singing hallelu.
Hallelujah.
Come on my soul. Oh, don't you get shy
on me. Lift up your song cuz you got a
lion inside of those lungs. Get up and
praise the Lord.
Come on my soul. Oh, don't you get shy
on me. We lift up your song cuz you've
got a lion inside of those lungs. Get
praise the Lord.
Come on my soul. Oh, don't you get shy
on me. Lift up your song cuz you got a
light inside of those lungs. Get up and
praise the Lord.
Oh,
So I throw up my hands and praise you
again and again
cuz all that I have is a hallelu
and I know it so much I've been for a
king
for a
Hallelujah.
So I hands and praise you again and
again.
Cuz all that I have is a hallelu.
And I know it's not much. I'm nothing
else for a king
except for a heart singing hallelujah.
Hallelu.
And I know it's not much. I have nothing
else fit for a king
except for a heart singing hallelu.
Hallelujah.
Okay.
Now, may the God of peace
equip you with every good
that you may do his will.
We pray all this in Jesus Christ's name.
Amen.
Please be seated.
Well, we thank you for joining us on our
worship service. First, I'd like to go
ahead and welcome any newcomers. If if
you're here for the first time, we don't
want to embarrass you, but if you can
raise your hand, we just like to welcome
you and give you a welcome packet. So,
anybody here for the first time?
Oh, I see one over here. Welcome.
Raise your hand again. Yeah. Thank you.
All right. Anybody else here for the
first time?
And uh we have ushers in the lobby as
well. Um so if you're here for the first
time, raise your hands so that you they
that you can be recognized and we can
welcome you. All right. Um so uh onward
to announcements. So we do have a
Mongolia mission sharing like way
overdue. Way overdue. Uh so please join
Priscilla uh Doris and myself. Uh we'll
be doing a Mongolia mission sharing, not
just to share about our trip, but also
to share how God has been working
through Mongolia. Um and also if you're
interested in uh maybe God is like
Pastor Steve said, maybe God is calling
you to go to Mongolia. So come come hear
uh what we saw. All right, next slide.
Uh second service update. So we did want
to give you an update um that the
Redmond English Council has reviewed all
your feedback. And by the way, thank you
for all those who filled out the survey.
Um, we do believe that God is leading us
to move forward with adding a second
service. And so, the Redmond campus
spiritual leadership team has taken the
steps to explore the next steps. They're
going to be calling a committee together
involving all of the congregations on
this side um to explore the next steps
on how to create a a second
congregation. So, please continue to
pray for God's guidance and wisdom um
and unity among the three congregations
as we move forward with this
um monthly prayer meeting um coming up
April 24th at 7:00. We have two uh
locations and these kind of rotate so
you got to pay attention so you don't go
to the wrong person's house. So, this
time it's going to be over at Ellie and
Michael's house and Pui and Jeff's
house.
um update on youth minister search. So,
there'll be a new youth uh there's a new
candidate, Sam, who will be visiting our
church. Uh some of you guys know him.
He's an awesome guy. Um uh please join
us for uh two Q&A sessions to hear about
him. He's going to be coming uh May 3rd
uh for youth parents meeting uh in the
Mandarin worship hall uh general meeting
May 10th. He's also going to be speaking
um uh May uh 10th uh at during the youth
worship as well. Um and and I we also do
want to mention um we we want to thank
uh Raymond Chan for going through that
search process at this point. We will
not be moving forward with Raymond. Uh
but please pray that God will continue
to lead him and his wife where he
desires uh uh for him to serve uh for
his glory.
All right. um uh governance
restructuring. So uh boy, we got a lot
of things. So May 17th, I just marked
the date 11:15. So as our church has
grown larger, um our current leadership
structure has not fully adapted to that.
Uh so we've had very large inefficient
meetings that really don't allow for
meaningful discussion um at the church
board level, at the elderboard level.
So, we're proposing a revised governance
model better designed to support the
church's growth and for future ministry.
So, do come here on May 17th um uh what
we're proposing and this is also a time
for people to give feedback because
nothing has written in stone yet. So, we
would like to hear your feedback on
that.
Uh deacon nominations for this is a
weird 2027 to 2029.
That doesn't sound right.
Oh, I see. They they their term is from
2027 to 2029. Thank you. Um so uh deacon
nomination forms are now available. Um
uh you can go to the uh our church
website. Uh you'll be able to get those
forms or email Grace Lee. Um and
candidates must be ECC members. Um uh
and recommended by three other ECC
members. Um, and uh, please submit those
forms to the ministry council chair,
which is Dennis, Dennis Lee. Uh, raise
your hand, Dennis, because I saw you
that you were here.
There's Oh, maybe in the lobby. Okay.
Um, give it to Dennis or or really you
can reach out to any of the deacons uh
or elders.
All right. Children's Ministry in-house
Teachers Training, April 25th, 9:30 9:30
to 2:30. um they've put together an
experienced team of trainers. So whether
or not you're a a seasoned teacher, a
brand new volunteer, maybe even
interested in serving in youth ministry,
uh sign up here um and uh get some
wonderful uh teaching.
Uh hosting Pingling student. I think you
guys have heard this already, but I'll
just mention it again. Um we're looking
for host families um uh to host Pingling
students from Taiwan. Uh we'll be
hosting 14 students and three teachers
from July 31st through August 16th. Um
and we're looking for host families to
to um host them during that period of
time. And so if you're interested,
please contact Joseph. Uh and by the
way, uh I know the slides are going back
and forth. Um if you miss any of these
things, go to our church website. You
can see the bulletin. All this
information is there. Uh VBS volunteers
needed. Um, uh, VBS, uh, by already
Redmond June 22nd to June 26th. Seattle
July 13th through 17th. We're starting
to plan for that. Um, as you know, we
need a huge amount of volunteers for
that. So, if God is calling you to help
out in that ministry, again, please sign
up with that QR code.
And then we do have an open position for
the administrative assistant. ECC is
looking for a detail oriented admin
skilled uh person uh who is bilingual
Chinese English uh to serve in the ad as
an administrative assistant uh to
support our church. If you're interested
or if you know of someone uh who might
be interested in this position um uh
that information is there for you to see
what that information uh that position
is all about and how to submit in your
resume.
Um, eyeglass donations. Uh, boy, you
know, I probably have like 20 pairs of
glasses sitting around my home. Uh, I'm
sure being Asian, you guys probably have
hundreds of glasses sitting at your
home. Come on. Um, so we are partnering
with Global Eyeglass Ministry, which
conducts um, uh, vision clinics. Um, so
if you can bring your gently used
eyeglasses and readers, by June 30th,
there's going to be a collection box um
uh at the entrance and it supports that
ministry. Um, and okay, so so just uh
correction, YSF YSF folks, there's still
Sunday school today. So you guys have
Sunday school. So go off to Sunday
school. Um, and then uh but otherwise
we'll have our Mongolian missions
sharing. There's no uh adult Sunday
school
and like I said, bulletins are online
and um uh giving of tithes and offerings
is part of our worship of God. Um and so
there's several ways that you can give.
If you're here visiting us, please don't
feel obligated to give. With that, thank
you for joining us. God bless. Have a
great week.