[Music]
(gentle music)
(gentle piano music)
(soft piano music)
(gentle music)
(gentle piano music)
Good morning. Good morning.
morning church. Welcome the ECC Redmond English side.
My name is Ben, I am one of the worship leaders.
just here. Happy spring. I know it has
officially be gone and it was really sunny and nice yesterday after all.
all this rain.
I don't know if anybody has
checked out and seen any cherry blossoms yet.
It's kind of crazy. I feel like it's blooming super early.
But yeah, how about let's just turn to one another.
Let's just say hi with each other happy spring.
Ring.
And then when you're ready, please stand.
As we'll start our worship set this morning.
Let me pray.
Heavenly Father, we welcome you.
Welcome you into this place.
We welcome your presence.
God, we ask that your spirit made a sand over us.
that Lord that we can come with a posture too.
to listen, to posture, to understand.
and a posture to hear from you this morning, God.
We love you, interning we pray, Amen.
(gentle music)
(gentle guitar music)
(upbeat music)
to the world.
♪ Of the world you stepped down ♪
♪ Down into darkness ♪
Open my eyes, love.
♪ I'm missing ♪
♪ Beauty that ♪
♪ I'm named this heart ♪
♪ I adore you ♪
♪ Oh, Baba, life's been with me ♪
♪ If you ♪
And here I am.
♪ I am to worship ♪
Here I am to bow down.
Here I am to see
♪ You're my girl ♪
You're all together
♪ We're loving all together ♪
♪ Yeah, the world he ought to be ♪
together wonderful.
for to me.
(gentle music)
♪ ♪
♪ Being a bald day's also ♪
♪ So highly exalted ♪
♪ Go, I said, I ♪
♪ I've been above ♪
♪ ♪
you came to the earth.
♪ As you created all the way ♪
♪ Oh, for love's sake, be care ♪
for.
♪ ♪
♪ You hear I'm ♪
♪ I am to worship ♪
Here I am to bow down
Here I am to say
♪ And out of your mind, girl ♪
You're all together
♪ I love you all together ♪
♪ The little world he ought to ♪
♪ Together wonderful ♪
To me.
Here I am to worship
Here I am to buy
♪ Oh, now here I am to say ♪
♪ That you're my ♪
God, you're all together.
♪ Together, lo-o-o-o-o-o-o ♪
♪ Together we're the ♪
All together wonder
♪ Therefore to you ♪
♪ And sound them ♪
Never know how much
[Music]
♪ See my sin ♪
Upon that cross
I'll never know
Oh, how much?
cause to see.
♪ I said, upon ♪
♪ And I cross the moon ♪
Never know how I feel.
♪ Much across ♪
Just see myself.
♪ Of all that cross ♪
♪ 'Cause I'll never ♪
♪ You know how much it hurts ♪
♪ Take us to see ♪
♪ Be my son of Lord ♪
♪ On that cross ♪
And here I am.
♪ I am to worship Him ♪
Here I am too bad now
Here I am to say that
♪ Yeah, you're my God ♪
You're all together in love
♪ The link altogether ♪
♪ You're worthy all together ♪
Never wonder what she is.
♪ You hear me ♪
♪ Oh hear me ♪
♪ Here I am to worship ♪
Here I am too bound
Here I am to see
♪ You're my God ♪
You're all together
♪ And they're lovely all too ♪
together worthy of you.
♪ All together wonder ♪
♪ You're thoughtful to me ♪
(gentle music)
Take my life and let
♪ Gotta be conscious ♪
the Creator, Lord.
Take my heart.
♪ My moments are my day ♪
Let them fall.
♪ Go and see this prayer ♪
Take my hands
♪ Send the damn moon ♪
At the impossible.
♪ Love that love ♪
Take my feet and let
♪ Then be swift and... ♪
♪ I'm beautiful for you ♪
♪ For thee ♪
(gentle music)
Take my voice and let me
♪ Amazing ♪
♪ It's only for my life ♪
♪ Take my life ♪
♪ Lips and let them be ♪
♪ Feel where my soul is ♪
♪ It's edges from thee ♪
I take myself over.
♪ Where am I going? ♪
Not a my would I?
♪ I will fall ♪
Take my answer, look down
♪ And use every power ♪
♪ Power as you choose ♪
[Music]
Here am I!
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, like me ♪
♪ For the me and take my life ♪
I love...
So for the...
♪ Oh ♪
Take, take, take, take, take, take, take.
my will and make it
♪ It shall be ♪
♪ We no longer mind ♪
Take my heart in
♪ It is I known ♪
♪ It shall be thy role ♪
♪ Oh, you're thrown ♪
Take my love, my Lord, I'll take my love, my Lord.
♪ I fall ♪
♪ My feet is treasurest all ♪
Take my soul.
♪ All fans I will be ♪
ever only.
♪ Be your friend ♪
Take myself and stop.
♪ I will be ♪
ever only y'all.
for thee.
Here am I.
♪ Amen ♪
♪ All of me ♪
♪ Oh ♪
Sing my love!
♪ Hey, so ♪
for thee.
♪ Hear him ♪
♪ I'm herein' ♪
All of me
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Take my love ♪
♪ Take my soul ♪
♪ Oh, boy, me ♪
♪ Here am I ♪
♪ Forever ♪
All of me
♪ Oh ♪
Take my love
♪ It's so ♪
♪ Oh, for thee ♪
♪ For me ♪
Take my life and let it go
♪ Better be constantly ♪
♪ So created Lord ♪
♪ Take me ♪
♪ My moment's in my day ♪
♪ Let them flow ♪
♪ Go and cease this prayer ♪
[Music]
(gentle music)
(gentle guitar music)
♪ Here I am ♪
♪ I'm telling all my knees up ♪
again, surrendering long.
♪ Oh ♪
Surrendering all.
(gentle guitar music)
♪ Find me here ♪
What has you drawn me?
♪ It's just before you ♪
you.
Tests before you.
I swear.
♪ Render ♪
(guitar music)
(upbeat music)
(gentle music)
♪ And my soul ♪
♪ It's mercy and grace ♪
I hung her answer
[MUSIC]
♪ The hunger and thirst ♪
We're so...
♪ Armstrong stretch wide ♪
I know you hear my
I cry, speak to me now
♪ Down ♪
Speak to me now
I surrender.
♪ I'm dead ♪
I want to know
Oh you, Martin!
I want to know you
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ I swear ♪
♪ Surrender ♪
I surrender
I want it.
♪ I know you more ♪
I want to know you
♪ You more ♪
(gentle music)
(gentle piano music)
♪ I'm like a rushing wind ♪
Jesus breathe.
with him Lord.
Lord have your way, Lord have your way.
♪ Away and me ♪
[Music]
Like a mighty
♪ Stay storm, stay with them ♪
♪ I'm in my soul ♪
Lord of your way, Lord of your life.
♪ Love your way in ♪
♪ Me ♪
Like a Russian
♪ When Jesus ♪
♪ Just be with them ♪
Lord of your way
Lord of your way.
♪ And me ♪
♪ Like a mind ♪
♪ My dear store ♪
♪ Under with him I say ♪
So Lord of your way
Lord of Your way, in Your way.
♪ Let me like a... ♪
♪ I'm rushing like a rock ♪
♪ Her sweet wind ♪
Jesus, beware!
♪ With and Lord of your way ♪
Lord, I'll you aint...
♪ Let me ♪
Like a mind.
♪ In Easton ♪
♪ Still within my heart ♪
♪ My soul, Lord, have You all come ♪
Lord of your way
♪ And me ♪
♪ Like a real girl ♪
♪ You're rushing with me ♪
Jesus bring you.
♪ You're within' but I ♪
♪ Lord, Lord, Lord, Lord, Lord ♪
♪ Hey, hey me ♪
[Music]
Like a mind is...
♪ So, stay with him ♪
♪ And my soul ♪
♪ Lord have your way, Lord have your way ♪
♪ Away in me ♪
(gentle music)
Lord, have you way, Lord, have you way?
♪ Look away at me ♪
[Music]
I surrender.
♪ I swear ♪
♪ The render ♪
I want to know you
more I want to be a part of this song.
♪ I know you more ♪
I surrender.
♪ Up ♪
♪ I surrender ♪
I want to know
♪ Oh you more ♪
I want to know you
(gentle music)
You may be seated.
(soft music)
[MUSIC]
(gentle music)
♪ For us you and me ♪
♪ In the heart ♪
♪ Make his face to shine ♪
♪ I'm on your foot to shine ♪
♪ I'm the only happy Christian ♪
[Music]
♪ I ask for fun to you ♪
(gentle music)
♪ For bless you and be ♪
♪ I love you, love you ♪
♪ What is this to try ♪
♪ I love my youth ♪
♪ I love all you, let's respect ♪
♪ And show us that we will ♪
♪ Let the shadows come to you ♪
(soft music)
♪ All is of life ♪
♪ Love is for you ♪
♪ The day is far ♪
♪ I knew that ♪
♪ For each other ♪
♪ Love, love is ♪
♪ The journey's on ♪
♪ I love you ♪
♪ I'll give you ♪
[Music]
♪ And give ♪
♪ I'm a little bit more beautiful ♪
♪ And you ♪
(gentle music)
(soft music)
♪ Peace ♪
(eerie music)
♪ Amen ♪
(singing in foreign language)
(screaming)
(cow mooing)
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
(sobbing)
♪ Ah ♪
(dramatic music)
[Music]
[APPLAUSE]
(audience applauding)
[ Applause ]
[APPLAUSE]
Thanks again.
Thanks again, children's choir. Let's give them another round of applause.
(audience applauding)
[APPLAUSE]
And would you all write?
rise with me for the Congregational Prayer.
Definitely, Father, we thank you this morning for their children's choir.
that's speaking the way around to the different congregations this morning.
Thank you for what it is you're doing in our church.
And we do thank you for our children's ministry.
We pray.
Praise God for the D6 conference that was recently attended.
attended and well attended by brothers and sisters of
all the campuses. We praise God for the dedicated
volunteers who faithfully show up every week.
take care of our children in Sunday school, choir.
as well as chess club.
We know that many
folks sacrifice their time to do.
you that and are often not able to come and join us here in this
congregation. And so we thank you for those who are already
serving in that way and we do pray
alert that you would raise e
even more volunteers to help offset that load.
We pray for the planning for the upcoming.
features training on 425 just
next month and we definitely pray for recouping.
including for this summer's VBS as well as teachers and TA.
for next semester.
We pray also that you would help us find the right candidate.
for the Seattle and EDS Children's Ministry.
that's been open for some time.
It's like we have Gordon over here, Lord.
We need somebody to help over.
on the Seattle and Edvin side as well.
For our congregation, Lord, Easter is just around the corner.
and we pray for the preparations for the Easter brunch.
I thank you so much for Tara and her team for helping.
to arrange that and organize that and we pray that that would be
blessing to this community, to the friends that are in
as well as the people from our congregations who attend.
This one we also want to lift up our missionaries.
to you this morning we want to pray for John and Jen.
from pioneers. They are focused
addressing their ministry on children.
our kids of third culture as they call it.
as well as Asian American young people.
spend countless hours just mentoring.
and sharing younger adults as well as having a good time.
having them over at their place for meals and
leading Bible studies. Pray that you would
just help them in their ministry as they continue.
They've been
and missionaries with us for a very, very long time.
And now that they're back stateside Lord, we pray that you continue.
to just leverage all of their experience as they
work among missionaries and those who are
a missionary minded.
We do pray for
or peace in the Middle East.
We pray that you would be.
raise peacemakers. Lord, we see on the news.
news what's happening and while we may be a sure way.
Lord clearly there's a lot going on.
going around, like going on that needs
your grace and your peace. Though we rely on you, we are still in the midst of your suffering.
on your sovereignty and knowing what to do in these situations.
and Lord, I pray that you would indeed
bring the peacemakers into the Middle East.
We pray also for the hearts and minds of those in need.
Thailand and despite having 200 years of
work there, they are at around or less than 1%
Christians or at least people that would call themselves Christians.
And so we pray Lord that You'd work in people's hearts and minds.
We pray that you would work among the missionaries that are there.
that you would give them the support that they need as well as
as the encouragement in spite of the different circumstances.
circumstances and difficult circumstances that they are going through.
for all of our missionaries.
We pray that you
you would help use us Lord,
whether it be through prayer.
Whether it be to funds, whether it be through having a
us actually go and participate in these different
missionary opportunities. Pray that Lord you
just accomplish what it is you want to accomplish throughout this world.
through your people and through us.
And now we pray the prayer that your son Jesus taught us.
Our Father in Heaven, hallelujah.
your name. Your kingdom come, your will be done.
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this to
our daily bread and forgive us our debts.
as we also have forgiven our debtors and lead us to
not into temptation, but deliver us from evil.
for yours is the kingdom, the power and the glory.
forever. Amen. And one more thing Lord we do.
just lift up Elton to you this morning as he speaks.
on your behalf. Pray that you give us open ears and open
minds to hear what you have to say to us this morning. Help us to
just set aside the distractions that we might have going out.
I'm going to bounce around in our minds and allow us to just hear from you.
from you to your servant.
In Christ and we pray, amen.
Please be seated.
Thank you for that added prayer for me.
I need it.
So, you know, Minister,
Ryan gave us survey.
at the beginning of his talk.
Last time, and I thought I'd--
do the same and my question is if
What would you do if you won the lottery?
So just turn your neighbor for just a minute and share.
What's the first thing you would do?
if you won the lottery.
[ Laughter ]
(audience laughing)
(audience chattering)
(audience laughs)
(audience laughing)
(laughter)
All right, all right, let's get on the mic.
So, okay, I'm gonna go share it.
the results from one poll.
and granted it's one pole.
one pole was from Philadelphia so great.
that what you will. These are phillage delphians and
So they said, what were they doing?
What would you do if you won the lottery?
Travel the world.
world. Was that a lot of people's answers traveled the world?
world. All right. The other one was
Pay off my debts.
I would pay off my debts. I think that's a solid
answer. Becoming artist.
That was a surprise to me. I guess again.
Phil Delphians, maybe they just love being artists and
And also, their next answer was write a book.
It's a very learning experience.
city I think and the last
one and this might ring true to some of the youth here.
become a pro gamer.
That they would become a pro-wrestler.
Okay, all right.
Now.
One thing that a lot of people do and
Maybe whether or not it's their first choice or not.
A lot of people would pay off their debts.
You know, and you know, guess what?
We have won the lottery.
We have won the spiritual law.
Right? Jesus has paid off.
all of our deaths and our spiritual
spiritual debt that we owe to God because of our sins.
in. Minister Ryan taught last week that we are
are free from condemnation.
free from death because of Jesus' work on the cross.
and you may have remembered his funny, slightly janky.
make you slide. It's a great slide.
So with Jesus and death, go ahead.
going off the cliff, demonstrating he's
he's paid for that.
And so we're totally free.
free from condemnation, free from death.
and free from death.
And so the question becomes now.
what? Now what do we do?
After we have won the spiritual model, what's the name?
next thing that we do.
A lot of Christians think, once I'm saved.
That's it!
No more needs to be done. I'm on Easy Street.
until I get into heaven.
If that's the case, the Bible, especially
really the new testament would be way more.
way shorter and in fact we're going to be able to do it.
Romans, which has 16 chapters, would
end at chapter 11 because chapter is going to be
1-11, the Apostle Paul goes at great lengths.
to describe and explain the good news of justice.
Jesus. And that's the essence.
1 through 11 is the essence of the gospel message.
but there's 16 chapters in one.
Romans. And so if chapters 1 to 11 is
the gospel, then the rest of Romans.
is the essence of Christian conduct.
Christian living. And so I'm going to
be covering chapters 12.
versus one through eight this morning. And if you're interested in this, please subscribe to our channel.
If you can, please stand with me at a respect for God's word.
Let's read it.
read God's Word together from Romans chapter 12.
12 versus 138 starting with verse 1.
Therefore, I urge you, brother.
others and sisters in view of God's mercy.
to offer your bodies as a living sacrifice.
Holy and pleasing to God.
This is your true and proper worship.
Do not conform to the pattern of this world.
be transformed by the renewing of your mind.
Then you will be able to test and approve
what God's will is is good, please.
and perfect will.
For by grace given me, I say to you.
every one of you do not think of yourself more.
more highly than you ought, but rather think of yourself.
with sober judgment in accordance with the law.
with the faith that God has distributed to each of you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
little jumping bait.
>> These members.
do not all have the same function.
So in Christ we though many form one.
one body and each member belongs to all the
others. We have given gifts a quote.
to the grace given to each of us.
If your drift is prophesying, then prophesying.
in accordance with your faith.
It is serving than serve if it is teaching.
teaching than teach if it is to encourage
than giving encouragement if it is giving.
then give generously if it is to lead.
do it diligently if it is to show mercy.
do it cheerfully. Please pray with me.
Father God, we thank You Lord for Your mercy.
word which has the power to transform.
We ask that you would open up our hearts and minds.
to allow your word to penetrate.
into our lives.
And I ask that
your Holy Spirit would fill me this morning to deliver.
your word. We pray these things in Christ's name. Amen.
Please be seated.
So here's the outline.
of my talk this morning. I'm going to be talking about what is
a living sacrifice and a life that is not a living sacrifice.
And how do you become a living sacrifice?
and the true worship of a living son.
So the power of the gospel we've been going through.
going through this series, the power of the gospel, we have reached the end of the episode.
received God's mercy and grace.
And as Minister Ryan said, we have been set for
free from condemnation from death by
Jesus' work on the cross.
and we won the spiritual auto.
So what's
What's the next step? What do we do next?
And our passage
today tells us what to do next after receiving.
leaving such a tremendous gift.
And it starts with this huge pivot in
chapter 12 with this word "therefore."
Therefore, I urge you, brothers and sisters to pray for your life.
in view of God's mercy.
see. So this therefore, the
marks a major shift in the direction of his life.
entire letter to Romans and we can see from
brothers and sisters when he says that.
that the target audience of this letter
is to Christian believers in Rome.
So in view of God's mercy,
He's saying in light of everything that I've seen.
said about the good news of Jesus.
And another way of seeing this is that once you
Once you're saved, once you've become a Christian,
This is only the beginning.
It's only the beginning.
And so look at what he said.
He says, "Therefore I err."
I urge you.
That phrase is a call.
for a response, a call.
for change. He's saying
if you understand the gospel of metal.
message. If you have accepted
the good news of Jesus into your life.
If you have received the
the gift of salvation.
Then,
Then you will live like this.
this. You will conduct yourself.
in this way. And there is
a call to action.
a call for a response. And this next step
if you become a Christian and what is
What is this next step?
And what does he say?
He says to offer your body.
bodies as a living sacrifice.
to offer your body
as a living sacrifice.
Now, living sacrifice, I gotta say,
term living sacrifice.
is really confusing.
It's a really confusing
using term and the Old Testament when you sacrifice
something, it's dead.
Pigeon Dead. Ram Dead.
Goats dead.
All is telling us to become a living,
sacrifice. That's... that's...
to me that sounds like an oxymoron.
How can you set
sacrifice something and yet still be alive. So...
So what does this term mean?
Well, let me start by saying what it's not.
Okay, so what is a living sacrifice?
It's not, it's not, it's not.
a sacrifice on the altar, but a living.
sacrifice. Note that Paul is not
reintroducing Old Testament sacrifices.
We're not sacrificing something.
to a tone for our sins.
Our ties and offerings when we give
Give that it's not a sacrifice.
as an atonement for our sins.
The sacrifice that is needed for us since have been a call.
accomplished by Jesus himself.
He is
is a sacrificial lamb that paid for our
sins for mine and for yours.
So that is done and it's
done. So when we are called to be
living sacrifice. Nothing that we do