As we sing and worship him,
see I Come
quiet my soul.
Remember
redemption's heal.
Will your blood spill?
Oh my.
Everything I once held,
I count it all as lost.
Lead me to the cross where your love
pour out.
Bring me to my knees, Lord. I lay me
down.
Rid me of myself. I belong to you.
Oh, lead me.
You were as I
tempted and dry.
You
were
the word became flesh
for my sin and death.
Now you're
everything I once held
I count it all as lost
lead me to the cross where your love for
us.
Bring me to my knees, Lord. I lay me
down
with me of myself.
I belong to you.
Oh, lead me.
Lead me.
to your heart.
To your heart.
Lead me to your heart.
Take me to the cross where your love
fall down.
Bring me to my knees. Lord I lay me
down.
Bring me up myself.
I belong to you.
will be me.
Lead me to the cross where your love for
now.
Bring me to my knees. Lord, I lay me
down.
Bring me up myself. I belong to you.
Oh, lead me.
Good morning again, ECC. Uh today we're
starting a series on the gospel, the
power of God.
Um, I know it can seem uh or can be hard
to feel like God is in control or that
we do serve a powerful God when there's
so many different things going on in the
world and even in our own lives. But we
do know that we serve a God who is
great, mighty, and powerful. And the
gospel is his most powerful message. So,
let's sing the greatness of God and
let's go to him in prayer.
Uh, dear Lord, we thank you that you are
a mighty God, a great God, that no
matter what it seems like, that you are
always in control, that we can trust in
you.
And can be easy to try and trust in our
own strength, but we know that you've
given us your son. You've given us your
gospel.
And I just pray that we're able to trust
in you and the words that you've given
us. Uh, just pray all these things in
Jesus name. Amen.
Splendesty.
Let all the earth rejoice.
All the earth rejoice.
He wraps himself
in light
and darkness tries to hide
and trembles at his voice.
Trembles at his voice.
How great
is our God.
Sing with me. How great
is our God. And all will see how great,
how great
is our God.
which he stands
and tides his
hands.
Beginning and the end.
Beginning and the end,
the God that he was.
are the spirit
son,
the life and the lamb.
I am the lamb.
How great
is our God.
Sing with me, how great
Don't see how great
how great
is our God.
Name above all names.
Worthy of all praise.
My heart will sing how great
is our God.
Name above all names.
Worthy of all praise.
My heart will sing. How great
is our God?
>> Great
is our God.
Sing with me. How great
is our God. I will see how great
how great
is our God.
How great
Sing with me. How great
is our God. All will see how great,
how great
is our God.
My hope is built on nothing less
than Jesus blood and righteousness.
I dare not trust the sweetest frame
but holy trust in Jesus name.
My hope is built on nothing less
than Jesus blood and righteousness.
I dare not trust the sweetest friend
but only trust in Jesus name.
Christ alone
corner
stone
weak made strong in the Savior's
love
through the storm.
He is Lord,
Lord of Lord.
Darkness seems to hide his face.
I rest on his unchanging grace.
In every high and stormy hill
within the lands
within the lamb
us
for the soul.
We made strong in the Savior's
Lord
through the stor.
He is Lord.
Lord of all
with thee shall come with trumpet sound.
Oh, may I then in him be found
dressed in his rightousness
alone.
All must stand before the throne.
Christ alone
corner
stone
weak and strong in the sior
long.
He is Lord.
Lord alone
Christ
corner stone
weak made strong in the Savior's
love
through the storm.
He is Lord,
Lord of all.
Uh will you join me in the
congregational prayer?
Our father in heaven, we thank you for
today. We thank you for this time that
we get together. We thank you for being
a reason for our gathering. Being the
reason for our gathering.
We thank you that no matter where we are
in life, no matter where we come from,
no matter where we're going,
you promise that if we seek you, we will
find you. And you promise that you will
not stop the work that you have begun in
us until it has been completed.
And we in our
broken hearts, in our despair of what
life is sometimes, we can look up to you
knowing that you are there for us in our
success, in our joys. We can celebrate
knowing that you delight in us thriving
as well.
Lord, we thank you for all that you are
to us, both in the good times and the
bad times because we know that you are a
constant cornerstone that we can lean on
no matter how things are.
Lord, we lift up so many things to you
uh as we pray and petition. Lord, we
lift up our church into your hands. lift
up our congregation into your hands for
all the challenges that we may feel um
at times, especially now when we are
thinking about and when we're discerning
about what is next uh as we grow perhaps
out of this space um at least in this
time.
Lord, we pray that you will give us
wisdom. We pray that you will uh give us
courage. We pray that you will give us
faithfulness
to follow you, to follow your lead, to
follow your will. Even if it may be
difficult, even if it may be hard, even
if it may be inconvenient
for us at times, we pray that you will
always keep our eyes focused on you. We
will always keep our eyes focused on the
mission that you have given us, the
great commission to make disciples of
all nations.
And no, it may not be easy. And no, it
may not mean we get to do things the way
that we've always done. But Lord, we
know that when we seek and follow after
you,
life will be so much sweeter than
whatever comfort we can find for
ourselves.
Lord, we lift up um our church into your
hands, not just our congregation, but
our whole church, knowing that space
isn't just a problem for our
congregation, but for Mandarin as well,
for Cantonese as well, for uh not just
this campus, um but for Seattle as well.
Uh Lord, in all of this we pray that we
will work together as one church, as one
body. Um that we will be considerate of
our Mandarin and Cantonese brothers and
sisters. Um even as they are considerate
of us. Um and that together we can
continue to be a church that is life to
life, generation to generation, and
faith to faith. Um
no matter what we pursue um
as our church grows
Lord we pray for this country. We pray
for this world. for all the turmoil that
is, for the
uh for the bombings that have been
happening in the Middle East,
for the lives lost, for the broken
hearts in fathers and mothers and
children as loved ones are lost, for the
dangers of those who have to evacuate.
Lord, a lot of times we look at this and
we think,
why are we like this, Lord? Why is
humanity so insistent on the things that
it wants to do, neglecting others?
Lord, in these moments, we cling on to
your promises that
those who
seek righteousness, Lord, they will be
filled. those who are peacemakers, Lord,
you will honor.
And those uh who are poor in spirit and
those who are meek, Lord,
you will be there for them as we have
been learning.
And Lord, we know and sometimes we admit
that in these times we also wonder,
Lord,
where are you and how are you going to
bring your justice and your peace onto
this earth?
In those moments, Lord, may we remember
that
for some reason, you have chosen to use
us as your hands and feet on this in
this world. And we pray that we will be
strong and courageous in seeking out
your peace by preaching your gospel, by
being good neighbors, by loving those
that may not be easy to love. regardless
of the cost at um because Lord this is
what you did for us.
And now we pray, Lord, as you have
taught us to pray, saying, "Our Father,
who are in heaven, hallowed be your
name. Your kingdom come, your will be
done on earth as it is in heaven. And
give us this day our daily bread. And
forgive us our debts as we have also
forgiven our debtors. And lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For yours is the kingdom, the
power, and the glory forever. Amen.
Good morning, ECC.
>> It's good to see everybody. I can't see
those of you who are at home or
traveling on live stream, but we're glad
you're joining when with us today.
And I want to start with just a short
word of prayer. I know we just prayed,
but I want to pray for the sermon. Let's
pray. Um,
Father, we do ask you speak to us. You
speak to us through me.
You use me. Your spirit be at work.
and you open our hearts and our ears to
hear what you have to say.
Call us to faith
in Jesus name we pray. Amen.
As Paul mentioned or as uh Jordan also
mentioned, we're starting in the recap
of the gospel series we've been doing
the past five years. In the past five
years, we've talked about the gospel
mission, the gospel meth message, and
the gospel impact.
And the next few couple of months, we'll
be doing a recap of that. But the focus
being on the gospel, the power of God.
And today's sermon opens with the verse
that gives it that name, verses 16 and
17 of Romans 1. And so we're going to
talk about the power of God to save. The
power of God to save.
I want to make a couple of quick remarks
as it go into this.
The focus of today's sermon is the focus
of the passage. The gospel of salvation.
The gospel is understood in two senses.
the gospel of salvation. But it's also
in the broader sense the good news that
Jesus has come and he's making all
things new. He is taking the people. He
is redeeming them and making them into a
new kingdom, a new people and going to
make a new heaven and a new earth of God
among us.
In light of the events of the US bomb
bombing Iran, I have to make just a
couple of quick remarks.
Um, the gospel of salvation seems to be
totally disconnected from that. But
realize the gospel of salvation is the
foundation
for the gospel in the broader sense. It
is a foundation where God redeems us and
makes us his people. And then he sends
us into the world to love our neighbors,
to be salt and light, to love the
creation, to make the world a better
place until he comes again and makes all
the nations his nation and all the kings
of the earth bow before him and all
things are set right.
The gospel of salvation makes us that
salt and that light to live in the
world. And that's how the gospel of
salvation is connected to the events
today. But I'm not going to say anything
more about that because the focus today
is the essential gospel of salvation
because that's what the focus of the
passage is. I just don't want people to
think it's disconnected if I say
nothing. It is totally connected in the
bigger sense of the word.
The first four sermons of this series
will be from the book of Romans.
And the key verse,
the T key verses 16 and 17 of Romans 1,
they are the key because they unlock the
door
to understand and to see like you open
the door and you see what the rest of
the letter to the Romans is talking
about. And so to understand the letter
to the Romans, it is essential to
understand verses 16 and 17 of Romans 1.
And with that in mind, I invite you to
stand with me. Um, I guess you're if
you're at home on live stream, you don't
have to stand, but you're welcome to.
Uh, but let's read together
uh Romans 1:16-1 17. For I am not
ashamed of the gospel. For it is the
power of God for salvation to everyone
who believes, to the Jew first and also
to the Greek. For in it the
righteousness of God is revealed from
faith to faith, as it is written. But
the righteous one will live by faith.
Amen. Please be seated.
I'll give a little background so we
understand where this letter is coming
from.
Paul wrote this letter to the church in
Rome because he will be going there and
when he gets there as he says in verse
15 he will be he is eager to preach the
gospel in Rome as he has in other
places.
Rome is the power center
of of of Rome. It is a center of
political power, military power,
economic power, cultural power,
civilization power.
Rome is the power center of everything
Roman.
Those
living in Rome have the resources
to live a good life, to improve their
life.
And in many ways, living in Rome was not
too different from living in America
today.
In America, we had the power to improve
our lives. We had the power to get
education. We had the power of access,
of resources,
of good things, of insurance.
of health system,
the power of connection.
You know, recently I needed to change my
doctor. my old doctor retired
and I kept looking around for he he's
actually not that old just previous uh
but searching around for a good doctor
and and then another doctor friend gave
me a good recommendation at Evergreen
and Kirkland which is like 10 minutes
from my house really close
uh and but he said this doctor's filled
out but you try and call to get in
anyway so tried and I called and I
couldn't get in. He's filled out.
There's no space for anybody else. So
then my friend says, "Let me talk to
him." So he talked to him and then he
said, "Okay, I'll let him in. Just tell
him to make an appointment." Tell them.
I said, "It's okay. Check with me."
That's the power of connection,
right?
That is power in a way.
Yet all this power we have, all that we
see,
taste and feel
cannot compare to the power of God.
All these powers we have as just as all
the powers that the Romans had, it will
pass away. Where's the Roman Empire
today? Will where will America be in 500
years assuming Jesus doesn't come back
before then?
Likewise, all the power we have to give
us a comfortable life, a convenient
life, a secure life, it will pass.
And then what?
Today's message is about a greater power
than any of this.
The passage that Paul wrote here brings
us to the power of God. And it's a power
not only for today,
not only in the past, but a power that
goes on continually.
Verses
16 and 17 in of Romans 1 give us three
reasons why Paul is eager to preach the
gospel
in Rome. And the three reasons all have
to do with the power of God.
We can see in in the first part of verse
16, the gospel has admirable power. In
the second part of verse 16, the gospel
has the power to save. And then verse
17, the gospel has power to last.
I'll briefly go through these and then
conclude with what does that mean for us
today?
The gospel has admirable power. As Paul
says in 16a, for I am not ashamed of the
gospel.
Paul says it this way because in Roman
culture and Roman society there are many
things in the gospel of which people
would be ashamed.
It was shamefully irresponsible for a
leader to die on behalf of his people.
It is shameful for a leader
like Jesus to serve his people to wash
their feet.
to touch the unclean. It was shameful
for Jesus to die on the cross. The most
shame of all shames in Roman society.
But Paul says, "No,
I am not ashamed. There's nothing
shameful."
Instead, Paul sees the gospel as
something to be boasted in, as he says
elsewhere, something that is admirable.
For Paul's whole long life, he had been
following
a legalistic form of the faith of
Judaism.
And in his legalistic experience
experience, he despised Christians and
he zealously persecuted them. He was a
driven man.
And then in a moment
Jesus appeared.
Suddenly
everything
everything changed for Paul
and everything became 180 degrees
opposite.
Now Paul is defending
Christians,
being gracious to those around them,
helping Christians, preaching the faith,
preaching what the resurrection of Jesus
and gracious forgiveness for sins.
And even more because of this because it
so dramatically changed who he was and
to who he is now. Paul wants to share
the same dramatic power
that he has experienced
that changed him.
This is the gospel that he received in
his heart.
Paul didn't do anything for it. He
didn't make it happen. He was on his way
to jail Christians, stoned them, have
them killed, and Jesus appeared to him,
and he put his Holy Spirit within him.
That is the gospel power
that changed Paul.
Wouldn't you want to change
share
this kind of experience for others?
The word here power means ability. The
word here power means strength. Strength
enough to be called a miracle.
And that leads us to the second point
that Paul talks about.
This miraculous strength of God
that God has belongs
to his good news
because it belongs to God who brings us
the good news.
the power of God. In verse 16b, he talks
about it.
When he says that the gospel has power
to save,
as he says, for it is the power of God
for salvation to everyone who believes
to the Jew first and also to the tree
Greek.
salvation.
The word salvation you look up in the
Greek
essentially it means deliverance.
It means we just prayed deliver us from
evil. That is a form of salvation. It
means deliverance. It means
preservation. It means safety.
Many times the Bible speaks of God
saving his people, saving them from
their enemies and their adversaries.
They were delivered from Egypt out of
slavery.
And often times in scripture
speaks of safety. God is our shield.
He surrounds us and protects us.
Now the salvation that Paul talks about
actually has three stages. We we we
usually think of it as that first stage.
Stage one, you're saved
and you're going to heaven.
But if you read carefully the
scriptures, it talks about it in three
phases or three stages.
And salvation starts with that first
stage, but it is continuous through the
second and into the third stage. The
first stage is what we call
justification.
A fancy word. Essentially, it's about
our title was changed once and for all.
From being orphans, we have now been
adopted. From enemies, we are now the
friends of God. From being hated to
being loved. From con from condemned to
forgiven.
From unrighteous
to now righteous.
This is a once and for all act.
And what kind of miracle is it?
Many people, for instance, were born
into poverty.
A few of them managed to raise
themselves out of p poverty
through great effort, through
discipline, through much studying,
through constantly telling themselves,
"You can do it. You can do it. Don't
give up through the discouragement of
others around him saying you're wasting
your time. You'll never get out of here
and yet not giving up.
Out of such great efforts, some do raise
themselves out of poverty. Some people
grow up in homes where their parents are
terrible,
even abusive.
And how can they live? How can they
escape living in this constant fear and
even despair?
How they keep from being permanently
scarred and dysfunctional themselves?
But few do have the power to find a way,
to find an avenue, to find friends, to
find some way to get out.
But God's power is greater than these.
We are all born in sin
and we are unable to change ourselves
to escape the sinfulness of sin within
us.
God has the power to overcome our sin,
to change our hearts, as Ezekiel says,
to change them from being hearts of
stone, unresponsive to God to hearts of
flesh, sensitive to God, and desiring
God and what God wants.
God can change us.
God does change us.
That is the miraculous power of God.
Paul says in Ephesians 2:8, "For it is
by grace you have been saved through
faith and this not of yourselves.
It is the gift of God." That is called
justification.
just as if we had never sinned. Right
with God. The right relationship.
The one-time act of Jesus dying on the
cross and paying the penalty for our
sins to satisfy God's justice.
And he opens the door to God to
reconcile us once and for all.
They could empower God this way.
We cannot change anybody.
We cannot even change ourselves
but God does.
I've known people before they became
Christians and after
shopaholics to hardly going shopping.
centered to other centered
falling asleep reading scripture
to being eager to read and know and to
follow
that heart change that change a person
God can do
God does.
But the gospel continues in stage two,
what we call sanctification, the
changing of our status and our
character.
The gospel is a power of God that
changes us in this way. 1 Corinthians
1:19 and 20. Do you not know that your
bodies are temples of the Holy Spirit
who is in you, whom you have received
from God? You are not your own. You were
bought at a price. Therefore, honor God
with your bodies.
The Holy Spirit is in us. And now we
have an obligation to him to live for
him in this life every day. How does the
Holy Spirit change us daily?
The Holy Spirit makes us alert.
The Holy Spirit reminds us of God's
word. The Holy Spirit makes us feel our
guilt when we do sin.
The Holy Spirit brings people into our
life to help us to guard us, to remind
us. He empowers us to resist temptation
and guards our heart so that we don't
have to so that we can bear under
temptation. As Paul promises in 1
Corinthians 10:13, "No temptation has
overtaken you except what is common to
mankind." And God is faithful.
He will not let you be tempted beyond
what you can bear. But when you are
tempted, he will also provide a way out
so that you can endure it. Did you know
that promise?
Temptations may come, but God never lets
us be tempted beyond what we can bear.
He provides a way out
in this life. It is a long process.
It also means God delivers us from
dangers.
and he prevents us from walking away
from him.
Paul, for example, talks about how he
was in prison, but he for saw how God
would deliver him out of prison when he
says in first in Philippians 1:19, "I
know that though your prayers and God's
provision through your prayers and God's
provision of the spirit of Jesus Christ,
what has happened to me will turn out
for my deliverance
and the circumstances of life. God
is working in him and delivering him,
protecting him.
Do you believe that a lot of times in
life, God is guarding you and has
guarding you from dangers you're not
even aware of?
Do you believe
that there are many times you could have
been in an accident, but God prevented
it from happening and you didn't even
know it?
How many times has cancer come to our
body and God eliminated it and we never
knew?
We never knew
day by day.
How many times has God
and his gospel power protected us from
temptation?
The power that changes our heart from
stone to flesh to be sensitive to what
God wants and guard against the temple
the wrong that comes to us.
God's power has given his spirit to stir
in within us and he stirs our hearts
against what is wrong to hunger after
God.
The Holy Spirit day by day is answering
the prayer that we just prayed and we
pray. Deliver us from evil
and lead us not into temptation.
We pray that every Sunday.
Do you do you realize
do you believe that we are all all of us
capable of killing someone?
We are we we may not believe ourselves
but we are
that moment of rage that overcomes us
and just in a split second to bring harm
to somebody before we hard even realize
what we're doing.
Last night I was at Family East and
Elder Dan was sharing with them.
There was a psychiatrist who did a study
of the Nazis
and the mass murdering that they did in
the concentration camps and they figured
there must be something mentally wrong
with these people. He studied them
and he came to the conclusion there's
nothing mentally wrong with these
people. They came up in good homes. They
had good upbringing. They had what
normally would be considered good
character.
And he concluded
they're no different from the rest of us
that all of us can go into such
depravity.
And he became dep so depressed at this
realization he committed suicide.
The author of the book to rape of
Nanjing did a similar study. The
Japanese soldiers who did such horrors
in Nanjing
and she came to the same conclusion.
They were raised in good families. They
were well- raised. They were cultured
and yet they did such horrible things.
She too became depressed and eventually
committed suicide.
We are all capable of doing far more
evil and harm than we think ourselves
have.
But God guards us. The power of the
gospel and the Holy Spirit with us,
guards us and protects us from the evil
that all too often would dwell in our
hearts. It is the work of Holy Spirit in
sanctification. That power that renews
us and works in us day by day throughout
our lives
for all of us who are being saved. We
were saved. We are being saved. As Paul
says in 1 Corinthians 1:18, "For the
message of the cross is foolishness to
those who are perishing, but for us who
are being saved,
it is the power
of God. Being saved is that second stage
of salvation,
justification. We have been saved once
for all in the process of life and
sanctification. We are being saved,
rescued out of the dangers and
temptations and being conformed so that
we come more and more in our character
the way God wants us to be in the final
stage of salvation's glorification.
Change our fate.
Shaon shared with me at her brother's
funeral this summer.
The Catholic priest said this
to the people gathered. Her family
said, "You all know where you are from.
You all know where you are from,
but do you know where you're going?
Do you know where you are going?
Are you sure of where you're going?
And do you like
where you are going?
You all know where you're from, but do
you know where you're going? Are you
sure where you're going? And do you like
where you are going?
Powerful message.
powerful message.
We have no choice where we're going. We
only have one choice. Either to be
condemned eternally, to stay within our
sin and alienated from God, or through
faith in Christ,
receive a new destiny, a new fate.
to constantly and continually without
end
be with Christ or constantly and
continually be with without hope
separated from God.
We're all born into that fate. We're all
born in sin and our faith is to
constantly, continually, without hope be
separated from God.
But for those who are in Christ, for
those who have been saved through faith,
we have been given a new fate.
We can have a great job. We can have a
make great marriage and kids
cultured and morally upright in our
bringing and still
we all end up in the criminal's place.
If there's no salvation from God,
if there is no salvation guaranteed from
God,
then or by the power of God, then no
matter how smart we are, no matter how
good we are at life, no matter how bad
we are at life, educated, skilled,
whatever, male, female,
Chinese,
Caucasian.
We're all condemned because of sin.
But there is salvation.
Salvation that changes our fate.
Peter speaks of this when he says, "Who
through faith are shielded by God's
power until the coming of salvation."
He's looking into the future. that is
ready to be revealed at the last time.
Who can be saved?
He also says, "So Christ was sanctified
once to take away the sins of many,
and he will appear a second time, not to
bear sin, but to bring salvation to
those who are waiting
for him.
That is a fate that is changed.
Now we're saved and our souls are saved
and we are going to a different
destination because we are in Christ
and later our bodies will be saved in
the resurrection unto eternal life with
Christ when he comes again. But the
question in all of this is who?
Who can be saved?
And Paul answers it. Everyone, all
who believe,
no matter rich or poor, fat or thin,
slave or free, good or bad, educated or
ignorant, skilled or clumsy, all and
anyone and everyone who believes
who believes
As Paul says in the passage, for the
power of God for salvation to everyone
who believes
to the Jew first
and also for the Greek,
those who believe, those who trust God.
First here when he says first of the
Jew, it's not a first of priority. It's
a first in order. Historically in the
plan of God, he chose a nation from all
the other nations to be his witness to
the nations, the Jews. And out of that
family, he out of that nation, he chose
one family, the family of David. And out
of the family of David, he eventually
chose one couple, Mary and Joseph.
And one baby was born,
Jesus Christ.
Salvation came to the Jews first.
Historically,
God's intention has always been to bless
all the nations.
And through Christ, now we all share.
And that's salvation through faith,
all who believe,
all who believe.
The gospel has power, God's power to
save all who believe.
and change our fate
forever.
The third reason Paul gives for being
eager to preach the gospel in Rome is
the gospel has power to last.
He says, "For in it the righteousness of
God is revealed from faith to faith as
it is written, but the righteous will
live by faith."
Where do we see the righteousness of
God?
Where has it been uncovered or unveiled?
We see the righteousness of God.
When Jesus died for our sins on the
cross,
previously everybody thought
righteousness is what I do. They work
for what? How how can what work shall we
do to be saved? They kept asking Jesus
and Jesus kept on saying believe.
believe in the one God has sent
and that he revealed the righteousness
himself by dying for our sins on the
cross.
An astounding answer.
A righteousness that by which now God
says, "You believe, I give you that
righteousness.
I declare you righteous.
It is not our righteousness. It is God's
righteous or only God is truly
righteous. But by it he gives us a right
relationship with him
and like he puts a stamp on the forehead
so when he sees us he sees righteous.
He has declared us so. That is the
gospel.
The good news
that Jesus,
the holy God,
has bought for us. So that God now says,
"You're right. You're right with me.
You're right with me. You're right with
me.
Forever and ever."
And when we go to see Jesus and
everything is gone, but our faith
remains,
he will still say, "You're right with
me. You're right with me."
Paul quotes Habach 2:4. Habach is a
prophet who is he is puzzled. How can
God
How can God God He even asked God, "How
can you use a nation far more evil than
us to punish us and chastise us? We're
better than they are. We're better than
they are."
And he realized the only way to live
before God,
to have his soul right,
is to trust God.
with it all
to continually walk with God in trust in
believing him
so that
from faith to faith to faith it
continues
and that's how we live by faith
not by sight not by what we do
and then we're not in. We will not lose
our salvation or the power of God.
What's next? That's what I want to say.
What is next? If all this is true,
what's next?
I just want to say if you're not a
Christian yet and we hope and we welcome
non-Christians to come and join us,
you don't have to make yourself better.
You don't have to give your life in
order
to come to God.
You just have to believe.
Learn the lesson from the thief on the
cross.
who even had he even had no dignity left
and his life is bleeding away
gasping for breath
but he recognized who Jesus is
and he said it's very simple
remember me when you come into your
kingdom notice he he recognized who
Jesus is when you come into your
kingdom. Remember me.
That's all. That's all he did. He came
to Jesus
by turning him and saying, "Remember
me."
And Jesus says, "I promise.
You will be with me today. You will be
with me in paradise."
Come to Jesus.
If you're not a Christian, all you have
to do is say, "I know who you are.
Save me and I will follow you." And he
will
faith.
Believe in him.
If you are a Christian,
it's still about faith, brothers and
sisters. It's not about works. It's not
about what we can do for God. It's about
walking through life believing and
trusting in him from faith to faith.
Believe he walks with you. Believe he is
with you. Believe he is for you and not
against you.
Believe that he uses the things you do
for good.
Believe that the sacrifices you have
made, the things you have lost, God uses
for good. He counts it all. Believe him
for the next steps of your life that he
is with you and walking with you. Will
never abandon you.
Believe that God is in charge of your
children's lives.
believe
that he cleanses you,
that he restores you, that yes, he still
forgives you when you keep on messing up
again
and again.
And say again,
I trust you, God.
I trust you, God. I won't run away in my
shame. I will come back to you.
I depend on you. I submit to you once
again.
We have nothing.
We have nothing that we can offer God
except our faith.
Everything we have is from God. Our
brains, our bodies, our education, our
skills, they all are provided by God.
Only we can offer our faith.
And the more faith we have, the more
faith we offer God, the more he responds
to us and gives us his righteousness in
return.
Faith plugs us into the power of God.
Let me say that again. Faith plugs us
into the power of God
that saved us, is saving us, and will
save us in the end.
And one way we can see that faith
because you can't see my faith. Can you
see my faith? I can't see your faith. I
can't look at Charles here and say, "Oh,
I see Charles has great faith." I'm not
going to pick on anybody for small
faith.
We can't look and see.
But the action of coming to God
demonstrates our faith. We come to God.
We come to God. When we mess up, we come
to him again.
And with that, I I hope I want to end
with the stances of an old hymn. I
update the language a little bit. They
keep saying thee and thou. So far I
changed it to modern English. But
I hope the words of just as I am echo in
your soul
as I read them to you. You can see them
on the screen.
Just as I am without one plea, but that
your blood was shed for me and that you
bid me come to you, oh lamb of God.
I come
just as I am and waiting not to rid my
soul of one dark blot, but to you to you
whose blood can cleanse each spot.
Oh lamb of God
I come.
Just as I am, though tossed about, with
many a conflict, many a doubt, fighting
and fears within, without.
Oh lamb of God, I come.
Just as I am,
you will receive, will welcome, pardon,
cleanse, relieve.
Because your promise
I believe.
Oh lamb of God
I come.
Let us pray.
Help us oh Lord to glimpse and to see
your power
greater than the power of creation.
Greater than the power of formation,
the power that saves, the power that
resurrects our dead souls, the power
that calls us to yourself and renews us
and through us you will renew all
things.
Pray, oh God,
if there any in this room have yet
believed in Jesus,
they would hear your call and they would
come.
I come, Lord. I come.
And for those of us who do know you and
we're walking through
salvation in our daily life,
we hear your call every day and we keep
coming to you.
And when we face death to know you, call
us home
and home we will be with you.
give us that faith. We will come
in Jesus name we pray. Amen.
Thank you, Pastor Mack, for that
message. Let's sing to God and of the
power that we have through him, his
death, and ultimately his victory over
it. Uh let's stand.
You called me from the grave by name.
>> You called me out of all my shame.
>> I see the old has passed away.
The new
has come.
All I have resurrection power
living on the inside. Jesus, you have
given us freom.
No longer
bound by sin and darkness.
Living in the light of your goodness.
You have given us freom.
>> I'm dressed in your royal.
Your holy spirit lives in me.
I see my past has been redeemed.
The new
has come.
Now I have resurrection power
living on the inside. Jesus
you have given us freom.
No longer
bound by sin and darkness.
Living in the light of your goodness.
You have given us freom.
Freedom. You have given us freom.
You have given us freedom.
My chains are gone.
Freedom. You have given us freom.
You have given us freom.
Halleluah.
Freedom you have given us. Freom
you have given us. Freom
chains are gone. Oh
freom.
You have given us freom. You have given
us freom.
Halleluah.
Now I have resurrection power
living on the inside.
Now no longer
my sin and darkness.
Living in the light your goodness.
I give us freom
resurrection power
on the inside. Jesus
you have given us free
sin and darkness living in the light of
your goodness.
You have given us freom
resurrection power
inside Jesus you have given us free
no
darkness
of your goodness
you have given us freom
Please be seated.
We come to the celebration
of the Lord's table,
the sacrament of communion.
We recognize two communions, bapti two
sacraments, baptism and communion. And
both of them are symbolic declarations
of the gospel.
They take us back to God and what he has
done for us. They remind us and draw us
to commune with him and restrengthen our
faith in what God has done for us.
Communion. The bread represents the body
of Christ.
The the wine represents his blood shed
for us. Picturing his death on the cross
for our sin
and declaring
that he will come again.
We remember him until he comes again.
Christ ordained the sacraments
and gave them to us that we might
benefit. So as we partake of the
communion today, his communion, it
doesn't belong to this church, belongs
to those who have been baptized and
recognized as believers in Jesus.
He gives it so that we might meet with
him. we might commune with him that he
might strengthen us in our faith.
Talk with Jesus,
thank him for your salvation.
Reach out to him
and commune with him.
As we do this,
I ask the servers to come forward.
I invite you take eat in remembrance of
Jesus.
Take drink in celebration of the king.
Amen.
I invite us to rise and let's sing the
doxology together.
Praise God from whom
all blessings
flow. Praise him all creatures
here below.
Praise him
above.
Heavenly
host. Praise father,
son, and holy
host.
Amen.
And now may grace, mercy, and peace from
God the Father, God the Son, and God the
Spirit be on you. Amen. You may be
seated.
Hello. Hello. Uh, welcome to ECC Redmond
English. We are glad that you're here
with us. If you're joining us online,
uh, we hope to be able to see you in
person uh, sooner than later. Uh we have
a decent amount of announcements. So I'm
trying to get to them to bear with me a
little bit. But before we get to that,
if you're here for the first time uh in
person, uh could you just give a quick
raise of hands? We thank you for joining
us. And our ushers will have a few uh
pieces of information for you. We have
one over there, one over here.
Anyone else joining us for the first
time?
Well, thank you for joining us. We're
glad you can make it. We're glad that
you're here with us. Um, announcements
if uh first is uh there is a council Q&A
session this uh this Sunday school hour
today here. So, at 11:15 um your your
ministry council will be up here. You
can ask them any questions you'd like
about anything that you'd want. Uh we
promise we'll do our best. We can't
promise we have every answer. We promise
we'll do our best to let you know uh
what is going on and and and all of
that. So if you have any questions,
there is a code um this is an older
slide that I reused. So I'm not super
sure that that code works, but we will
have a fresh code that if you don't want
your name, if you don't want to be
associated with the question because you
don't want to come to the the
microphone, that's fine. Type it in. You
know, we don't have to. Yeah.
Uh there's a survey that we have up uh
as we are preparing to multiply for our
church because we're really packed. We
just want to know where our congregation
is. We want to know where you are. We
want to know what you think and feel and
all of that so that we can uh make the
best plan. So please fill that out if
you haven't.
Couple updates on room reservations.
Sometimes you want to come here to
church and do stuff. Uh we it's now
digital. You can you don't have to email
Grace anymore. And there's a QR code at
the back of your bulletin in paper or if
you go online to eccato.org
um scan that code, use the system, book
your room, email questions at info
eccato.org.
Couple things for children's coming up
um in this announcement deck. First,
there's a D6 Northwest conference. Lots
of breakout sessions about family, about
children. If you're interested, please
let Gordon know because you cannot go uh
on your own without registration. But if
you register for if you go for the first
time, it's free. Gordon can figure all
of this out for you. Uh, so please let
Gordon know. Gordon Sunson eccciato.org.
Uh, I'm sorry. Next week is daylight
savings time in spring forward. It means
y'all have to wake up an hour early.
It's not my fault. I'm sorry. Um, but I
do hope to see you here uh on time at
service next week. It means sunset is
later, so that's great.
Uh, there is baptism class starting next
week and the week after. So, if you've
not been baptized, if you don't know
what baptism means, if you want to be
baptized, um, uh, please join us, uh,
for in W107, which is that way, uh, for
two Sundays in a row of classes. Um, if
you have any questions, contact Kobe.
Uh, there is a outreach event uh for
people uh, kids, youth, adults with
special needs that is coming up hosted
by Angel's Love uh, here at ECC Redmond.
That will be June uh, March 14th. That's
a Saturday 1 to 4. You do need to
register. So if you're interested,
please register at the link. And there
is a Easter brunch coming up because
Easter is upon us soon, April 4th,
Saturday, uh here on Redmond campus.
We'll have stuff set up. Um it's, you
know, everyone is welcome, not just
people in your church. Invite your
neighbors, invite your friends. We love
to see them here. And there is a
in-house teaching thing for youth uh uh
children's ministry as well. So, if you
have been a teacher, if you want to be a
teacher, if you're interested in knowing
what that's like, uh, please come. Um,
and please do sign up because lunch will
be provided.
VBS is coming up June 22nd to 26. There
is a logo, there is a theme. You don't
have to need a whole know a whole lot
more. Just mark the dates if you know
your kids will be interested in VBS.
Uh, there is an IT manager position open
here at church. So if you know who
somebody who is looking for a job, who
is capable, who's skilled, uh please let
them know, please have them apply.
And we are also looking for Cantonese
pastor and minister for our Redmond
English or not English, Redmond
Cantonese congregation just down the
hallway. So if you know anyone for that
too, uh there's a list of um the
activities for sports ministry that we
have. Um there's a Google calendar you
can scan for all of it going forward.
But volleyball, basketball, pickle ball.
I know pickle ball is super popular. Um,
contact Billy Tang if you have any
questions. We love to see you there,
too. Uh, and there is a Redmond
Elementary School, which is just, you
know, kind of in our figurative
backyard. Um, they're doing a donation
drive for non-perishable food items.
This is a school with a large population
of um families with financial needs. Uh,
so we would love we we've been signing
up for this because we want to be a part
of the community um that serves them.
So, uh, if you have any questions about
any of the stuff, contact Billy Tang.
Um, he has all the answers.
That's a lot. That's really quick. If
you have any questions about any of
those things that I breezed through, uh,
you can find them at the worship
bulletin online at eccato.org.
Feel free to ask me any questions that
you have as well. Um, and last but not
least, ties and offering. You can do
bill pay, you can do cash check, if you
can do Venco, but if you're visiting us
for the first time, please don't feel
obligated to give. Thank you for joining
us, for bearing with my massive amounts
of announcements. Uh we hope we have a
blessed Sunday. Um yeah, have the rest
good uh good rest of your week.
my life.