Introduction - What's my mission in the Great Commission?
I love action movies - and while I think Tom Cruise is a bit wackadoodle, I do like his
Mission Impossible movies.
And of course, Mission Impossible is not the only movie with a mission.
There's a whole line up of movies with a "mission" - one of my fav is also "The Mission"
- if you haven't seen that one, it's worth watching.
Our church's vision is about "The Missional Church" One of Jesus' last words, His last
command to His disciples was a call to Missions in the Great Commission.
Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father
and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, [20] teaching them to observe all that I have
commanded you.
And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age." Matt 28:19-20 This call, of
course, was not only to his disciples at the time but a call for all of us, every follower
of Christ to heed.
The question becomes - What's my mission in the Great Commission?
How am I part of the Great Commission?
Does that mean I have to become a missionary?
(Spoiler alert - no).
How can I actively participate in the Great Commission?
Our passage from today becomes a model for us to learn how we can all participate in
fulfilling the call, the command to the Great Commission.
Read Passage - Acts 13:1-5 1 Now in the church at Antioch there were prophets and
teachers: Barnabas, Simeon called Niger, Lucius of Cyrene, Manaen (who had been brought up
with Herod the tetrarch) and Saul.
2 While they were worshiping the Lord and fasting, the Holy Spirit said, "Set apart for
me Barnabas and Saul for the work to which I have called them." 3 So after they had fasted
and prayed, they placed their hands on them and sent them off.
4 The two of them, sent on their way by the Holy Spirit, went down to Seleucia and sailed
from there to Cyprus.
5 When they arrived at Salamis, they proclaimed the word of God in the Jewish synagogues.
John was with them as their helper.
Background on the Great Commission Who initiates God's Global Missions?
The Church as Sender The Church as Sent Your Mission in the Great Commission Background
on the Great Commission The Great Commission - 2 passages Matthew 28:19-20 ESV "Go
therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and
of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, [20] teaching them to observe all that I have commanded
you.
And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age." Jesus said at the beginning of
Acts, right before His ascension in Acts 1:8 "But you will receive power when the Holy
Spirit has come upon you, and you will be my witnesses in Jerusalem and in all Judea and
Samaria, and to the end of the earth." Many understand that Acts 1:8 as part of the Great
Commission.
So these 2 passages - Matthew 28 and Acts 1:8 together form the call of the Great
These are Jesus' last words, the last instructions, His last charge to His disciples
before His ascension, before He left them.
We see in Acts how God unfolds the Great Commission: In fact, if you're studying the Book
of Acts, an easy way to structure the book is by the Great Commission of Acts: 1:8: We see
a progression - from Jerusalem - to Judea and Samaria - to the ends of the earth.
Ch 1-7 is the part on "Jerusalem" - where the Apostles and others preach throughout
Jerusalem, predominantly to the Jewish people Ch 8-12 - is the part on "Judea and Samaria"
- Acts 8:5 ESV, which Pastor Steve Moy preached last week, Philip went down to the city of
Samaria and proclaimed to them the Christ.
Here in Ch 8 Phillip proclaims Christ in Samaria (racially mixed Jewish and Gentile
ancestry), who was then backed up by Peter and John, Ch 10 - we see Peter was given a
vision from God to "eat unclean animals" - and right afterwards, he entered and preached
at a Roman Centurion's house (Cornelius) - marking the first intentional preaching to a
Gentile audience Ch 11 - we saw the formation of the Antioch Church, the first Gentile
Church and a major movement into the Gentiles Rest of Acts: Ch 13- 26, starting with our
passage in Acts 13 - God unfolds the rest of the Great Commission: to the ends of the
earth - with our passage showing the first of Paul's 3 missionary journeys, along with
Barnabas and others.
(show map) - so we see God's plan unfold - starting in Jerusalem, then to Judea and
Samaria, then, as recorded in Acts, Paul launches three of his missions trips throughout
the Roman world.
Who initiates God's Global Missions?
Was it the church?
Was it the prophets in the church?
Was it the church leaders?
(The Holy Spirit) 1 Now in the church at Antioch there were prophets and teachers:
Barnabas, Simeon called Niger, Lucius of Cyrene, Manaen (who had been brought up with
Herod the tetrarch) and Saul.
2 While they were worshiping the Lord and fasting...
"They" were probably the whole congregation, not just the people listed.
So the church was worshiping God, they were fasting ...
and then we see "the Holy Spirit said, "Set apart for me Barnabas and Saul for the work
to which I have called them." 3 So after they had fasted and prayed, they placed their
hands on them and sent them off." What was going on here?
It is in this setting of worship, fasting, and prayer that the Holy Spirit calls them
into action.
It's important to note that they were NOT having a missions meeting.
This setting in the Antioch church was NOT a strategic planning or visioning meeting.
It was during worship, fasting, and prayer, something they were already doing, something
that they were probably regularly doing, which was putting themselves in the presence of
God, and in so doing, God called upon them.
2 While they were worshiping the Lord and fasting, the Holy Spirit said, "Set apart for
me Barnabas and Saul for the work to which I have called them." We can learn our first
teaching point - The Holy Spirit initiates God's Global Mission!
We can see the Holy Spirit's hand all over the place in our passage.
He was guiding the entire missions trip!: V4 4 The two of them, sent on their way by the
Holy Spirit, went down to Seleucia and sailed from there to Cyprus.
V9 9 Then Saul, who was also called Paul, filled with the Holy Spirit, looked straight at
Elymas and said...
In other passages, the Holy Spirit played a very active role in guiding, leading, and
directing the unfolding of His Global Missionary plans.
God directed Peter in Acts 10 to look beyond the Jews towards the Gentiles by giving him
a vision to "kill and eat unclean animals" In Acts 16, during Paul's second missionary
journey, the Holy Spirit blocked Paul from going into Asia Minor and instead, again
through a vision, directed him to Macedonia.
There are many passages like this.
The point is...
God is always calling - are we responding?
Are we listening and are we responding?
First, are we actively listening to what the Holy Spirit is telling us?
Do we spend enough time in prayer, in fasting, in worship, in meditation, in the Word, in
all the various avenues to quiet our mind, quiet our souls, putting down our 5x2 inch
screens and listen to what God is calling us to do?
And many times - we do hear the Spirit nudging us in a direction - But do we respond?
Are we ghosting God like we sometimes do when we don't want to respond to messages!
(sarcastically, I would never ghost you if you messaged me...
na ahh!) I believe sometimes we do hear God, but we don't want to respond.
Because sometimes His calling is uncomfortable.
Sometimes His calling is time consuming.
Sometimes His calling means making sacrifices.
But that's exactly what God is calling us to do.
That's the point of being a "living sacrifice." That's the point of the surrendered life.
It is clear from our passage and the entirety of Acts that God has a plan.
We don't need to come up with a plan.
We just need to listen for God's call for us.
And we need to respond.
God has a plan and we just need to figure out how we can be part of His plans!!!
By "We" I mean "We" both as a church and and "We" as individuals.
What can we learn from the Church in Antioch?
The Holy Spirit spoke to them and as a Church, they responded!
Let's see how they responded.
They responded two ways - as sender and as sent.
The Church as Sender They responded to the Holy Spirit - how?
As a church - They gave of their resources.
The Biblical city of Antioch was powerful and wealthy, currently "Antakya" in modern day
Turkey It was a metropolis of Syria.
A Hellenistic Roman metropolis.
(show map) In the past, it was the capital of the Seleucid (Greek) kingdom.
Romans made it the capital of Syria after conquering the Seleucids in 64 BC.
Powerful city.
On coins, called itself the "capital of the East." Seat of the Roman governor of the
region.
It was a "free" city - Romans allowed it to govern itself (not ruled or subjugated by the
Roman authorities.
Large enough to boast its own marketplace, theater, and amphitheater.
They also had a palace and a circus.
Josephus claims that the city ranked third in size and wealth after Rome and Alexandria.
The Church in Antioch - We know about the city, what about the church?
If you recall in Acts 11, this was the first Gentile church formed by these "no named"
Jewish Christ-followers who were persecuted and scattered and witnessed to the Gentile
believers around them.
Barnabas was sent first to minister to them and Barnabas grabbed Paul to join him in
teaching them and growing their faith.
They were young Christians, but grew fast - and matured fast.
Despite being a Gentile Church, they were "grafted in" to God's family.
They responded generously at the end of Acts 11 by collecting a relief package for the
Jerusalem Church sent via Barnabas and Saul/Paul.
What can we gather?
The Antioch church, by it's location in a powerful and wealthy city, had God given
financial resources and means to be a sending church.
And respond with their resources they did.
They became the sending church, the launching pad, of not just one, not two, but all
three of Paul's great missionary journeys as recorded in the Book of Acts.
And their sacrificial giving was not limited to money.
They responded to the Holy Spirit's call by sending their best - Barnabas and Paul.
They sent them off sacrificially, they held nothing back.
What about us?
What about ECC?
Are we giving sacrificially for the Great Commission?
Bellevue, Redmond, Seattle, like the City of Antioch, is a wealthy area.
ECC as a church is resource rich.
The heart: are you using your resources for the Great Commission?
Are you using your resources for Kingdom purposes?
Missions Fund: Let me give you some insight on our church's Missions fund.
(show slide) Here's our Missions Budget.
How did we do?
We gave about ½ million dollars through our missions fund, supporting over 40 long term
missionaries, 7 from ECC, spread out over 17 countries, but their missions fields actually
covers more countries than that.
We also supported mid term missionaries and 6 teams of short term missionaries.
As you can see, in 2024, we had a shortfall, and in 2025, we had a surplus.
But even that is a bit misleading.
Albert Ang, who chairs the Missions Committee, informed me that every year, they run a
deficit literally right up until the last couple weeks of the year, because we are
regularly supporting our missionaries throughout the year - and by God's providence, by
prayer, through the compassion of some of the brothers and sisters in Christ, there is a
last minute attempt to make up the deficit so we can continue to support our missionaries
the following year.
Not many know, but our Missions budget, by design, is not commingled with our general
fund, so there is never a risk of raiding it for a church shortfall.
That said, unless you are earmarking donations to the Missions Fund, you are personally
not contributing to it.
So if you feel led by the Holy Spirit to financially support our missionaries, please
contribute your additional donation to the missions fund.
It's easy - just in the memo section of your donation, you can specify how much to the
general fund and how much to the Missions Fund.
Beyond financial giving, they supported their missionaries.
They prayed for them, fasted for them, and encouraged them.
How are we supporting our missionaries?
Prayer - can you pray for our missionaries?
Every week, we highlight one of the missionaries that ECC supports.
You can find out which missionary is highlighted for prayer each week by going to our
website - eccseattle.org - go to worship - then online bulletins.
As Rosalie shared last Sunday during our Mongolian Missions sharing, your prayers mean so
much out there.
Anything can happen.
So many things can go wrong.
There are so many obstacles, hurdles, not to mention, spiritual attacks from Satan that
can derail months of planning that is so much out of our control, but so much is in the
control of our Lord Almighty.
Your blanket of prayer has a deeper and more powerful effect than you could imagine.
Supporting and encouraging our missionaries?
I know some of the small groups have "adopted" a missionary.
Where y'all are in contact with our missionary to check in on them, pray for them, and
give them encouragement.
It's lonely out there!
Your encouragement means a lot.
And When you go on short term missions, a vital role you play is encouraging the local
church and the local long term missionaries who are doing the outreach work.
I've heard multiple times from them that our mere presence out there gives them a lot of
encouragement.
The Church as Sent - what we can learn from the attributes of Barnabas and Paul 2 While
they were worshiping the Lord and fasting, the Holy Spirit said, "Set apart for me
Barnabas and Saul for the work to which I have called them." 3 So after they had fasted
and prayed, they placed their hands on them and sent them off.
How did they respond to the Holy Spirit's call?
They went.
The passage doesn't say whether they struggled and wrestled with their decision, but
based on the terseness of the passage and what we know about them, I think not.
What do we know about these two and what led them to respond the way they did?
I want to spend just a couple minutes going over their attributes and their attitude.
It's a model for how we can respond when God is calling us.
(Missional.
Available.
Compassionate.
Flexible.
Heart of servant.
Willing.
Adaptable.
Selfless.) Barnabas - name meant -"Son of Encouragement" - And he certainly lived up to
his name.
He was the one who was sent from the Jerusalem church to check out the Antioch Church,
but they did not send him only to examine them but to encourage and support them.
We see in him a willing to serve others.
And Barnabas was the one who recruited and sought out Saul/Paul for additional help.
Paul - had an infamous past as a persecutor to the church.
In fact, it is ironic that he was part of the persecution of Stephen that drove the
Jewish believers to Antioch to found this very church that he is serving in.
Paul's persecution of the early church was so intense that after his conversion that his
persecution stopped that there was some semblance of peace in the churches throughout
Galilee and Samaria!!!
(and it said in Acts 9:31 ESV "So the church throughout all Judea and Galilee and Samaria
had peace and was being built up.
And walking in the fear of the Lord and in the comfort of the Holy Spirit, it
multiplied.").
Also, when Paul was zapped and blinded by Jesus and sent to Ananias to be healed, Ananias
was afraid of him.
But Jesus said to Ananias: Acts 9:15 ESV But the Lord said to him, "Go, for he is a
chosen instrument of mine to carry my name before the Gentiles and kings and the children
of Israel.
Paul was an instrument of Jesus to proclaim His name In Ch 11, Paul, for his part, was
willing to drop whatever he was doing in Tarsus and go with Barnabas to assist the Antioch
church.
Paul was a consummate teacher and spent his energy preaching and teaching about Jesus.
And the both of them threw themselves into the ministry alongside the Antioch church.
And now in ch 13, we see them submitting to the calling of the Holy Spirit to be 'sent" I
just want to highlight some of their attributes: They were clearly missional minded -
willing to share the Gospel to everyone and anyone.
They made themselves available.
Their agenda was God's agenda.
And they showed a willingness to serve wherever God sent them.
They were flexible.
They were adaptable.
They were willing to drop their agenda, their schedules, whatever they were doing to
serve the Lord.
This is a key trait for missionaries.
Something I've heard and learned over and over again in the field.
Because you can make all the plans you want, but you don't know how God will use you once
you get out there.
They were willing to be sent.
Barnabas from the Jerusalem Church.
And here, he was again sent from the Antioch Church.
Paul, followed after the way of Jesus - I don't think he had his own home.
From the moment of his conversion on the road to Damascus, Paul was always on the move to
share the Gospel message, proclaiming the risen Christ throughout the Roman world, up
until he was martyred in Rome.
They both were selfless and had the heart of a servant.
Paul embodied the term, "A living sacrifice" - he fully lived the "surrendered life." We
know that multiple times, Paul suffered for the Gospel.
In 1 Corinthians 11, Paul recounts that he was flogged multiple times, beaten with rods,
pelted with stones, shipwrecked, imprisoned multiple times, and left for dead.
Yet amazingly, he remained faithful to Jesus and to his calling to minister to the
Gentiles.
In his letter to the Philippians he wrote "For to me to live is Christ, and to die is
gain." These are all attributes and attitudes that we should have in common when
responding to God's call for us.
But are we all called to go?
Are we all "called to Missions, specifically cross-cultural missions" - Here's our last
topic - What's my Mission in the Great Commission?
The Great Commission one more time - (show it) Your Mission in the Great Commission All
are called to fulfill the Great Commission some people teach and guilt trip people that
all are called to go on cross-cultural missions - I don't think that's actually right
(phew).
I do believe that all are called to fulfill the Great Commission.
As Rick Warren said, "The Great Commission is not the Great Suggestion." Part of the
Great Commission is of course, sharing the Good News of Jesus locally.
In our community, in our schools, in our work, to our friends, to our families.
Really, the missions field is right at our door and sometimes coming into our doors.
It's our sphere of influence.
The Great Commandment and the Great Commission answers all of life's tough questions.
Why am I here?
What's my purpose in life?
How should I live my life?
The Good News is the Good News for everyone, everywhere, including here.
But we shouldn't stop locally - we do need to participate in God's Global missions.
The Great Commission is active today and continues "to the ends of the earth" But the
Gospel message and God's plan in the Great Commission did not stop at the end of Acts.
God is still at work in the world today!
While some areas are well trodden and the Gospel message is widely available, there are
still many areas of the world that are still unreached.
Many of you are familiar with the 10/40 Window - there is still much of the world that
has not heard.
The green areas are areas which are considered "no longer unreached" where there is a
strong Christian presence.
The Red areas are Unreached People Groups defined as people groups with less than 2%
evangelical Christian populations.
In some of the red areas, there are no known efforts focused on establishing
self-sustaining churches with evangelical faith and practice.
For more details, there's a cool interactive map if you go to peoplegroups.org.
How do I know what my "calling" is?
How do I know if I'm being called to go?
How do I know if and how I'm being called to send?
I want to really take the mystery out of the word "calling." It's a really confusing term
and sometimes, it's frankly misused.
"Calling" or "invitation" in the NT almost always refers to our calling as believers, not
our calling to a specific ministry.
1 Cor 1:2, Ephesians 1:18, Hebrews 3:1 1 Corinthians 1:2 ESV To the church of God that is
in Corinth, to those sanctified in Christ Jesus, called to be saints together with all
those who in every place call upon the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, both their Lord and
ours: Ephesians 1:18 ESV having the eyes of your hearts enlightened, that you may know
what is the hope to which he has called you, what are the riches of his glorious
inheritance in the saints, Hebrews 3:1 ESV Therefore, holy brothers, you who share in a
heavenly calling, consider Jesus, the apostle and high priest of our confession, So most
of the time - calling refers to a calling of faith, essentially a call to become a
follower of Christ.
Calling is sometimes used improperly to elevate one's spiritual status.
It's as if my "sense" of divine calling to my particular profession obligates others to
treat me in a special way.
OK, so what's the right way to look at what being "called to a particular ministry" means
- How do I know what my "calling" is?
(Being "called to a particular ministry") - In our passage, the Holy Spirit directly
called out Paul and Barnabas for this missions trip.
For almost all of us, our names will not be called out by the Holy Spirit in a prayer
meeting.
It's also very unlikely that you'll be blinded by Jesus and called to serve a particular
people while out taking a walk.
So how do we know?
How do we know which ministry God is calling you to?
How do we know if God is calling you to cross-cultural missions?
Here's where I really want to take the mystery out of what it means to be called.
And btw, this applies to any calling to any ministry, not just on missions, but yes,
definitely for missions too.
You discover the ministry God is calling you to in 3 phases: Learn, Discern, and Confirm.
Learn: (Exploration) Posture of a student (for the youth here - this is important for
you, but it's also a good reminder for the adults here): I'm here to explore.
To discover.
To Open yourself up to possibilities and make yourself available.
A Willing heart to be used by God.
A teachable heart.
Much like the posture of Paul and Barnabas.
I want to learn what God is doing in the World.
See what He is already doing in different missions field.
Find out what opportunities there are.
Remember - God already has a plan - He's already working - through people, through
organizations, through other churches.
His plan is already enfolding.
You're exploring how you can be part of God's plan.
There are many ways to learn.
Perspectives Class - how many have taken this?
Esther and Pat and others organized this at our church last year.
It's a great course.
I would encourage you to take it the next time it's offered.
Joshuaproject.net - a great website to learn about Go to missions conferences, Seattle
has a yearly Missions Fest (see slide), For college students, check out Urbana, put on by
InterVarsity - now every 3 years - so, if you're a junior or senior in High School - keep
this in mind.
It was an incredible experience when i was in college and still resonates with me even
until today.
Find out how God is already at work throughout the world and see if He may be calling you
to join in what He is already doing.
In the Learning phase, it's all about discovery.
Then comes the next phase: Discern: - Holy Spirit, Prayer and Wise Counsel of others.
Here's where you're figuring out what God is calling you to do.
Passion - do I have a passion for this.
God will rarely make you do something you hate.
Gifting - Do I have the ability, the skills, the aptitude to do this?
Ask yourself, does this ministry fit the way God made me?
Opportunity - Is God presenting an opportunity for me to go?
We see many examples in the Bible where sometimes God's call is just someone asking them
to go.
Barnabas went to Tarsus to find Paul to help in Antioch.
In Paul's 2nd missionary journey in Acts 15, Paul chose Silas to go with him.
Barnabas chose Mark to go another way.
In Acts 16, Paul was in Lystra.
He heard that Timothy had a good reputation so Paul asked Timothy to join him.
For both Silas and Timothy, Paul's invitation was enough for them to go.
Instead of waiting for some miraculous sign, look for opportunities.
Pray - here's a dangerous thing you could do.
You could ask God to show you opportunities to serve Him.
You could ask God to open doors for you to go.
Do Pray that God would open your eyes and open your heart to His missionary work.
Holy Spirit - ask the Holy Spirit to guide you and lead you in Missions.
Ask the Holy Spirit to reveal to you how you can fulfill the Great Commission.
The Holy Spirit leads in a multitude of ways - from circumstances, opening and closing
doors, speaking and convicting you in Scripture, to speaking directly to your soul in a
way that only He can, including visions and miracles.
Wise Counsel of others.
One way the Holy Spirit can speak to you is through the wise counsel of others.
Many times, I have asked mature brothers and sisters in Christ what they thought about my
next steps.
If I should step into a particular ministry.
If I have the right skills and gifting for that.
Confirm: For any ministry - try it out.
Sometimes we just need to go and do.
Whether that is serving in the church, serving in a particular ministry, or missions.
And for missions, short term missions, mid term missions, is a great opportunity to
explore if God is calling you to do missions work In doing the work, is the Holy Spirit
confirming your choice?
Are others affirming your calling and recognizing your role?
Recently Steve Moy was just ordained.
As he shared last week, it was a long journey that got him there.
As part of his ordination, a council of Elders and Pastors met to confirm his calling as
a Pastor.
But here's the interesting thing about it.
It's not like he wasn't already doing the work.
He was!
He was already doing the work of a pastor, a shepherd, an overseer.
Part of his ordination is just a confirmation that he is called to serve as a pastor.
You don't need to be ordained to do the work God is calling you to do.
Try doing the ministry that you think God is leading you to do.
See if that lines up with your gifting and if you have an aptitude for it.
See if you really have a passion for it.
See if others recognize and affirm your calling to it.
See if the Holy Spirit, in all the ways that He works, confirms your ministry.
Let me conclude with this.
Rick Warren again said - "A great commitment to the Great Commandment and the Great
Commission will make you a great Christian." The Great Commandment - Love God with all
your heart, soul, and mind, (and love others).
The Great Commission - Go and make disciple of all nations - A commitment to both, will
make you a great Christian.
We are all called to fulfill the Great Commission.
We need to discover how God will use us, our God given gifts, our resources, and our
ability to share the Good News of Jesus around us and beyond us.
Is God calling you to send?
Is God calling you to go?