Good morning.
>> Good morning. Happy Easter.
>> Okay, that I only heard two people. All
right, let's do that again. Good
morning. Happy Easter.
>> He has risen, right? Okay, let's rise
everybody.
All right, happy Easter to those online
for not being able to join us. This is
ECC Redmond. Um, welcome and hopefully
one day you guys can join us here live
as well. Um, so let's go ahead and sing
praises to him this morning.
How great the chasm
that lay between us. How high the
mountain
I could not climb.
In desperation,
I turned to heaven
and spoke your name into the night.
And through the darkness,
your loving kindness
tore through the shadows
of my soul.
The work is finished.
The end is written.
Jesus Christ my living
hope.
Who could imagine
so great a mercy?
What heart could fathom
such boundless grace?
The God of aes
step down in glory
to wear my sin and bear my shame.
The cross has spoken.
I am forgi.
The King of Kings calls me his own.
Beautiful Savior,
I'm yours forever.
Jesus Christ, my livinging
hope.
Hallelujah.
Praise the one who set me free.
Death has lost his grip on me. You have
broken every chain. There's salvation in
your name. Jesus Christ, my living
hope.
Hallelujah.
Praise the one who set me free.
Death has lost its grip on me. You have
broken every chain. There's salvation in
your name. Jesus Christ, my living
hope.
Then came the morning
that sealed the promise.
Your buried body
began to breathe.
Out of the silence,
the roaring lion
declare the grave has no claim on me.
Then came the morning
that sealed the promise.
Your very body
began to breathe.
Out of the silence,
the roaring lion
declare the grave had no blame on me.
Jesus, yours is the victory.
Hallelujah.
Praise the one who set me free.
Death has lost its fruit for me. You
have broken every chain. There's
salvation in your name, Jesus Christ, my
livinging
hope.
Hallelujah.
Praise the one and set me free.
Death has lost its grip on me. You have
broken every chain. There's salvation in
your name. Jesus Christ, my livinging
hope.
Jesus Christ, my living.
Oh God, you are my living
hope.
Amen. Lift it up.
All right. Okay. With that, greet your
neighbors. Congratulate each other. You
have been saved. You are here today. You
have been saved. Congratulate. Hug each
other. Congratulate each other.
>> You have been saved. The Lord has saved
you. You are here.
And also for those that are sitting in
the back, please move to the middle.
I've been told to tell you guys that as
well.
Ah, such a s so amazing that our Lord
has saved us. We don't deserve it. We
don't. We really don't. every single day
I'm just like I'm so blessed. Every
single time there's a miracle in my
life, I'm just like I don't deserve it.
Um and I know like this is this great
day, this Easter, you know, like is
where we're here to remember that the
Lord died on the cross for us, but we
really should remember it every single
day of our lives.
My hope is built on nothing less
than Jesus blood and righteousness.
I dare not trust the sweetest frame,
but only trust in Jesus name.
My hope is built on nothing less
than Jesus blood and righteousness.
I dare not trust the sweetest friend
but only trust in Jesus name.
Christ alone
corner stone
we made strong his savior's
love
through the storm
he is Lord
Lord of all
in darkness seems to highest face.
I rest on his unchanging grace.
In every hard and stormy air,
my anger holds within the veil.
My anger holds his name.
Like the Lord,
cornerstone
that we made strong in a day of love
through the stor.
He is Lord.
Lord of all,
he is Lord.
when he shall come with trumpet sound.
Oh, may I bend in him be found
dressed in his rightousness
alone.
For they stand before the throne.
Christ alone,
corner stone,
weak made strong in Savior's
love
through the storm.
He is Lord,
Lord of all.
Christ alone,
cornerstone,
weak made strong in the Savior's
love
through the storm.
He is Lord,
Lord our home.
Thousand generations
Falling down in worship
to sing the song of ages to the lamb.
And all who have gone before us and all
who will believe
sing the song of ages to the land.
Your name is the highest. Your name is
the greatest. Your name
stands above them all.
All throws and the minions. All power
and position. Your name
stands above them all. And the angels
cry.
Holy.
All creation cries.
You are lifted high,
holy,
holy forever.
If you've been forgiven
and if you've been redeemed,
sing the song forever to the lamb.
If you walk in freedom
and if you bear his name,
sing the song forever to the lamb.
Sing the song forever and amen.
And the angels cry,
"Holy,
all creation cry,
holy,
you are lifted high,
holy forever."
Your people sing
holy
to the king of kings.
Holy.
He will always be.
Holy,
holy forever.
Your name is the highest. Your name is
the greatest. Your name
stands above them all.
All thrones and dominance, all powers
and positions. Your name
stands above them all.
Jesus, your name is the highest. Your
name is the greatest. Your name
stands above all.
All
and dominions, all powers and position.
Your name
stands above them all. And the angels
cry.
Holy
all creation cries.
you are lifted high.
Holy,
holy forever.
Your people sing.
Holy
to the King of Kings.
Holy.
He will always be,
holy,
holy forever.
You will always be
holy,
holy forever.
Father God, we come before you this
Easter morning with thanksgiving and
praise. This past Good Friday, we
remembered and reflected on your son,
our Lord Jesus, who bore our sins and
our shame and paid the ultimate price
for something he did not deserve, but we
clearly did.
But we thank you, Father, that this was
not the finality of the story. That in
power he conquered death, resurrected
from the dead three days later, so that
we also might share and be partakers
with him in life, eternal life.
May all your people around the world
rejoice and give you praise today for
indeed Jesus is our risen savior and
lord.
And we take turn as we take turns
lifting up the different congregations
in prayer. We now turn to lift up to you
our brothers and sisters in the Seattle
Cantonese congregation. We thank you for
raising up faithful Sunday school
teachers who take the time to share
their gifts and knowledge and willingly
serve to build up the body of Christ. We
pray for the brothers and sisters in
that congregation who are ill, frail, or
undergoing cancer treatment. We lift up
to you Mr. Gao, Mrs. Shiao, Ted, Tommy,
Steven, Daniel, and Sylvia. We ask that
you would place your healing hand upon
them and grant wisdom to their treating
physicians.
We pray for the outreach ministry at
Legacy House. We pray that you would
raise up more brothers and sisters who
are willing to respond to your call and
participate in that local gospel
ministry.
We also take the time to lift up to you
prayers for our missionaries.
This Sunday, we lift up to you Shawn and
Mandy Miller who serve as area directors
for the Caribbean and Bermuda area with
Child Evangelism Fellowship.
May you work through them as they equip
and lead the local CEF staff and those
uh who are serving in those countries.
May your gospel message find fruit in
the children that they serve and reach
out to.
And we pray for the wars go ongoing in
Iran and Ukraine. We pray that you would
provide a peaceful resolution. May it
come swiftly and according to your
sovereign will. We pray for our
Christian brothers and sisters around
the world who are undergoing
persecution.
May you grant them protection and may
you give them hope on this resurrection
Sunday. And let's pray the Lord's prayer
as he taught us. Our Father in heaven,
hallowed be your name. Your kingdom
come, your will be done on earth as it
is in heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread, and forgive us our debts as we
also have forgiven our debtors. And lead
us not into temptation, but deliver us
from evil. For yours is the kingdom, and
the power, and the glory forever. Amen.
Please be seated.
again. Happy Easter.
>> Happy Easter.
>> Today especially, but not only today,
today especially, we celebrate that
Christ rose from the dead. We celebrate
the gospel of Jesus Christ. His life,
his death, and his resurrection that
proves
that he is who he said he is. It proves
that he saved us and even conquered
death.
All too often, we tend to leave Easter
in the past.
God doesn't leave Easter in the past.
God wants Easter in our present.
lives, not just 2,000 years ago. And in
the passage today, God through Paul is
speaking to us about the effects of what
Christ did in the present. He brings
Easter into the present.
And I think it's a great passage to go
through
for Easter Sunday. And so with that in
mind, I invite you to stand with me and
let's read together Romans 8:31-39.
If God is for us, who is No, I'm sorry.
I skipped the line there. I treated it
like a t title. What shall we say to
these things? If God is for us, who is
against us? He who did not spare his own
son, but delivered him over for us all.
How will he not also with him freely
give us all things? Who will bring
charges against God's elect? God is the
one who justifies, who is the one who
condemns. Christ Jesus is he who died,
but rather was raised, who is at the
right hand of God, who also intercedes
for us, who will separate us from the
love of Christ, will tribulation or
trouble or persecution or famine or
nakedness or danger or sword.
Just as it is written, for your sake we
are killed all day long. We were
regarded as sheep to be slaughtered. But
in all these things we overwhelmingly
conquered through him who loved us. For
I am convinced that neither death, nor
life, nor angels, nor principalities,
nor things present, nor things to come,
nor powers, nor height, nor depth, nor
any other created thing will be able to
separate us from the love of God that is
in Christ Jesus our Lord. Amen. And
amen. You may be seated.
Now to understand what Paul is saying,
we need to put it into context and
remember that Paul has written this
letter to the Christians in Rome to tell
them about the gospel he has been
preaching. And all along
and after covering all the basis of the
gospel and answering some questions that
people have in the beginning of Romans
8, he makes this great declaration.
There is now no more condemnation at all
for those who are in Christ Jesus. Did
you hear that? There is no condemnation.
Not at all for those who are in Christ
Jesus.
And yet despite this,
as he then proceeds to say, we still
struggle with sin. We still wrestle with
sin. In verses 1-1, he covers that. And
we still suffer. We grown through
hardships and burdens. In 12-1 17, and
we are longing for our bodies to be
redeemed.
And yet, we're still waiting and
waiting. A lifetime of waiting. And in
that lifetime, we often suffer pain and
suffering and sickness and loss
and still waiting for Jesus to come.
18-26 he covers this.
And at the end of it all, we still die.
In the middle of all this though, Paul
points out that we have been given the
Holy Spirit. We are not orphans.
The Holy Spirit works in us to enable us
to fight against sin and to struggle and
to give us hope. Verses 1 to 11. The
Holy Spirit causes us to identify and
call out to God as our father. Aba
Father.
The Holy Spirit prays to the father for
us.
And he helps us throughout life.
We are not orphans.
And now we come to verses 31-39.
And Paul says, "What shall we say to
these things?"
What shall we say to these things? All
these things he just said
and more.
And he then answers this question with
five rhetorical questions. Now
rhetorical questions are like statements
in the question form. The answer is so
obvious
that everybody knows and it invites us
from within our hearts to respond
and say they can be very powerful.
Those questions he gives us
in verses 31b to 36.
You know, if I for instance say that ice
cream is made with a lot of sugar, who
can say ice cream is not sweet? You say,
you say. I'm inviting you. Say it.
>> Say what?
>> Of course it's sweet.
No one can say it's not sweet.
Okay, that one fell flat.
God keeps me humble.
But you understand the answer is so
obvious you you know nobody can say it's
not sweet.
At the end of verses 37 and 39 Paul
concludes his answers and wraps them up
with a key idea. God's love is the key
the power that overcomes all this.
So since the essential question that we
are answering this passage is what shall
we say about these things?
What shall we say about these things?
Let's make sure we understand who we is
and who these things are that he's
talking about. I already hinted that
these things are everything he says in
chapter 8. But more especially Paul is
referring to what he just said in verses
28-30 when he said, "We know that God
causes all things to work together for
good to those who love God,
to those who are called according to his
purpose. For those whom he forno, he
also predestined to become conformed to
the image of his son, so that he would
be the firstborn among many brothers and
sisters. And these whom he predestined,
he also called. And these whom he
called, he also justified. And these
whom he justified, he also glorified.
So the we he is talking about is we who
have been fornown, who have been
predestined, who have been called, who
have been justified, who have been
glorified,
those who have been saved. And these
things are those things good and bad
that serve God's purpose in fornowing us
and predestining us and calling us and
justifying us. all his
means to the end of saving us and
glorifying us in Christ Jesus.
And so the question is, what shall we
say about these things?
And the first answer Paul gives in 31B
is if God is for us,
who can be against us? I mean, nobody
can defeat God.
No one no one then can can def can can
defeat us. None can succeed
since God fought for us. No one can go
against what he has done for us. They
can't stop his he they can't keep God
from calling us. No person can block
God's for knowing us. None can cloud
God's predestination.
God justified. There's none then who can
condemn
what God did for us in Christ on Jesus
in on Easter will absolutely succeed is
already succeeded.
What then shall we say about these
things? Verse 32 he says he who did not
spare his own son but delivered him up
over for us all. How will he not also
with him freely give us all things?
I think of the man who buys a half
million dollar boat. Is that man going
to then take that boat and park it on
his driveway and forget about it?
Of course not. Having spent so much
money for the boat, he's going to spend
more money to fill it up and take it out
on for a ride
and go fishing, whatever he wants to do
in the boat. And he's going to spend
money to maintain it. He's going to
spend money to repair it. He's going to
treasure that thing.
That's what Paul is saying.
God has paid the absolutely monumental
price of giving his son to gain us and
get us back to himself.
Of course, he's going to spend the
pennies
necessary to give us everything we need
to know him and to follow him
to succeed in life for what he wants us
to succeed in.
This is important because as we saw
earlier, as you look earlier in in this
chapter, we do suffer.
We do have setbacks. We do have losses.
Relationships fail. We lose loved ones.
We can get ill. And sometimes in the
middle of all that, we're going to say,
"Where is God?
Has God forgotten me?
Is God angry with me? And what Paul is
saying is absolutely not. He has paid so
much for you. He's not going to turn you
away. He's not going to forget you. He's
right there.
He's in your life and he has given you
everything you need. Hang on. Latch on
to him and keep on walking.
What shall we say to these things?
Who will bring charges against God's
elect?
God is the one who justifies.
You know, it's not just God. God is the
judge and he has already declared us not
guilty. Now, we could confuse.
When God says we're not guilty, that
doesn't mean we're innocent.
An illustration helps here. And Jesus
gives us the illustration with the
servant of a master. And the servant
owed the masses the master a massive
amount of money.
He couldn't pay it back. And he begged
his master to forgive him. And so his
master did and he wiped the debt clean.
There's the illustration. The debt is
canceled.
No longer guilty. The man failed to pay
the debt back. That is a fact.
The man is not innocent of failing to
pay the debt back. But the debt has been
paid for him. The debt has been paid for
us by God.
There is no more debt.
So how can anybody bring any charges
against us? There's there's nothing
left.
It's completed
and cleared out.
Yeah, we we struggle with sin. We do
wrong things. Our sin is real and we
have guilt. We feel it. But God doesn't
want us then to wallow in our guilt.
That's what Satan wants. He wants us to
wallow in our guilt. God wants us to
confess our sin. He wants us to repent.
and he wants us to get up and keep on
walking with him. That's what God wants
us to do. To turn our back and move
forward and to grow.
That's the response. Because there is no
guilt in God's sight anymore.
What shall we say about these things?
Who's the one that condemns?
Christ Jesus is he who died but rather
raised who was at the right hand of God
who also intercedes for us.
Christ's saving work is finished. It is
complete and absolute. He not only died
for our sins, paying the debt, he also
rose from the dead. Happy Easter. It is
complete. It is vindicated. It is proven
right. He also raised to the right hand
of God the Father. The right hand is the
most honored place in all of heaven. And
think about it. If Christ is sitting in
the most honored place, will God not
honor what he did for us? He will. And
on top of that, Paul is saying he is
interceding for us. He's praying for us.
He's speaking on behalf for us. We we
catch a glimpse of this in how for
instance Jesus prayed for Peter
in the upper room.
Jesus said to Peter, "Simon, Simon,
behold, Satan has demanded to sift you
like wheat, but I have prayed for you
that your faith will not fail. And when
you have turned back, strengthen your
brothers. Christ prayed for Simon.
Satan wants to sift him like men sift
wheat.
But Christ prayed
his faith would not fail. He is praying
for you and me today.
Today as he sits to the throne, he is
praying for you and me to the father.
that we too will continue in the faith,
that we too will succeed, that we too
will not fail, that we too will not let
go.
He's not just founding empty promises.
He is actively saving us today
and bringing us along in his great
sanctifying work
which he will complete when all
eternity.
What shall we say about these things?
Who will separate us from the love of
Christ?
With tribulation or trouble or
persecution or famine or nakedness or
danger or sword, just as it is written,
for your sake, we are killed all day
long. We are regarded as sheep to be
slaughtered.
Again, we have to say no one. The
question is, who will separate us from
Christ? the love of Christ. No one,
none can.
God is zealous for you, my friends. He
is zealous for you. He is zealous for
you.
the love of Christ.
This passage reminds us of what he
already said in Romans 8:28.
All things work together for good.
In many ways, this question and these
answers that Paul's given are
elaboration on that one verse there. All
things work together not to separate us
from Christ, but to unite us with him.
God is the one who causes them to work
because God loves us
and we have been called according to his
purpose.
But you notice here
at Romans 8:28, it's we who love God.
Here it's Christ who loves us.
Our love may fail, but his love never
fails.
never lets us down.
And notice also Paul asked who, but
everything on this list is an it. It's a
thing. You don't see a who there, but we
are reminded here that behind the things
that happen in our lives, there is a
who.
We may not see it.
Sometimes it's another person. Sometimes
it's our own failure. But ultimately,
our great enemy is Satan himself
who is battling against us and waring
against us. As Peter says in 1 Peter
5'8, "Be sober, be alert. Your
adversary, the devil, prowls around like
a roaring lion, seeking someone to
devour.
He is active.
He is working against you and me.
And we have seen in scripture that he
can use famine, he can use wars, he can
use disease, he can cause economies to
collapse and natural disasters.
And he can tempt us to sin.
He can provoke people to oppose us and
hurt us and harm us.
But Paul says, and we may wonder, again,
we may wonder, is God against me? Is God
angry with me? But again, he says, just
as it is written.
Just as is written. Let me go back to
that. Just as it is written. That phrase
means our situation is the same as those
people in this quote from Psalm 44:22.
These people also suffer. These people
are also being killed
for somebody's sake.
Not because they did anything wrong.
They were innocent of of wrongdoing
here. Like Christ
suffered for the sake of us. I think of
Job.
Job didn't know what's going on. Satan
provoked God and Satan caused many
things to happen in Job. the death of
his children, the loss and and pillaging
of all his possessions, great illness
come upon his suffering, and then his
friends discourage him. Even his wife
says, "Why don't you just curse God and
get it over with?"
Joel did not give up.
He didn't get everything right, but he
did not give up. He He latched on to
God. He stayed hooked to God. He looked
to God. He asked, "God, defend me." And
in the end, God sets a record straight.
And God blesses him more than ever
before. And then God does something
through him that he never saw.
We are all blessed and we are all
encouraged as we read about Job.
for our sake.
God took that suffering and that loss of
Job and he speaks for generations to
others
so that we may understand
God is in it all and God is not
forgotten.
Even our enemy may pull us down, but he
will not prevail.
God never lets us go.
So what if somebody kills us? Then we go
to heaven to be with Jesus in glory.
So what if we hunger and thirst and are
chasteed?
Didn't they do that to Jesus also?
Yet Jesus overcame it all by love.
Love of God, God's love for us.
And that is where Hebles goes next in
verses 37-39.
But in all these things we
overwhelmingly conquer through him who
loved us. For I am convinced that
neither death nor life, nor angels, nor
principalities, nor things present, nor
things to come, nor powers, nor height,
nor depth, nor any created other created
thing will be able to separate us from
the love from the love of God that is in
Christ Jesus
our Lord.
This is the conclusion
and the conclusion brings us to the love
of God.
The love of God is the power that holds
us to himself.
It saves us and then holds us to himself
and none can separate us.
It is the power that superconquers
everything and turns it for our benefit
through him who loved us. He who died
and he who rose again from the dead. He
who purchased us for himself by dying
and paying the debt for our sin and
justifying us with his life.
You know, a super conqueror, an
overwhelmingly conqueror is one who
takes his enemies and makes them serve
him.
Again, just as he said, all things work
together for good for those who love
God.
who are called according to his purpose.
God makes everything serve
in this life today. The things you go
through, the things you face, the things
you that challenge you, God is using
them to make and mold his love in your
life and draw him closer to himself.
Death serves to liberate our decaying
bodies from sin
and frees us to receive the resurrected
spiritual body without.
Life gives us room to grow. Angels serve
us. Principalities a reference to the
donic realm. Principalities test us and
they tempt us. But God uses these trials
to strengthen us.
Present things distract us. But over
time we realize these things will never
satisfy us.
And more and more we say, "God,
fill my life.
Be my end."
None can compare to Christ. Illness
makes us let go of hope in life today.
This is not our hope. My hope is in
Christ and the life that God has given
me. And I look for the return of Christ
to make heaven and earth meet together.
Everything, everything,
everything is made to serve God's
saving, sanctifying
love work in you and me.
Everything is under God's control.
Why?
Because God loves us.
He loves us.
He takes the things that the devil would
use to separate us from him and uses
them to draw us closer to himself.
But there is a peculiar thing in this
passage.
The peculiar thing is he says we
overwhelmingly
conquer through him who loved us. We
overwhelmingly conquer through him who
loved us.
How so?
When we see the love of Christ for us,
we are moved to follow him,
to live for him, to rely on him, to
trust him.
It's not actually we who do it but as we
ride along with him through him
we conquer and even more than conquer
by ourselves we do not do it but he
gives us a power and even he's given us
himself today the Holy Spirit in our
lives and so John says in 1 John 4:4 you
are from God little children and have
overcome come them. There's that
overcoming again.
Because greater is he who is in you than
he who is in the world. Greater is he,
the Holy Spirit, the spirit of Christ
who is in you, brothers and sisters,
than he who is in the world.
Because of the love of God, we conquer
through Christ on the cross.
God has conquered so much already.
He conquered the debt. He paid the debt
for sin.
He turned not death into life, darkness
into light,
despair into hope.
That is the love of God that conquers my
heart and yours
and makes us to follow to him. So what
do we do? What do we say? How shall we
respond?
First, I would say bring Easter into
your life today.
Bring Easter into your life today. What
do I mean?
See your present difficulties as more
than just difficulties. They are
opportunities.
Opportunities to look to God, to rely on
God, to commune with God.
Yeah, we have difficulties and we will
have difficulties.
If anything, as we get older, they will
increase
and God is training us and growing us
and God is renewing us
and refining us.
Easter is that resurrection power that
turns and reverses the whole order of
the curse and brings us life and hope in
Christ.
And God's presence is more than just a
ticket to heaven
is the way of living.
And Paul tells us that Jesus now is the
right hand of God and he is praying for
us. But not only is Jesus praying for
us, the Holy Spirit is praying for us
also. We have two persons of the Godhead
at li actively in our lives praying for
us, rooting for us, cheering for us.
So live in hope.
live looking to God and not just the
circumstances around you
because he already lived and died for
you.
Bring Easter into your present life, not
just in the past, not just in the
future, today. Love God and serve God.
Love God and serve God. The Bible is
God's design for life. Bible is God's
love letter to us.
Read it, admire it, meditate on it, put
it in your heart so that you might walk
according to what his word says. As
Jesus says in John's 14, John 14:21,
the one who has my commandments and
keeps them is the one who loves me.
That's how we love God. The one who
loves me, he will be loved by my father
and I will love him and reveal myself to
him.
The Bible tells us about the love of
God.
And as Paul reminds us in Romans 5'8,
God demonstrates his love toward us and
that while we were still sinners, Christ
died for us. God doesn't just give us a
bunch of pretty words about how I love
you. He demonstrates he has loved us.
So be you motivated by his love to
follow his word to serve him in action
in the ways he says trusting him. Make
that the goal of your life
and in so serving him you worship him.
Three, in response,
care for those God cares for. Care for
those God cares for. Have a
missionminded life.
As Paul says in Romans 13:8,
"Owe nothing to anyone except
to love one another, for one who loves
his neighbor has fulfilled the law."
Even though the people around us face
difficulties,
they suffer.
And one way we love people is to share
the burden, to cry with them. And yeah,
to laugh with them, to give them
something they need,
to understand them, to listen to them,
even to pray for them.
Not just when you ask them, but say, "Do
you mind if I pray for you now?" You'd
be surprised how many people will say,
"Yes, please pray for me."
Doesn't matter. They're believers or
not. They want somebody to care whether
they really believe in God or not.
Hey, if you're willing to pray for me,
I'll let you pray for me.
And it's not just non-Christians. As
Christians, we all need
share in our life. Be blessed.
in our life to bring blessing to others
and then to share Christ himself. You
know we we can't sol solve our own
problems a lot of times but we do have
Jesus with us
helping us guiding us giving us
strength.
Can you imagine what it's like to face
all the problems of life without Christ
there?
Share Christ with them.
Not only they might be saved, but they
might have Jesus in their daily life
today.
Let me conclude with story about CH
Spurgeon.
CH Spurgeon,
a great preacher.
He taught himself to read by the time he
was five years old.
He was pretty much raised by his
grandfather who was also a pastor.
And he gobbled up and read his
grandfather's books and commentaries and
everything else.
By the time he was 17, he was pastoring
his first church. His preaching was so
powerful
he drew very large crowds. He is
considered one of the five greatest
preachers in history.
In a large service at Siri Music Hall
when he was just 20 years old, about
10,000 people were there listening to
him preach.
and some person decided to pull a prank
and yelled out loud, "Fire."
And of course, the people panicked. The
result is over 30 people were injured
and seven people died.
This impacted CH Spurs greatly
and from that point on he fought
depression.
It plagued him the rest of his life. He
could not get out of depression
because he felt so strongly the
responsibility here.
And later, not too many years later, he
kept suffering from gout. And they
didn't know how to treat gout like we do
today.
And he would spend days at the time
bedridden with gout, suffering
physically, suffering emotionally and
depression.
But you know what? CH Persian never let
go. He never gave up. He kept turning to
the word of God. He kept sharing the
word of God. He kept preaching the word
of God. He kept living out the love of
Christ and helping others.
And he never let go of the hope of
Christ that Christ gave him on Easter
Sunday.
And you know what? Through his ministry
and the ministry he founded, over 200
churches were planted
and the seminary was started
and people still read his sermons
and his devotionals.
He overcame.
He saw the love of God. And even though
he struggled,
he latched on to the love of God. And he
never stopped.
And that's how he conquered through
Christ.
And that's how we conquer through
We look to him. We see his love and we
do not let go even though we struggle.
You see, we don't have to be happy and
clappy all the time to be faithful to
Christ. We just have to keep following
him
and trusting him
and loving him.
That's what it takes
to be a conqueror through Christ.
Let us pray.
Lord, thank you. Thank you for coming
into our lives. Thank you for taking
what you did in the cross and bringing
it to heaven and bringing it into our
lives today
and giving us that hope and love to keep
on living and never let go. You latched
on to us and now we latch back on to you
and we through you will become more than
conquerors.
Glory be to you Lord Jesus.
We will cast all the crowns before your
throne. In your name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
All right.
Let's go ahead and stand and sing our
response song.
We are convinced, right? We are
convinced that he is going to take us
through everything in our lives.
I am convinced
that not even life, not even death can
break apart
the love of God from reaching out to
touch your soul and touch your heart.
I am convinced
not even angels or the demons of the
dark
come against the mighty evering
arms of our God.
Nothing.
Oh, nothing
nothing can reverse
the love of
our Savior
from chasing after us.
End times
we stray
so
far.
Nothing can undo
the love of God.
Nothing now, nothing then, nothing
beyond
even keep us from the ever loving bond
of our God.
I am convinced
the deepest depth of the highest of the
high
all creation cannot keep the love of
blood
and die.
Nothing.
Oh, nothing.
Nothing can reverse
the love of
our savior
from chasing after us.
Even
times
we stray
so
far.
Nothing can undo
the love of God.
No angel,
no devil,
no army,
a re,
no ner
has inure,
no time in the future,
no life,
no Never
no distance
in me long. No high
can reach you. No place he can reach
you.
Nothing.
Oh nothing,
nothing can reverse
the Lord
our savior
from chasing after
the
time
we streng
So
far,
nothing can undo
the love of the Lord.
And nothing can do.
Not the love of God.
As we come to this time of taking the
Lord's supper,
let us it again remind us of the depth
of the love of God
that we he would shed his blood for us.
Break his body for us.
He would not let any come between us and
him. Latch on to that love. be reminded
by that love, be encouraged, and then
turn and live for him and live for those
he cares about.
This I invite the service to come
forward
Take, eat in remembrance of him.
Take and drink, remembering he's coming
again.
Thank you, Father, for being with us,
loving us, and never letting go.
Jesus name we pray. Amen.
And now let's rise and sing to do
all
creatures
below.
Praise him.
the heavenly
host. Praise
the son and holy
host.
And now may the God of peace through the
blood of the eternal covenant brought
back from the dead, our Lord Jesus.
Please be seated.
>> Good morning, church. Happy Easter.
>> He is risen.
>> Good job. Good job. Okay. Uh, so we're
going to start off before some
announcements with welcoming visitors.
Uh, if it's your first time or you've
been too shy before, we're going to ask
you to raise your hand. If you're
sitting on my right side, your left, uh,
please raise your hand. Visitors. Wow.
Right here in the front. Thank you. Any
and also back there. I see. Okay. We're
We're going to give you some information
and we're going to also ask for contact
information if you're willing to share
that. So, we'll follow up with you also
after service. It's going to be a little
tricky, but on this side, my left, your
right, any visitors, I don't see them in
an east lobby. Uh there's an usher there
also who will connect with you. Uh we're
glad you're here. Welcome. Uh we want to
get to know you more. Uh yes, great. So,
we'll go into announcements. Uh
immediately after service, uh there will
be baptisms. Uh 12 of our youth are
getting baptized. Please come support
them. It's an important milestone in
their spiritual journey. Uh that's
happening in the Mandarin Hall. So
that's just down the hallway. If you
haven't been there, you'll have to exit
here and go down. Uh that's at 11:15. So
there will be no adult or youth Sunday
school. Uh we will need to leave this
space by 11:00. To aid in making that
happen, we won't be removing chairs from
this side. Snack will be in the hallway.
Pick it up and leave. Uh but also chat,
you know, but but get out of here
because uh we got to go go to baptisms
and also Mandarin second service will be
in this space. So uh we encourage you to
still socialize. It's valuable. Uh just
know logistically it's a little
different than usual. Great. Uh Henry uh
is is leading this um board game
interchurch group and that is meeting
this Saturday at 6 PM at ECC Seattle
gym. So there's some information here.
There's a QR code. Please sign up
because dinner is provided. That's for
our young adults specifically. Uh I'm a
representative of Steven Ministry and
that's one way that our church provides
care for people who are hurting. Uh end
of life is an important part of life and
we're having a guest speaker share in
Mandarin uh about preparing for end of
life care. So that is going to be not
this Saturday but the following Saturday
in the morning. Uh but it is in
Mandarin. So, not all of us maybe it's
targeting, but uh if it's something that
you could benefit from, uh please join
us.
Our Taiwan short-term mission team goes
to Pingling uh every year except for
there was a gap with COVID and then
every other year we've had students from
Pingling come to America. Uh we need to
be able to host them and we're inviting
families uh if you're willing to host uh
please come to an information session.
That's the last Sunday of this month.
It's an opportunity for cultural
exchange with those students, but also
for them to see what it's like living in
a Christian household. Uh so, Uncle
Joseph is leading that effort. His
contact info is here. Uh please join us
either in person or on Zoom.
We have an administrative assistant
part-time position that's open uh here
at ECC Redmond Church office. There's
actually five other ministry related
positions also. Uh so if you or someone
you know might be a good candidate,
please uh check out the website for more
details.
If you wear eyeglasses and you've had an
old pair that are gently used that you
no longer need, uh we're collecting
those uh to partner with an organization
to provide uh vision for uh people in
developing countries that might not have
access to the appropriate care. So
there's a box uh on your way in that's
happening for the next couple months.
If you uh probably are current Sunday
school teacher for children, uh you
might not be in the room, but if you've
been in past quarters or are thinking
about teaching Sunday school, uh we'd
love to invite you to a training that's
happening on the last Saturday of this
month. Uh that includes lunch. Please
reach out to Gordon for more
information.
And VBS, the dates are announced for
Redmond campus. Uh we'll need volunteers
to make that happen. Vacation Bible
School is a really important and
impactful meaningful experience. uh for
those elementary school uh students and
younger. Um so please uh consider
volunteering.
Our church has partnered with a
predominantly uh white and predominantly
black church uh for the last 10 years to
make kindred community happen. Uh I want
you to mark your dates. If you're in a
small group, go ahead and be thinking
about how you can incorporate uh a
kindred study into what you do or
consider joining one of the crossurch
groups uh that will be happening at that
time.
And then if you're not plugged in to a
small group in our church, you've been
attending, want to be a part of the
community better, this is a great way uh
to get connected. So there's a lot of
details here. We also have a little
contact card uh just outside the hall if
you need more information.
Our bulletins, we have some of them in
in print form, but we also have QR codes
uh if you want to see it digitally. If
you missed one of the links, uh that's
important. Please see it for more
information. And yeah, there's a lot of
lot of helpful information. The online
bulletin,
giving of tithes and offering is part of
our worship. Uh if you don't consider
ECC your church home, please don't feel
obligated to give, but there are several
methods uh by which you can give. Just
know that that's available. There's an
offering box also outside.
Thank you very much for joining us this
morning. Happy Easter, church. And
remember uh pick up your snack and you
know continue congregating but also move
to to uh Mandarin worship hall. Thank
you so much. Oh I have one more thing
for the youth uh YSF and YF uh if you
hopefully you're staying for your fellow
youth who are being baptized immediately
following that please gather in M101 in
the ministry building. Uh those youth
are going to have a time uh for sharing
and some light refreshments.