Good morning church.
>> Let's stand. Let's praise our God
together.
Sing.
I see the work of your hands.
Galaxy spinning a heavenly dance. Oh
God, all that you are so overwhelming.
And I hear the sound of your voice
all at once. It's a gentle and
thundering noise. Oh God, all that you
are is so overwhelming.
I delight myself in you.
Captivated
by your beauty. I'm overwhelmed.
I'm overwhelmed
by you,
God. I run into your arms,
unashamed
because of mercy. I'm overwhelmed.
I'm overwhelmed
by you.
I know the power of your cross.
Forgiven and free forever. You be my
God. All that you've done is so
overwhelming.
I delight myself in you.
in the glory of your presence. I'm
overwhelmed.
I'm overwhelmed
by you,
God. I run into your arms
and ashamed because of mercy. I'm
overwhelmed.
I'm overwhelmed
by you.
You are beautiful.
Oh God, there is no one more beautiful.
God, you are the most beautiful.
You are wonderful.
Oh God, there is no one more wonderful.
God, you are the most wonderful.
You are glorious.
You are glorious,
oh God. There is no one more glorious.
God. You are the most glorious.
I delight myself in you.
In the glory of your presence, I'm
overwhelmed.
I'm overwhelmed.
by you,
God. I run into your arms
and ashamed because of mercy. I'm
overwhelmed.
I'm overwhelmed
by you.
I'm overwhelmed.
I'm overwhelmed
by you.
Amen.
Amen. Well, good morning and welcome to
ECC Redmond. Thank you for joining us
and thank you for joining us if you're
on the live stream as well. Um why don't
we just take a moment to turn to those
around us and greet them in the name of
the Lord.
All
right, church. Let's come together and
worship our heavenly father together.
Um, and remind each other of his
goodness. We know all too well to well
that the world outside these doors is
just fractured by conflict and injustice
and it's so easy to feel lost and
disheartened. So let's sing and
encourage each other uh to look up to
fix our eyes on Jesus because he's the
king of glory and he has already
overcome this world and broken the power
of sin and darkness. So please pray pray
with us as we ask God to bless this time
of worship. Let's pray.
Heavenly Father, we just come to you
just as we are. And some of us carrying
the weight of the weak and others
feeling the heaviness of the world
around us. Lord,
we ask that you would meet us here.
Silence the noise in our minds, the
anxieties in our hearts so that we can
have a time of connection with you.
Lord,
remind us of your goodness and your
amazing grace.
Lord Jesus, may your Holy Spirit move us
to see all the goodness you have already
shown to us
and fill us with a heart of gratitude
and wonder at the sacrifice you made for
us already. And we ask that you bless
this time of worship in Jesus mighty
name. We pray these things. Amen.
Let's see
who breaks power of sin and darkness,
whose love is mighty and so much
stronger.
The King of glory, the King above all,
who shakes the whole earth with holy
thunder, who leaves us breathless
in awe and wonder. The King of glory.
The King above all kings.
This is amazing grace.
This is unfailing love.
That you would take my place.
That you would bear my cross.
you would lay down your life
that I would be set free.
Oh Jesus, I sing for all that you've
done for me.
Who brings out chaos
back into order? Who makes the orphan a
son and daughter? The king of glory.
The king of glory
with truth and justice. Shines like the
sun in all of his brilliance. The king
of glory,
the king above all kings.
This is amazing grace.
This is unfailing love.
That you would take my place.
That you would bear my cross.
You would lay down your life.
that I would be set free.
Oh Jesus, I sing for all that you've
done for me.
Worthy is a lamb who was slain.
Worthy is the king who conered the
grave.
Worthy is the king slain.
Worthy is the king who conered the
grave.
Worthy is the lamb who was slain.
Worthy is the king who conered the
grave.
Worthy is the lamb who was slain.
Worthy, worthy, worthy. Oh, this is
amazing grace.
This is unfailing love.
That you would take my place.
That you would bear my cross.
You would lay down your life.
That I would be set free.
Oh Jesus, I sing for you for me.
Oh, let you turn for me.
I love you, Lord.
Oh, your mercy never fails me.
All my days
I've been held in your hands.
from the moment that I wake up
until I lay my head.
And I will sing of the goodness
of God.
>> All my life you have been faithful.
All my life you have been so so good.
With every breath that I am able
and I will sing of the goodness
of God.
>> I love your voice.
>> You have led me through the fire.
In darkest night,
you are close like no other.
I've known you as a father.
I've known you as a friend.
And I have lived in the goodness of God.
All my life you have been faithful.
And all my life you have been so so
good.
With every breath that I am able.
I will sing
of the goodness of God.
Your goodness is running after. It's
running after me.
>> Your goodness is running after. It's
With my life laid down, I'm surrendered
now. I give you everything.
>> Your goodness is running after. It's
running after me. Let's sing that again.
Your goodness is running after. It's
running after me.
With my life laid down, I'm surrendered
now. I give you everything.
Your goodness is running after. It's
running after me.
All my life you have been faithful.
And all my life you have been so so
good.
Every breath that I am able,
I will sing of the goodness of God.
I will sing
of the goodness
of God.
Amen.
And can it be that I should gain
an interest in the Savior's
blood.
Died he for me
who caused his pain for me.
to him to death pursuit.
Amazing
love. How can it be that thou my God
should die for me?
Amazing
love.
How can it be that thou my God should
die for me?
He left his father's
throne above
so free so infernate
his grace
empted himself
of all but love
and bless. Head for Adam's
helpless
race
tears mercy all immense
and free
for
my God it found out me
is mercy
oh
immense and free
Oh my God, it found out me.
No condemnation
now I dread
Jesus and all
him is mine.
Alive in him my livinging
head
and clothe in rightuousness
divine.
Bold I approach eternal
throne
and claim the crown
through Christ my own. Hold high
approach
the eternal
throne
and claim the crown through Christ my
own. Let's sing that again. Lord I
approach be cert
and cling the ground
through Christ my own
high
approach
eternal
throne
and claim the crown through Christ my
own and claim claim the crown through
Christ
my
own.
Amen.
>> Um there is youth worship this morning.
So as we do go about our congregational
prayer, if you are in middle school,
please go ahead and make your way over
to the other building so you can take
part in that. Uh for the rest of us,
would you go ahead and just bow your
heads with me as we pray for the
congregational prayer?
Heavenly Father, we thank you for what
it is you're doing in our church. Lord,
we thank you for what's happening in
this congregation as well as the other
congregations down the hall. Lord, we
recognize there are many needs in our
own congregation, uh not to mention
around the world. And so, Lord, just
starting very very locally. Lord, I I
just want to thank you for uh Joanne's
successful surgery and her recovery.
Lord, I just pray that you would
continue to be with her. Actually, it's
her birthday. Pray, Lord, that you just
be with her this day and her whole
family uh as she continues to heal up.
There are folks in our midst, Lord, who
are looking for work. And Lord, I lift
them up to you. Pray, Lord, that you
would find uh the perfect positions
given their giftings uh and their skill
sets, Lord, so that they uh can uh be
productive uh working people uh in this
community as well. Lord, we thank you
for what's going on with CG, our college
ministry. Thank you, Lord, for all the
people that are attending that as well
as those who are serving. Uh Lord, we
thank you for just a great start of the
winter quarter and strong attendance
numbers uh as they've been uh creeping
up over the past several years actually.
Um they're starting a study on the book
of Judges. So, we we lift that up to you
that that will be effective uh and
interesting as that's a that is an
interesting book to be going through.
We praise you for the recent worship
night that they had that was well
attended. I pray that Lord those songs
would be an encouragement not just on
those single event things but throughout
the weeks as people uh think about their
own circumstances and how those songs
can apply to them.
Uh we do lift up um the upcoming CG
camp. I pray that that would be a great
way uh to get people involved uh get
people interested um and build
relationships between people who might
be on the periphery. Lord, I thank you
for the counselors and everybody else
who's involved in that ministry as well
who have been helping to make that
ministry just thrive. I do pray for
upcoming uh projects and exams for all
the students as it's that time of year.
And Lord, I ask that uh in the midst of
all their busyiness, they're able to
look up and see you. We thank you for
the growth that's happening in our
congregation, Lord, and the discussions
we have around multiplying. We do ask
for your guidance in the way we go about
that, Lord. As much as we try and come
up with our own ideas that we might view
as to be logical and where we think
you're leading us, Lord, our desire is
that we would follow what you want to do
with this congregation, even though that
might make us uncomfortable. Lord, we
know that we have to recognize we
recognize that we have to partner with
our other congregations as well in that.
And so I pray that you would help us as
a Redmond congre uh church uh to follow
after you and just adjust in the ways
that you might have us do that. This
morning we do lift up our missionaries
to you. We have many around the world
and specifically this morning we want to
lift up Dendra and Koko Rye. um they are
leading a Bible school on wheels as well
as multiplying churches in northeast
India and Asia. We thank you for the
provision you've already shown in um
many of the needs that were there. For
example, like 13 projectors that they
needed just for being able to do their
ministry. At the same time, we do
recognize that there are still needs
that need to be met. things like
inverter inverters, power inverters for
the stormy rainy season that's coming,
gifts for tireless teachers, financial
help for evangelists, and other things
that we see in the bulletin this
morning. Lord, I pray that you would you
would equip them, you would um supply
them with every need that they might
have, Lord, that you would fulfill those
needs and um bless the people that they
reach out to.
We pray for our world and uh this last
week as has as even more evidence of
that. We pray for the conflicts that are
happening in Ukraine, in Pakistan, in
Iran. Um
Lord, we recognize you as a sovereign
God. And so Lord, we put these
situations into your hands. We pray at
the same time, Lord, that you would
raise up peacemakers in the right ways,
Lord, to help resolve these conflicts
around the world. We pray for those who
are trapped in conflict. And Lord, this
morning we also want to pray for the
churches in Iraq and Iran uh who are
some of the fastest growing churches in
the world at the same time uh undergoing
much strife. So I pray that you would
help to strengthen the believers there
and as they reach out and as others
around them are able to observe their
witness, we pray that more and more
people would just come to a saving
knowledge of your son Jesus.
Lord, this morning we want to lift up
Petros to you who will be bringing your
word. Lord, I ask that you would speak
mightily through him. Lord, you give us
open ears to hear what you have to say
to us. And for those who are involved in
the youth service this morning, uh the
worship team as well as the people who
are speaking and and helping to guide
our middle schoolers, pray that you
would be with them as well. And now we
pray the prayer that your son Jesus
taught us, saying, "Our Father in
heaven, hallowed be your name. Your
kingdom come. Your will be done on earth
as it is in heaven. Give us this day our
daily bread. And forgive us our debts as
we also have forgiven our debtors. Lead
us not into temptation, but deliver us
from evil. For yours is the kingdom, the
power, and the glory forever. Amen.
Please be seated.
Oh.
Oh, it's so far up center. I'm sorry.
I'm going to have to move back a little
bit because you make me nervous.
I'm just kidding.
Okay. Okay. Oh, hi. Hello. Hello. Um,
greetings Redmond family. It is good to
see you all again.
Um, you guys online too there. Yes. Um,
I promise that uh this time I
coordinated properly with with Allan.
Uh, and he doesn't have to, you know,
save my butt for not letting him know
what the correct uh response song was.
This time we actually coordinated. Well,
um, if you have no idea what I'm talking
about, then after this you can go home
and watch the December 28th uh, 2025
message. It was awkward and I forced him
into an awkward position as well. Uh, I
apologized that day and I trust that
he's uh, forgiven me. This be before the
throne of God above, right? Yes. Okay,
great.
Perfect.
Um, this morning we continue on in
Romans,
the gospel, the power of God. Uh, last
week, Pastor Mack helped us to remember
the changes we go through when we become
disciples of Jesus and accept his
sacrifice for us, right?
um our justification, the change in our
title when we are declared legally right
with God. Uh sanctification, the process
by which we our character is changed to
be more like Jesus. And our
glorification, the change in our fate
and the future perfection that we can
hope for.
Our text this morning is from Romans
5:es
1- 11. Um, if you are willing and able,
would you please stand with me and read
along with me?
Romans
uh 1-11.
Therefore, having been justified by
faith, we have peace with God through
our Lord Jesus Christ, through whom we
also have obtained our introduction by
faith into his grace in which we stand.
And we celebrate in hope of the glory of
God. And not only this, but we also
celebrate in our tribulations, knowing
that tribulation brings about
perseverance and perseverance proven
character and proven character hope. And
hope does not disappoint because the
love of God has been poured out within
our hearts through the Holy Spirit who
was given to us. For while we were still
helpless, at the right time, Christ died
for the ungodly. For one will hardly die
for a righteous person. Though perhaps
for the good person, someone would even
dare die. But God demonstrates his own
love toward us in that while we were
still sinners, Christ died for us. Much
more than having now been justified by
his blood, we shall be saved from the
wrath of God through him. For if while
we were enemies, we were reconciled to
God through the death of his son, much
more having been reconciled, we shall be
saved by his life. And not only this,
but we also celebrate in God through our
Lord Jesus Christ, through whom we have
now received the reconciliation.
This is the word of the Lord. Thank you.
Praise be to God.
Uh, fun fact,
Pastor Mack also preached on this
passage, Romans 5 1-11,
four years ago in November 2021. Does
Does any does anybody remember these
these crazy days with all the masks and
the and the little box? Uh, it was
amazing. I don't remember because I was
in school in Singapore. Uh but but I I
witnessed the the leaps and bounds that
ECC made in their live streaming uh
service. It was incredible to see. I
want to remind you that this is what you
all looked like back in 2021. All the
masks, all the box, the I don't know how
many people were in the audience.
You have persevered.
Uh you have survived. And I expect that
the COVID experience has changed us.
Uh so I
don't expect any of us to remember
exactly what Pastor Mack said back in
2021. That would be unfair. Um but maybe
your small group leaders could give you
like a quiz in a week to just just to
see if you remember.
Um, this is the
perspective that I would like for us to
look at this passage with today. First,
that we are reconciled to God for all
time.
Second, we witness the depth of God's
love through Christ. And third, we
handle true suffering in life.
Um, you may notice, um, if you look at
this carefully that that our treatment
of this passage is kind of the reverse
of how we just read it.
Um, I'm hoping that we can build up to
our responsibility, namely perseverance,
by looking at the reasons
for our responsibility.
Because it's not particularly fruitful
or worshipful to just be told to do a
thing unless you can be convinced that
it is a necessary or good or beneficial
thing for you to do. So the first reason
to persevere I believe is because we are
reconciled
to God for all time.
We want to recognize that because of the
fall, we begin in rebellion against God.
In the same way that many new parents uh
are amazed that their children do not
need to be taught how to lie or they do
not need to be taught that even when
their parents are asking them to do a
certain thing, they will willfully do
the opposite. Um, our human nature is
inherently
rebellious to authority.
Now, why is this the case?
I think that there is a fundamental
allure of control when we think that we
get to call all the shots in our
destiny. Uh, we will have so many
experiences. We will see so much of how
the world works at the ground level.
Yeah. How could God possibly know what
I'm going through every single moment of
every day?
And to be sure, uh this is not talking
about, you know, development of uh
maturity or independence or
responsibility. Those those are the good
things. This is the immense discomfort
and frustration of knowing that very few
things, if any at all, are actually
within our control.
In that dread of uncertainty,
sometimes we would rather get a death
grip on the things that we have left and
and then just whatever will be will be.
lest we trust even those most final
personal parts of ourselves over to
someone else.
At the same time, there is audacity
uh that we have to sincerely but also
wrongly believe that we know ourselves
better than the creator of the universe.
The distrust
began in the Garden of Eden when woman
was first asked, "Did God really say you
must not eat from any tree in the
garden?"
And today, Satan also asks us the same
questions to the point that the really
we're really suspicious.
Did God really say
that money is evil? Did God really say
that you must suffer in this life?
Did Jesus really say that I am the only
way, the truth, and the life?
Are you sure that God said that he will
never leave you nor forsake you?
And so seeds of doubt are sown and the
fruit of that doubt is to trust in our
own judgment over God's and the
relationship is broken
with our thoughts and our actions. We
ignore a God who loves us and our and we
are practically telling him thanks but
no thanks. following you feels like kind
of servitude, almost like slavery. Not
only do I choose not to reciprocate your
love to you, I'm letting you know right
now that I plan to give my love to
something else. The audacity.
Now, if you if you were ever uh in a
relationship like that or if you aren't
in a relationship like that, we would
all be kind of advising you to to run
from that kind of relationship. Like you
wouldn't you shouldn't want to be near
them, let alone have any kind of
relationship with them. And yet
that is the condition that we find
ourselves in with God.
the pattern of uh losing to temptation,
choosing the modern idol, or trusting in
worldly wisdom, but God still
desired to pursue us. That's a that's a
crazy kind of love.
When we talk about reconciliation
here, um this isn't this isn't some uh
drama on TV where both sides they like
make mistakes and hurt each other to
create some kind of third act conflict
and then they come back to common ground
and they apologize and they promise to
do better next time like and they're
both better for it. um
as if as if there was anything that that
we could do except to get ourselves in
the posture of receiving all the grace
from God.
This broken relationship is totally
onesided. But
because we are reconciled,
a couple of things happen to us.
First, the the barriers to approaching
God are removed. The sin that enslaved
us is abolished and is no longer able to
keep us from enjoying God's presence.
Second,
we survive encountering God at all.
Now, this wasn't always true. God had to
shield Moses from seeing his full glory
until he passed by and Moses saw his
back. There was a reason why the
tabernacle and later the Jewish temples
have a common courtyard, a holy place,
and a most holy place. There's a reason
that only the high priest could go into
the most holy place and only once a
year. They had to tie a rope around him
just in case he didn't survive his
encounter with God so that the other
priests could pull him out instead of
having to go in and get him.
Part of the miracle
of reconciliation is how undeserved it
is.
Our offense against perfection gets to
be wiped away and we are able to
approach God without being utterly
destroyed like in the old days.
I think that we take that for granted
sometimes.
My hope is that uh none of us are fooled
into thinking that we are able to be
good enough that God was convinced into
reconciling with us. Right? Humanity did
not tear the veil of the temple that
separated us. That barrier was broken
down because of the love and mercy of
Jesus Christ dying in our place.
which is the second point. We witness
the depth of God's love
through Christ.
It's technically my shortest point, but
kind of the most important.
Verses 6 through 8 help to further
describe our condition before
reconciliation. Right? Verse six is
basically saying that Christ died for
the ungodly. Okay. Verse seven, how it
might be worth it for a person to die
for a righteous man and maybe even a
good man.
But then verse eight, we were not even
righteous, let alone good, but
Christ died for us.
This is the gospel
that while we were still sinners, Christ
died for us. Knowing that we would
continue to sin today, Christ died for
us.
Now, I have to ask,
do we live as if there was someone who
loved us enough to die for us? Uh maybe
we again only think of it as fiction,
right? Star Wars uh uh uh Grand Torino,
Saving Private Ryan, The Lion King, Big
Hero 6, uh Avengers, off the top of my
head, Endgame, not not the other ones.
What do these movies have in common?
Right. Not
they have the hero's sacrifice is is
what they call it.
But not only do they portray the hero's
sacrifice,
but they also depict when the surviving
characters uh they start following in
the hero's footsteps. They they take on
their ideals. They start trying to
imitate them.
They recognized that the hero's act of
sacrifice was not just done out of
idealism but a love for the survivors.
That love affected these survivors so
deeply that they wanted to change their
ways for the better. Now, uh do you know
do you know the movie uh do you recall
any movie where the characters are saved
by the hero's sacrifice and they
continue to live as if nothing happened?
I think I might call that uh reality and
daily life for some Christians.
And maybe that's maybe that's the
reality for some of you. And and I'm not
just talking about, you know, imitating
Christ like taking 12 of your friends
and going on a trip to tell people about
the kingdom of God, right? We we already
do that. It's called short-term missions
trips.
Um I'm talking about your dayto-day,
the people that God has placed in your
circles. What do they know about your
lives that shows them how precious Jesus
is to you?
Are you participating in this world any
differently than you would if you did
not know Jesus?
Does the sacrificial love of Jesus
inform what you allow into your eyes and
what takes up room in your heart?
This is more than uh I will not do this,
I will not look at this because God says
so kind of thing. This kind of
disciplehip is where we see the tempting
things of this world and we can say no
because the fulfillment and satisfaction
that comes from spending time with God
and seeing the way he sees is so much
sweeter.
Are you willing to see the world that
God so loved that he gave his only son?
Because not only are you reconciled to
God, but so is everyone else out there.
The ones who are still broken,
rebellious,
unrighteous,
undeserving in our eyes, looking for
love in all the wrong places. We were
all like this.
Some of us might still feel like this.
But the great thing is our
reconciliation to God is tied to the
permanent and perfectly sufficient
sacrifice of Jesus. Uh this is just a
fancy way of of describing verse 8,
right? While we were still enemies, God
wanted a repaired relationship with us.
While we were still doomed, God wanted
to save us. This is wonderful news.
While we were still slaves to Satan, God
sought to set us free, while we while we
were still suffering in this broken
world, God wanted to use it for good.
As we come to grasp more and more the
love of Christ and the sure
reconciliation that we have with God the
Father,
we nurture hope because we are able to
face the trials of this world with
confidence and perseverance.
And that's uh my final point today. We
handle true suffering
in this life.
Verses 1-5
tell us that hope is developed from
proven character which comes from
perseverance which comes from
tribulations or suffering.
This hope is tied to the faith that God
will do what he promises.
This is important to our application. It
would be understandably difficult to
face hardships in this life if you
thought that this was just another thing
that God was telling you to do just
because
now that's not something that that can
be easily justified because it feels
like we end up being the only ones who
have to suffer.
Now this is why I wanted to look at uh
this passage with the end in mind.
Right? There's a difference between
embracing discomfort with a faith in a
reconciled relationship and then simply
facing hardship.
Because if we can be confident in our
standing with God and if we can be
confident in his love,
we have the room to sometimes succeed
and sometimes fail.
Uh quick question. If you remember from
the very beginning, what is the process
called where we grow in our faith and
become more like Jesus? What is it
called?
Sanctification. Thank you. Yes. Very
good. Thank you for for listening. Um
did you think that the process of
sanctification would only be smooth and
successful until the day that you died?
That's I think that's as silly as as
thinking that I can get stronger without
regularly tearing my muscle fibers. Or
or worse, it's like thinking that I can
get stronger
uh by only sitting in my chair and
reading and studying about what it means
to exercise.
In the same way, the Apostle Paul
recognizes that a believer must have
their faith stretched to express the
full hope that they have more
accurately.
And this also depends on the view that
we have of the difficulties in our
lives.
Have you ever heard of exposure therapy?
Right? This is the the psychological
technique where a person usually with a
phobia of some sort is slowly exposed to
their trigger to hopefully be able to uh
coexist with it. That object or
situation that used to cause them great
anxiety is made less scary in the
patient's mind.
Now, does that sound like us and
suffering?
Uh, is it possible that we might have a
phobia of hardship?
We have turned our pursuit of human
flourishing into one that is less
prepared to deal with any kind of
discomfort.
And then for parents, while it's noble
and even responsible to ensure our
children's safety, uh, have we slowly
made it, have we slowly made them less
prepared to encounter real hardship?
Hardship that doesn't care how young a
person is, how safe a person was.
hardship that doesn't care how much a
person has achieved. Have we turned our
minor inconveniences, our first world
problems into more than they should be?
Questions that might sound like, um, can
I be excused from from my serving
commitments? I've been getting a ton of
work and I have to work late all the
time, so I can't serve in the church
anymore. Uh, can my child be excused
from attending fellowship? He has exams
coming up and he needs to study for
them. This is a real thing that I've
heard before. Um, do I have to stay to
converse with people during coffee time?
Uh, I stayed up really late preparing
for this sermon last night. Uh, this
actually also happened in my head, not
out loud until just now. Um, can we not
serve, please, in Chinatown anymore?
There are way too many drug users. Or
what if somebody out there has a weapon
and they try to rob us? also something
that I've actually heard before.
Now, please don't misunderstand.
I believe the concerns behind these
statements are sincere,
but I also believe that they can come
from a place that doesn't fully
recognize how much God wants to exceed
our imaginations in what he can do. Um,
maybe you've heard of the example of a
microscopic perspective versus a
telescopic perspective. Maybe
right now we might have a microscopic
view of our problems. Like we're taking
something that is really small and
making it look a lot bigger than it
actually is.
Alternatively,
uh the solution to that is that we might
need to take a telescopic view of God's
love and grace. Now, what do telescopes
do? They take huge objects
that look small
and make them look closer to their
actual size.
Right? Once we can regularly embrace how
big God's love for us is,
then I think that perseverance,
character, and hope become fruit of a
trusting, reconciled relationship with
God.
church family, the gospel has the power
to reconcile us to God because it
demonstrates God's love for us.
We started off with these three points.
Um, if there is one thing that you take
away today, I would like to tell you to
remember it as maybe one phrase instead.
When we can witness the depth of God's
love,
we can handle true suffering in life
because
we are reconciled to God for all time.
Now, can we see an example of this?
Great question. Yes, you can. You go
further back in Romans chapter 4, we are
given the example of Abraham.
In Genesis 22, God wanted a sacrifice
from Abraham in order to restore their
relationship. God asked him to sacrifice
Isaac, his favorite son at the time.
If you haven't experienced it yourself,
I don't know how many of us have, it's
difficult to imagine the suffering of
being asked to give up a child, right?
What must have been going through
Abraham's head as he was climbing up
this mountain with his son? The life
that God promised before, he was about
to take back.
Where was the justice in this? Isaac
still had his entire life in front of
him, but it seemed that God had
different plans. And what heartbreak did
Abraham feel when Isaac asked him,
"Father, we have the sticks and and
other things for the sacrifice. Where is
the actual sacrifice itself?"
And yet
I think that with whatever faith that
Abraham had left, he responded that God
will provide the sacrifice. My son,
um I think there might be two ways that
that we can understand this.
Now,
Abraham trusted that God maybe would not
allow him to actually sacrifice his son.
That's one possibility. Or
more likely,
Abraham had faith that God would find a
way to keep all of his promises. And
this meant that even if Abraham were to
obey God in sacrificing and killing
Jacob, I believe that Abraham trusted
that God
could have the power to give Isaac back
to him.
And so it was uh that God provided to
Abraham
a suitable sacrifice,
right? one-sidedly securing the means of
reconciliation and simultaneously
uh stretching Abraham's faith.
Now, I truly believe that you are all
very capable people, right? High
achievers. You are known for your
gentleness and your ability to provide
fellowship, to welcome people, to be
hospitable.
Those are things that you can do that
you are able to do and you do do very
well.
However, when it comes to matters of
eternal life and salvation,
I want us to find rest, a little bit of
rest in the fact that we cannot do
anything to earn it. We cannot
achieve it by our effort.
There is nothing that we can do except
to accept it.
And I know that while it's scary to hand
over control of our destiny like that,
for me personally, it's actually a
really great relief to depend on someone
that we can be sure is fully capable
for salvation.
For our salvation, we needed a
superior sacrifice.
In order to be able to meet with God
again, we needed the greatest high
priest.
Because of God's own love for us, he
gave us Jesus who accomplishes both.
Please, please seek to make that more
precious to you.
Let us pray.
Uh Lord,
we thank you for
your love really. uh the love that is
willing to
die for us. The love that is willing to
uh come down to earth and to be like us,
to empathize with us.
Lord, we pray that
we would be able to go through this life
changed, recognizing that
you were willing to die for us.
Yeah. I pray for your Holy Spirit to
transform us, that we would uh never be
the same.
In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
Right.
Thank you, Petrus. Uh what a great
reminder that through Jesus u sacrifice
on the cross we have been reconciled
with him. So now we can come before the
throne of God. So let's stand and let's
sing in response to God.
See, before the throne of God above,
I have a strong and perfect plea,
a great high priest whose name is love.
Whoever lives and pleads for me,
my name is great
on his hands.
My name is written
on his heart.
I know that while in him he stands,
no tongue can bid me this teart.
No tongue can fit me that's deep.
Satan temps me to despair
and tells me of the guilt within
upward I look and see him there
who made an end of all my sin.
Because the sinless
Savior died, my sinful soul
is counted free.
For God the just is satisfied.
To look on him and pardon
me.
to look on him and pardon
Hallelujah.
Praise the one
risen son
of God.
Behold him there.
Risen lamb,
my perfect spotless
righteousness,
the great unchangeable.
I am the king of glory and of grace.
One with himself.
I cannot die.
My soul is purchased
by his blood.
My life is healed with Christ on high.
With Christ my savior and my God.
Hallelujah.
Praise the one,
risen son
of God.
Let's sing that again. Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.
Praise the one
risen son
of God.
Praise the one
risen son
of God.
Amen.
And now may the Lord bless you and the
Lord keep you. May the Lord make his
face to shine on you and be gracious to
you. May the Lord turn his face toward
you
and grant you peace.
Amen. Please be seated.
Good morning. Welcome again to
Evangelical Chinese Church. It's great
to see you all this morning in spite of
the 1-hour lack of sleep. Uh I do have
to say things have changed a bunch
though since we've gotten phones that
change time for us already. You know,
back in the old days, you had to make
sure you actually switched everything
and now that's much less of a risk. So,
great to see you here this morning. And
for those of you who are joining us
online, hope to see you in person one
day. Uh we do want to start by just
welcome anybody who might be here for
the first time. We want to make sure we
get a welcome packet into your hand.
We're not going to do anything to
embarrass you. If you're on this side of
the hall and you're new with us this
morning, would you mind just raising
your hand? Just want to make sure that
we get some information into your hands.
Uh welcome. Thank you for joining us
this morning. Have one of our ushers
come over here just up here a few more
rows up.
And how about on this side? Is there
anybody here who's new? hasn't been with
us before or hasn't received an
information packet.
Doesn't look like it. All right. Okay.
Let's get into some announcements. There
are quite a few announcements this
morning, everyone. Uh let's go ahead and
get through these. So, first of all,
there is lift today, which means that
all the ladies can head over to the
ministry center, just the other building
up on the second floor, and they'll have
a time of fellowship and food as they
always do monthly. Uh that's at 11:15
today. Next slide. Now, this one is
super important. Um, we are as a
congregation expanding and we really
want to hear your opinions uh about some
of your preferences and how it is you
might be able to serve. If you haven't
filled this in, please do. Um, and this
is one per person, not one per family.
So, whether you be in high school,
middle schoolers are all over in the
other building today, but if you're
whether you be in high school or if
you're an adult, um, we do want to hear
from you. So, please do go ahead and
fill this survey out. Next slide,
please. Board game night. The next
iteration of this is happening this
coming Saturday. This is an interchurch
thing that is being run by Henry, who is
here. Um, this is um happening over in
the Redmond Ministry building, which is
the other building. And uh we do ask
that you RSVP for food. Uh there's
information on the Discord server and
what have you behind me. And Henry's
contact information. He is over here on
this side waving. If you have any
questions, please don't hesitate to get
in touch with him. There is a special
event happening for everybody who's
involved or knows people with special
needs. Uh this is going to be happening
next Saturday in our east and west
lobbies. Um Wendy is the contact
information contact person for this. Her
email address is on the slide. They do
ask that you RSVP for this as well. Um
but if you or uh you or people you know
are um looking for some support in
regards to special needs people um this
is the the way to go and do that. Next
week
we are celebrating the ordination of
Minister Steve Moy um on the Seattle
campus on Sunday March 29th. Please join
us for that. Um this many of us know um
minister Steve uh he's been here
speaking with us several times and this
is our opportunity to celebrate as he
gets ordained
on the weekend of Easter. Uh there's
many things going on. We always have our
Good Friday service and Easter Sunday
service. Um but we also have something
that is meant for all of us in this
church as well as people that we want to
invite. Um, this is happening from 9:30
to noon and it's something that you can
just drop in at any time and leave at
any time. Uh, we do ask that you RSVP
and of course we're looking for people
who are willing to help out with this as
well. Uh, but this is a a great
opportunity for us to reach out to our
community and many many different things
going on including the um interactive
Good Friday uh and Saturday thing that's
happening that Cantonese is helping to
organize in the other building. um
really really impressive last year as
well as the whole Saturday thing. So
please do join us for that. Uh our
children's ministry is holding an
in-house training uh that is happening
more than a month from now. So this is
very much a a mark your calendars thing
uh as it will take up much of your
Saturday. Lunch is going to be provided.
Minister Gordon's the contact. His email
address is on the slide. We still have
an open position for an IT manager. Uh
we're looking for somebody who's
experienced to help be able to take care
of the church's technology
infrastructure. You can go to our
website there um to see the open
positions we have and Elder Howard is
our contact for that whose email address
is on the slide. Similarly, we're
looking for a Cantonese pastor or
minister. If you know somebody who might
be appropriate for this, please again go
to our website where you can look at our
open positions. They're looking for
somebody to help minister to that
congregation just down the hall. If
you're looking to reserve a room during
the week, uh during the weekend for some
fellowship or something like that, there
is a QR code that you can go and do that
from. It's at the back of our bulletin,
which some of you have physical ones,
and our bulletin is found online as
well. Um and you can just go to that QR
code if you've got any questions,
info@ccattle.org.
No Sunday school today because we have
lift on the other side. Uh all the men
can hang out here and and chatter uh
about things. Next, uh, giving is very
much part of our worship here at ECC.
Uh, we have many ways to give as you can
see behind me. Um, if you're if you're
here just joining us, please don't feel
obligated to give.
Thank you for joining us this morning.
Um, hope you guys have a great nap this
afternoon and uh, we'll see you guys all
later. Thank you.